<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8c3414a2eeacd86a698f2f567682b5f0b9e4dfb4.005.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-21T23:10:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-21T23:10:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-21T23:10:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-22T11:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Warning issued August 21 at 11:10PM EDT until August 23 at 12:00AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Warning, up to two to three feet of
inundation above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking
waves of 5 to 10 feet in the surf zone. For the Beach Hazards
Statement, dangerous rip currents and large breaking waves
expected in the surf zone.

* WHERE...Northern Outer Banks and Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Warning, until midnight EDT
Friday night. For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 7 AM EDT
Friday through Friday evening.

* IMPACTS...Up to 2 to 3 feet of inundation above ground level
(with locally higher inundation) is possible in some areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways resulting in an elevated threat
of property damage. Flooding will extend inland from the
waterfront threatening some homes and businesses. Road closures
and flooding of vehicles will be possible. Significant impacts
from ocean overwash are likely to continue around high tide both
Friday morning and Friday evening due to continued elevated
water levels, high astronomical tides, and persisting powerful
swell and wave run up. Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions
and localized beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the
best swimmers away from shore into deeper water. Dangerous shore
break can throw a swimmer or surfer head first into the bottom
causing neck and back injuries.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 1:30 PM Friday.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 220310</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT FRIDAY NIGHT... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT FRIDAY NIGHT... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 7 AM EDT FRIDAY THROUGH FRIDAY EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.CF.W.0002.250822T0310Z-250823T0400Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Outer Banks; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>