<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.90e3494c921409898cc995d4c8ac4e0430e86705.005.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-21T02:04:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.513e1e4a36ff8a751ffa8ed29ac5c3888f640bf6.005.2,2025-08-20T15:53:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-21T02:04:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-21T18:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-21T18:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Upton NY</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued August 21 at 2:04AM EDT until August 21 at 11:00PM EDT by NWS Upton NY</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the High Rip Current Risk, life-threatening rip
currents. For the High Surf Advisory, breaking waves building
to 8 to 12 feet through tonight, subsiding to 4 to 8
feet by Friday afternoon. For the Coastal Flood Advisories, 1
to 2 ft of inundation above ground level expected.

* WHERE...Kings (Brooklyn) County.

* WHEN...For the High Surf Advisory, until 8 PM EDT Friday. For
the High Rip Current Risk, through Friday evening. For the
first Coastal Flood Advisory, from 6 PM to 11 PM EDT today.
For the second Coastal Flood Advisory, from 6 PM to 11 PM EDT
Friday.

* COASTAL FLOOD IMPACTS...Minor flooding is expected in the most
vulnerable locations near the waterfront and shoreline. Expect
1 to 2 feet of inundation above ground level in low lying,
vulnerable areas. Some roads and low lying property including
parking lots, parks, lawns and homes/businesses with basements
near the waterfront will experience shallow flooding.

* SWIMMING IMPACTS...Life-threatening swimming and surfing
conditions and localized beach erosion. Life-threatening rip
currents are likely for all people entering the surf zone.
Anyone visiting the beaches should stay out of the surf. Rip
currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into
deeper water.

* SHORELINE IMPACTS...The threat for beach erosion and beach
flooding will increase with successive high tides thru Fri
morning. Scattered areas of dune erosion are possible during
the Thu eve and Fri morning high tides.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

If you enter the surf zone, always have a flotation device with
you and swim near a lifeguard. If caught in a rip current, relax
and float, and do not swim against the current. If able, swim in
a direction following the shoreline. If unable to escape, face
the shore and yell or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWOKX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS41 KOKX 210604</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT FRIDAY... ...HIGH RIP CURRENT RISK REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH FRIDAY EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 6 PM TO 11 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 6 PM TO 11 PM EDT FRIDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KOKX.CF.Y.0006.250821T2200Z-250822T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-21T23:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Kings (Brooklyn)</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036047</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ075</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>