<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.41bcd3bf583e38f513fee1133bfb1041a4af6648.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-21T16:45:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-21T16:45:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-21T16:45:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-22T00:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued August 21 at 4:45PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>HLSMHX

This product covers Eastern North Carolina

**SIGNIFICANT COASTAL HAZARDS CONTINUE ALONG THE OUTER BANKS AS ERIN
MOVES FURTHER AWAY**


NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Warning has been cancelled for East
Carteret, Hatteras Island, Mainland Dare, Northern Outer Banks,
and Ocracoke Island

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for East Carteret, Hatteras
Island, Northern Outer Banks, and Ocracoke Island

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 370 miles east-northeast of Buxton NC or about 440 miles
east-northeast of Morehead City NC
- 36.4N 69.1W
- Storm Intensity 100 mph
- Movement Northeast or 50 degrees at 20 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Hurricane Erin continues pulling away from Eastern North Carolina
and the Outer Banks this evening as a category 2 hurricane. Wind and
wave hazards are steadily decreasing through the day, but this
evening's high tide will continue bringing significant coastal
impacts to the Outer Banks.

Moderate to significant storm surge inundation of 2 to 4 feet above
ground level is expected to continue along the oceanside north of
Cape Lookout, resulting in a significant threat to life and
property. The worst impacts will likely be felt along the Outer
Banks on Ocracoke and Hatteras Island. Portions of NC-12 and
secondary roads along the Outer Banks, in particular on Hatteras and
Ocracoke Islands, are already closed and will likely remain
impassable or inaccessible through the remainder of this week due to
significant ocean overwash.

Minor to locally moderate inundation of 1 to 3 ft can also be
expected for soundside areas adjacent to the southern Pamlico Sound
today and possibly into Friday as well. We once again expect
impacts around the high tide cycles this evening, when the higher of
the daily tides is expected.

Strong rip currents are expected to continue north of Cape Hatteras
through the weekend, with the threat decreasing south of Cape
Hatteras for remaining area beaches. Extensive beach erosion is also
likely due to strong long period waves as high as 10 to 15 feet in
the surf zone along the Outer Banks.

Very dangerous marine conditions will continue for the coastal
waters due to gusty winds and dangerous seas, with worst conditions
north of Cape Lookout. Gusty winds will continue for inland sounds
and rivers through tonight. This will create treacherous conditions
for mariners.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are now unfolding across
the Outer Banks from Duck to Cape Lookout. Remain well away from
life-threatening surge having additional significant impacts. If
realized, these impacts include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.

Also, minor to locally moderate soundside inundation is possible across
the southern Pamlico Sound and adjacent tributaries due to the north
winds. Highest water levels expected across Downeast Carteret County
today. Remain well away from locally hazardous surge having additional
limited impacts.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.


* WIND:
Little to no additional impacts are anticipated at this time
across Eastern North Carolina.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:

During the peak of the storm be ready to move quickly. Keep your
shoes on and rain gear handy. Boots and athletic shoes offer the best
foot protection if you become unexpectedly exposed to the weather.

Keep your cell phone charged and in power-saving mode. If you lose
power, use it sparingly and mainly for personal emergencies and
check-ins.

Do not be a thrill seeker or risk your life for senseless photos or
videos.

If you are prone to flooding or in an area under a storm surge watch
or warning, be prepared for the possibility of a quick and dramatic
rise in water levels.


* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Newport/Morehead City NC around 11 PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMHX 212045</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>SIGNIFICANT COASTAL HAZARDS CONTINUE ALONG THE OUTER BANKS AS ERIN
MOVES FURTHER AWAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Mainland Dare; East Carteret; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ047</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>