<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f6671c2d38b5f33ad12ca5fbf87d0c083658e462.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-21T22:58:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-21T22:58:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-21T22:58:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-22T07:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued August 21 at 10:58PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>HLSMHX

This product covers Eastern North Carolina

**HURRICANE ERIN MOVES FURTHER AWAY AS COASTAL IMPACTS LINGER**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- All watches and warnings have been canceled

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 490 miles east-northeast of Buxton NC or about 570 miles
east-northeast of Morehead City NC
- 37.3N 67.0W
- Storm Intensity 100 mph
- Movement East-northeast or 60 degrees at 22 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Hurricane Erin continues pulling away from Eastern North Carolina
and the Outer Banks tonight as a category 2 hurricane. Winds are
steadily decreasing through the night and waves are slowly easing up
through the weekend, but high tides through Friday night will
continue bringing coastal impacts oceanside.

Significant impacts from coastal flooding and ocean overwash are
likely to continue for the Outer Banks portion of Dare County
through Friday, with the highest impacts across Hatteras Island.
Inundation of 2 to 3 feet with locally higher amounts can be
expected around both the Friday morning high tide, and the Friday
evening high tide. Portions of NC-12 may remain closed or restricted
through the day Friday.

Minor to moderate coastal flood inundation of 1 to 2 feet above
ground level will continue oceanside across Ocracoke, the Crystal
Coast, and Onslow beaches due to high astronomical tides and
residual high water through the day Friday.

Minor to locally moderate inundation of 1 to 2 ft can also be
expected for soundside areas adjacent to the southern Pamlico Sound,
and Core Sound through Friday.

Strong rip currents are expected to continue along the Outer Banks
Friday, likely continuing through the weekend north of Cape
Hatteras. Continued erosion of beaches is also likely due to strong
long period waves as high as 7 to 13 feet in the surf zone along the
Outer Banks, highest north of Cape Hatteras.

Hazardous marine conditions will continue for the coastal waters due
to gusty winds tonight and dangerous seas through the weekend. Gusty
winds will continue for inland sounds and rivers tonight. This will
create dangerous conditions for mariners.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* SURGE:
See local coastal flooding products for more information

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:

Allow extra time for emergency vehicles to reach you as they navigate
road hazards.

Do not attempt to return to evacuated areas until local authorities
give the all clear. Allow time for officials to inspect bridges and
overpasses and to mark washed-out roads.

Be alert for flooded roads which could be compromised or littered
with debris. Avoid travel until water levels subside and roads have
been cleared. Do not drive through places where flood waters cover
the road. Turn around, don't drown!


* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

As it pertains to this event...this will be the last local statement
issued by the National Weather Service in Newport/Morehead City NC
regarding the effects of tropical cyclone hazards upon the area.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMHX 220258</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HURRICANE ERIN MOVES FURTHER AWAY AS COASTAL IMPACTS LINGER</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Mainland Dare; East Carteret; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ047</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>