<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 08 Feb 2023 07:13:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AR1266365F7B44.FloodWatch.1266366E1C30AR.LZKFFALZK.fcc5d7f9089bd57415e179f6fac0b946</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-02-08T13:13:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Jackson; Lawrence; Randolph; White (Arkansas) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-02-08T18:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2023-02-09T09:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Little Rock (Arkansas)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Watch issued February 08 at 1:13PM CST until February 09 at 9:00AM CST by NWS Little Rock</headline>
<description>...FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT CST TONIGHT...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues to be
possible.
* WHERE...Portions of central Arkansas, eastern Arkansas, north
central Arkansas, southwest Arkansas and western Arkansas,
including the following areas, in central Arkansas, Conway,
Faulkner, Garland, Northwest Yell County, Perry, Pope County
Higher Elevations, Pulaski, Saline, Southern Pope County, White
and Yell Excluding Northwest. In eastern Arkansas, Jackson,
Lawrence and Randolph. In north central Arkansas, Baxter, Boone
County Except Southwest, Boone County Higher Elevations, Cleburne,
Eastern, Central, and Southern Searcy County Higher Elevations,
Fulton, Independence, Izard, Marion, Newton County Higher
Elevations, Newton County Lower Elevations, Northwest Searcy
County Higher Elevations, Searcy County Lower Elevations, Sharp,
Southeast Van Buren County, Stone and Van Buren County Higher
Elevations. In southwest Arkansas, Clark, Hot Spring and Pike. In
western Arkansas, Central and Eastern Montgomery County, Central
and Southern Scott County, Johnson County Higher Elevations,
Northern Montgomery County Higher Elevations, Northern Polk County
Higher Elevations, Northern Scott County, Polk County Lower
Elevations, Southeast Polk County Higher Elevations, Southern
Johnson County, Southern and Eastern Logan County, Southwest
Montgomery County Higher Elevations and Western and Northern Logan
County.
* WHEN...Until Midnight CST tonight.
* IMPACTS...Excessive runoff may result in flooding of rivers,
creeks, streams, and other low-lying and flood-prone locations.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- Widespread rain and thunderstorms are expected to develop and
move across the watch area. Two to four inches of rain have
been reported across the watch area. An additional one to
three inches of rainfall is expected, which may prolong flash
flooding or lead to additional areas of flash flooding.</description>
<instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ARZ004>008-014>017-024-025-031>033-039-042>044-052>054-103-112-113-121>123-130-137-138-140-141-203-212-213-221>223-230-237-238-240-241-313-340-341</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KLZK.FA.A.0002.000000T0000Z-230209T0600Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Jackson; Lawrence; Randolph; White</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>005067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>005075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>005121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>005145</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ARZ008</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ARZ017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ARZ025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ARZ033</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>