<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2ad5d545e8aed964fea50cb42fc85aa04388d5cb.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-22T17:46:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-22T17:46:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-22T17:46:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-23T17:45:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued September 22 at 5:46PM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>A broad tropical disturbance, being monitored as Invest 92W, is
slowly moving through western Micronesia and is located to the
northeast of Yap, roughly near 10.4N 139.2E. Today's scatterometery
data shows a weakly defined circulation in this area within a
broader elongated area of cyclonic (counter-clockwise) turning. This
is generating numerous locally heavy showers and some isolated
thunderstorms across the region, with potential for gusty winds. The
Joint Typhoon Warning Center now rates 92W as a "low" for
development, which means it continues to be monitored for development,
but development into a significant tropical cyclone is unlikely
within the next 24 hours. Overall model consensus trend supports
development later this week after 92W passes to the west and
northwest of Palau and Yap. The system is currently meandering
westward into the Philippine Sea.

This slow and disorganized development will lead to widespread
variability in conditions across Palau and Yap State. However, there
is potential for locally heavy showers, strong gusty winds, and
choppy seas across the region over the next few days. Model ensembles
show the potential for 3 to 6 inches across the region through
Saturday, but the location of the highest rainfall totals will depend
on where the locally heavy showers set up. At this time, landslides
are unlikely, due to the high variability in rainfall potential.
However, if soils become saturated by heavy rain, this potential will
increase with the onset of additional rainfall. Also, sustained
winds look to increase as 92W passes to the north of Palau,
potentially sustaining at 22 knots or greater and producing hazardous
conditions for small craft. This looks most likely for Palau waters
with the timing of development as 92W passes nearby, with the
potential for strong sustained winds looking highest around Tuesday
night through Wednesday night.

Additionally, northwest to north swells generated by distant
Typhoons Ragasa and Neoguri will bring elevated surf along west and
north facing reefs of Palau and Yap this week. The forecast will be
closely monitored for the potential for hazardous surf of 9 feet or
greater over the next few days. After 92W moves west of Palau and
Yap and organizes, there is the potential for a monsoon-like pattern
to develop, prolonging elevated seas and surf along the western
sides of the islands and impacting areas sensitive to southwest to
westerly winds and swells.

Residents and mariners should monitor the latest forecasts for the
region at weather.gov/gum/PublicForecasts and any information shared
by WSO Palau and WSO Yap for their local regions.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSPQ2</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWPQ82 PGUM 220746</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>POTENTIAL FOR LOCALLY HEAVY SHOWERS AND GUSTY WINDS THIS WEEK... ...SURF TO BUILD ALONG NORTH AND WEST REEFS OVER NEXT FEW DAYS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Yap; Melekeok; Airai; Koror; Peleliu; Angaur</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>064060</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>070212</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>070004</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>070150</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>070350</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>070010</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FMZ037</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PWZ002</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PWZ003</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PWZ004</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PWZ005</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PWZ006</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>