<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f70f8428bad0f52bf5211b47cd724224f9e6eece.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-11T15:00:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-11T15:00:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-11T15:00:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-14T09:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Aberdeen SD</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued July 11 at 3:00PM CDT by NWS Aberdeen SD</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency has issued an Air
Quality Alert for fine particles pollution. The Air Quality Index
(AQI) is expected to reach the Red or Unhealthy category.

* WHERE...Western Minnesota.

* WHEN...Until 9 AM CDT Monday.

* IMPACTS...Some members of the general public may experience health
effects. Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease
(including asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, may
experience health effects.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Heavy ground-level smoke from wildfires in
central Canada moved into northwest Minnesota early Friday morning
behind a cold front. This first band of smoke is currently impacting
northern Minnesota as it moves east during the day Friday. Air
quality will worsen across northeast Minnesota Friday evening as
smoke arrives over the region. A second round of smoke will move into
northwest Minnesota late Friday evening. This smoke will be more
widespread as it moves southeast overnight, and by Saturday afternoon
the entire state may be impacted. The heaviest smoke on Saturday will
be across the northern half of the state. Air quality will begin to
improve across western Minnesota Sunday morning as cleaner air moves
in from the west. By Sunday evening, the smoke should be gone from
most of the state. Another round of smoke is possible across far
northern Minnesota Sunday night.
</description>
        <instruction>Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease (including
asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, should avoid
prolonged or heavy exertion. The general public should limit
prolonged or heavy exertion.

Reduce or eliminate activities that contribute to air pollution, such
as outdoor burning, and use of residential wood burning devices.
Reduce vehicle trips and vehicle idling as much as possible.

Keep windows closed overnight to prevent smoke from getting indoors.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAABR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS73 KABR 112000</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT UNTIL 9 AM CDT MONDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Traverse; Big Stone</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027155</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ046</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>