<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 03 Jun 2022 03:18:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL1263F9DE35B8.HurricaneLocalStatement.1263F9DF6730FL.MLBHLSMLB.2cd15f7a1624f8e3519a2b475792cf9e</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-06-03T11:18:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Okeechobee; Osceola; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-06-03T11:17:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-06-03T19:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued June 03 at 11:18AM EDT  by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>This product covers East Central Florida
**TROPICAL STORM WARNINGS AND FLOOD WATCHES CONTINUE FOR BREVARD,
OSCEOLA, OKEECHOBEE, INDIAN RIVER, SAINT LUCIE, AND MARTIN COUNTIES**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Coastal Indian River,
Coastal Martin, Coastal Saint Lucie, Inland Indian River,
Inland Martin, Inland Northern Brevard, Inland Saint Lucie,
Inland Southern Brevard, Mainland Northern Brevard, Mainland
Southern Brevard, Northern Brevard Barrier Islands, Okeechobee,
Osceola, and Southern Brevard Barrier Islands
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 540 miles southwest of Fort Pierce FL
- 22.3N 86.8W
- Storm Intensity 40 mph
- Movement Northeast or 35 degrees at 5 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Potential Tropical Cyclone One, near the northeast tip of the Yucatan
Peninsula is forecast become a Tropical Depression or Tropical Storm
later today as it moves northeast across the southeast Gulf of Mexico.
The system is then forecast to move across the southern half of the
Florida peninsula on Saturday.
Widespread rainfall has already developed across south Florida this
morning well ahead of the center of this system, and as it draws
closer to the southern Florida peninsula late tonight into Saturday,
the frequency of showers and squalls will increase. Sustained winds
may approach tropical storm force, and will frequently gust above
tropical storm force in stronger outer rainbands, and squalls near
where the center tracks across the state. Based on the latest forecast
track, the strongest winds and gusts are expected from early Saturday
morning through around sunset.
The main hazard for east central Florida remains the potential for
flooding rainfall. Widespread rainfall totals of 4 to 8 inches are
forecast across Okeechobee, Martin, Saint Lucie, and Indian River
Counties, with local amounts as high as 10 inches. For Osceola and
Brevard Counties, 3 to 5 inches with local amounts up to 7 inches may
occur.
With the system forecast to track eastward as a weak Tropical Storm
across Florida, storm surge is not expected along the east central
coast. However, a few tornadoes cannot be ruled out, mainly south of
Interstate 4.
Residents and visitors should stay tuned to the latest forecasts and
information regarding Potential Tropical Cyclone One today through
Saturday.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across across Okeechobee County and the Treasure
Coast, specifically in Martin County. Potential impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may
become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas, destructive runoff
may run quickly down valleys while increasing susceptibility to
rockslides and mudslides. Flood control systems and barriers
may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Additional flooding impacts are possible in Brevard and Osceola
Counties, where a Flood Watch remains in effect.
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
areas now under a Tropical Storm Warning. Potential impacts in this
area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
Elsewhere across East Central Florida, little to no impact is
anticipated.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across East Central Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging wind
gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the center of
the storm.
Keep cell phones well charged. Cell phone chargers for automobiles
can be helpful, but be aware of your risk for deadly carbon monoxide
poisoning if your car is left idling in a garage or other poorly
ventilated area.
It is important to remain calm, informed, and focused. Be patient and
helpful with those you encounter.
If you are a visitor, be sure to know the name of the city or town in
which you are staying and the name of the county or parish in which
it resides. Listen for these locations in local news updates. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 6 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053-058-154-159-164-247-254-259-264-347-447-547-647-747</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Okeechobee; Osceola; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ058</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ159</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ164</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ247</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ254</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ259</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ347</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ447</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ547</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ647</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ747</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>