<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 03 Jun 2022 09:38:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL1263F9DD5328.HurricaneLocalStatement.1263F9DE8E64FL.KEYHLSKEY.d9ed7063537b4589b0a05a2f58d3c0fd</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-06-03T05:38:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Monroe Lower Keys; Monroe Middle Keys; Monroe Upper Keys (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-06-03T05:13:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-06-03T13:45:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Key West (Key West - The Florida Keys)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued June 03 at 5:38AM EDT  by NWS Key West</headline>
<description>This product covers the Florida Keys
**Tropical Storm Warning remains in effect for all Florida Keys**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Monroe Lower Keys,
Monroe Middle Keys, and Monroe Upper Keys
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 340 miles west-southwest of Key West FL or about 390
miles west-southwest of Marathon FL or about 430 miles
west-southwest of Key Largo FL
- 22.3N 86.6W
- Storm Intensity 40 mph
- Movement Northeast or 40 degrees at 6 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
A Tropical Storm Warning remains in effect for all Florida Keys and
surrounding waters.
At 500 AM, the disturbance remains near the northeastern tip of the
Yucatan Peninsula and continues to move slowly toward the northeast.
This general motion with an increase in forward speed is expected to
begin later today. The system is expected to approach our western
waters this afternoon, through our deep gulf waters tonight, then out
across southern and central Florida on Saturday. Recent reconnaissance
data indicate that maximum sustained winds have increased to near 40
mph. The system is expected to develop a well-defined center and
become a tropical storm later today. Some slight strengthening is
possible while it approaches Florida today and tonight. Regardless of
further development, weather conditions will steadily deteriorate with
thundery squalls becoming more frequent.
There is a potential risk for multiple hazards for the Florida Keys,
including flooding rainfall, tropical storm force winds, especially in
squalls, isolated tornadoes, and treacherous marine conditions.
Heavy rainfall of 4 to 8 inches, with isolated maximum totals of 12
inches, may cause significant rainwater flooding. A Flood Watch remains
in effect through Saturday evening.
A few tornadoes will be possible today through Saturday.
There is potential for minor coastal flooding of 1 to 2 feet above mean
sea level along the Gulfside/Bayside Saturday, especially over the on
the bayside communities in the Upper Keys. Significant oceanside wave
overwash is expected today through Saturday, most evident around the
times of higher high tide.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across the Florida Keys. Potential impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across the
Florida Keys. Potential impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
the Florida Keys. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
* SURGE:
Prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
across Florida Keys. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of roads and parking lots inundated by surge water.
Driving conditions dangerous in places where surge water covers
the road.
- Moderate beach erosion.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
No mandatory evacuations are in effect expected for this storm.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
in a low-lying or poor drainage area, plan to move to safe shelter on
higher ground.
If a Tornado Warning is issued for your area, be ready to shelter
quickly, preferably away from windows and in an interior room not prone
to flooding. If driving, scan the roadside for quick shelter options.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
- For Florida Division of Emergency Management information, see
floridadisaster.org
- For Monroe County Emergency Management Information, see
monroecountyem.com/782/Emergency-Management
- For Monroe County EM Hurricane Preparedness Information, see
monroecountyem.com/1214/Hurricane-Preparedness
- For Monroe County EM Evacuation Information, see
monroecountyem.com/897/Evacuation-information
- For Monroe County shelter information, see
monroecountyem.com/992/Shelters
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Key West FL around 11 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ076>078</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Monroe Lower Keys; Monroe Middle Keys; Monroe Upper Keys</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ076</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ078</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>