<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 20 Jun 2023 07:28:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12664EEC4B60.FloodWatch.12664EED7ECCNC.GSPFFAGSP.ee3881a27de504e8c03c791ee1827a7e</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-06-20T03:28:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Alexander; Avery; Buncombe; Burke Mountains; Caldwell Mountains; Eastern McDowell; Eastern Polk; Greater Burke; Greater Caldwell; Greater Rutherford; Henderson; McDowell Mountains; Mitchell; Polk Mountains; Rutherford Mountains; Yancey (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-06-20T05:15:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-06-20T11:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Watch issued June 20 at 3:28AM EDT until June 20 at 11:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH THURSDAY AFTERNOON...
* WHAT...Flash flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues to be
possible.
* WHERE...Portions of Piedmont North Carolina and western North
Carolina, including the following areas, in piedmont North
Carolina, Alexander County. In western North Carolina, Avery,
Buncombe, Burke, Caldwell, McDowell, Polk, Rutherford, Henderson,
Mitchell, and Yancey Counties.
* WHEN...Through Thursday afternoon.
* IMPACTS...Excessive runoff may result in flooding of rivers,
creeks, streams, and other low-lying and flood-prone locations.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- A low pressure system persisting near the southern
Appalachians will keep deep moisture in place over the
region. Numerous rounds of showers and thunderstorms will
develop over the area today, tomorrow, and likely into
Thursday, bringing periods of very heavy rainfall. An
additional 5 to 10 inches of rain will be possible over parts
of the North Carolina mountains and foothills through
Thursday, falling on areas that have already received several
inches of rain over the past 24 hours. This will make ongoing
flooding worsen and likely cause new flash flooding to
develop.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood</description>
<instruction>A Flood Watch for flash flooding means there is a potential for
rapid onset flooding based on current forecasts. Flash flooding is a
very dangerous situation and may impact areas that do not typically
flood. Please monitor the latest forecasts and be prepared to take
action quickly should Flash Flood Warnings be issued.
Low-lying areas adjacent to streams, including campgrounds, are
especially vulnerable to flooding. If you live or are vacationing
next to a stream, please have a plan in place to seek higher ground
once heavy rainfall develops. Flash floods can occur quickly and
overwhelm adjacent low-lying areas with little warning. Once the
stream starts to rise, you may only have minutes to evacuate. Flash
floods can cause catastrophic damage and be powerful enough to sweep
away campers, vehicles, and mobile homes. Consider temporarily
relocating away from streams until the heavy rainfall threat passes.
Rainfall of more than five inches in similar storms has been
associated with an increased risk of landslides and rockslides. If
you live on a mountainside or in a cove at the base of a mountain,
especially near a stream, be ready to leave in advance of the storm
or as quickly as possible should rising water, moving earth, or
rocks threaten. Consider postponing travel along mountain roads
during periods of heavy rainfall.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ033-035-049-050-053-065-501>510</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.A.0002.230620T1000Z-230622T2200Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Alexander; Avery; Buncombe; Burke Mountains; Caldwell Mountains; Eastern McDowell; Eastern Polk; Greater Burke; Greater Caldwell; Greater Rutherford; Henderson; McDowell Mountains; Mitchell; Polk Mountains; Rutherford Mountains; Yancey</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037161</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037199</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ050</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ501</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ502</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ503</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ504</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ505</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ506</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ507</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ508</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ509</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ510</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>