<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.e3f5d0e35267631eff5986e6acaa99924d8b5cdf.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-27T23:21:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-27T23:21:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-27T23:21:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-28T08:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Melbourne FL</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued September 27 at 11:21PM EDT by NWS Melbourne FL</headline>
        <description>HLSMLB

This product covers East Central Florida

**Tropical Storm Watches Remain in Effect for Coastal Portions of
East Central Florida**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Indian River,
Coastal Martin, Coastal Saint Lucie, Coastal Volusia, Mainland
Northern Brevard, Mainland Southern Brevard, Northern Brevard
Barrier Islands, and Southern Brevard Barrier Islands

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 480 miles south-southeast of Cape Canaveral FL
- 22.4N 76.7W
- Storm Intensity 35 mph
- Movement Northwest or 310 degrees at 2 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

At 11 PM, Tropical Depression Nine was located about 100 miles
southwest of the Central Bahamas, drifting toward the northwest at
just 2 mph. The system is forecast to strengthen into Tropical Storm
Imelda by Sunday morning as it moves north-northwestward over the
central and northwestern Bahamas, then become a hurricane on Monday as
it parallels the Atlantic coast of Florida.

As the center of Tropical Depression Nine moves northward, outer rain
bands will begin to affect the immediate coast of east-central Florida
as early as Sunday. Multiple rounds of rainfall are forecast from
Sunday through early Tuesday, with amounts of 1 to 3 inches focused
along and east of Interstate 95. Through Tuesday, locally higher
amounts to 5 inches are possible where persistent bands of rain set
up, especially along the immediate coastline. Localized flooding or
ponding of water on roadways is possible where repeated rounds of
heavy rain occur.

Wind fields will gradually expand as the tropical system strengthens.
As a result, tropical-storm-force wind gusts are possible for much of
the east-central Florida coastline, especially from Cape Canaveral
northward. The potential exists for occasional tropical-storm-force
sustained winds along the northern Brevard and Volusia coast.
Therefore, Tropical Storm Watches remain in effect for coastal
portions of Volusia, Brevard, Indian River, Saint Lucie, and Martin
counties. A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for the adjacent
Atlantic coastal waters.

At the coast, battering surf from Sunday afternoon through Tuesday
will produce dangerous beach conditions. A HIGH risk of rip currents
is forecast with breaking waves of 6 to 10 feet. Beach erosion is
increasingly likely as waves run up to the dune line or sea walls,
especially along the northern Brevard and Volusia coast on Monday.
Long-period swells from this system combined with distant Major
Hurricane Humberto will produce the potential for long-duration beach
and dune erosion, along with high surf conditions, through late week.

For locations in and near the Tropical Storm Watch, do not let your
guard down. Slight westward adjustments in the forecast track will
increase the potential for tropical-storm-force winds, while an
eastward shift would decrease this potential. Regardless of the exact
track, significant coastal impacts are anticipated. Now is the time to
ensure your hurricane supply kit is stocked and your safety plan is in
place. Continue to monitor the latest forecasts from the National
Hurricane Center and National Weather Service in Melbourne, Florida.



--------------------

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
East Central Florida. Potential impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.

* SURGE:
Prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
across coastal areas of east central Florida. Potential impacts in this
area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of near-shore roads and parking lots become overspread
with surge water. Driving conditions dangerous in places where
surge water covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible limited
impacts across east central Florida. Potential impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding may prompt a few evacuations.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swifter currents.
Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may become swollen
and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and emergency supplies
kit and take necessary actions to protect your family and secure your
home or business.

When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.

When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.

Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 5 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMLB</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMLB 280321</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>Tropical Storm Watches Remain in Effect for Coastal Portions of
East Central Florida</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Volusia; Northern Lake County; Orange; Seminole; Osceola; Okeechobee; Coastal Volusia; Southern Lake County; Coastal Indian River; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Indian River; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Martin; Mainland Northern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Inland Southern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012127</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012069</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012117</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012097</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012093</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012061</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012111</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012085</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ041</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ044</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ046</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ053</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ141</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ144</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ154</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ159</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ164</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ247</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ254</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ259</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ264</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ347</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ447</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ547</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ647</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ747</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>