<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 16 Jun 2023 05:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA12664EB0C644.AirQualityAlert.12664ECD1FB0CA.PSRAQAPSR.0b1db86c0270f712db235c821d1952b4</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-06-16T10:21:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Imperial Valley (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Air Quality Alert</event>
<urgency>Unknown</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Unknown</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-06-15T13:05:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2023-06-17T20:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Phoenix (Central Arizona and California Desert)</senderName>
<headline>Air Quality Alert issued June 16 at 10:21AM PDT  by NWS Phoenix</headline>
<description>...AIR QUALITY ALERT FOR ELEVATED OZONE AIR POLLUTION...
The Imperial County APCD has issued an air quality alert for the
Imperial Valley due to high levels of ozone (smog). The air quality
alert is in effect Saturday, June 17, 2023 from 10 AM until 8 PM.
Elevated levels of ozone – the predominant summertime pollutant –
are likely to result in poor air quality in the afternoon and early-
evening hours. Ozone air pollution can cause respiratory health
problems, including trouble breathing, asthma attacks, and lung
damage. Children, older adults, and people with asthma or COPD may
be more sensitive to the health effects of ozone.
Air quality can change depending on time of day and weather
conditions. Increased emissions of chemicals and faster ozone
formation rates due to heat, along with low winds and stagnant
weather can cause unusually high and persistent levels of ozone
pollution.
To help minimize ozone air pollution levels:
• Limit the use of gasoline powered lawn and garden equipment until
evening hours
• Conserve electricity and set your air conditioner at a higher
temperature
• Try to delay trips to the gas station and the use of household
chemicals until the evening
Check air quality levels and take appropriate action as needed. When
air quality index (AQI) levels are Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups
(orange), people with heart or lung disease, pregnant women,
children, and older adults should limit prolonged or heavy outdoor
exertion. When air quality reaches Unhealthy (red) AQI levels,
everyone may experience adverse health effects and sensitive groups
should avoid prolonged time outdoors. At Very Unhealthy (purple) AQI
levels, sensitive groups should avoid all outdoor physical activity
and everyone else should avoid prolonged or heavy outdoor exertion.
To view current and forecast air quality within Imperial County
visit the Imperial County Air Quality website at
http://www.imperialvalleyair.org/ or follow ICAPCD on Twitter,
facebook or Instagram (@county_air).</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ567</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Imperial Valley</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ567</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>