<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.58d28421acd5d9041f8d762a254cddd09c1372c4.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T19:24:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.61ef6a36a2baf5bbfe1c420d4923e6e98614f690.001.1,2025-08-05T19:10:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T19:24:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T19:24:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-05T22:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 5 at 7:24PM EDT until August 5 at 10:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...A portion of northwestern Union County, North Carolina.

* WHEN...Until 1015 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 712 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicates that the heavy
rainfall responsible for nuisance flooding across the western
half of Union County has departed the area and additional
significant rainfall is not expected for the remainder of
today.  However, storm-total rainfall of 2-5 inches since
about 4am this morning has resulted in excessive runoff
producing high flows and areas of nuisance flooding.

Goose Creek, Bearskin Creek, and other streams across
northeastern Union County have crested and receded back below
bankfull levels; however, high flows continue along N Fork
Crooked Creek and S Fork Crooked Creek.  Therefore, the Flood
Advisory has been reduced in size to focus on the Crooked
Creek watershed from Hemby Bridge to Fairview and the Rocky
River confluence.

The north fork of Crooked Creek has crested and is falling
quickly.  Residual nuisance flooding of adjacent low-lying
areas will persist for the next 1-2 hours, but conditions
near Idlewild Rd, Indian Trail-Fairview Rd and Oakspring Rd,
where shallow flooding likely occurred, will continue to
improve.

South Fork Crooked Creek is currently cresting and will begin
a gradual recession over the next hour.  Extensive low-lying
flooding of wooded areas is ongoing.  Union County Emergency
Management is currently reporting road closures at Ridge Rd
and Friendly Baptist Church Rd due to shallow flooding from
the stream.  Expect gradual improvement in flood conditions
over the next few hours as the stream recedes.

Therefore, the Flood Advisory has been extended into the
later evening hours to allow conditions to improve.

Areas of ongoing concern include:
1) along North Fork Crooked Creek near Oakspring Rd, Idlewild
Rd and Indian Trail-Fairview Rd.
2) along S Fork Crooked Creek near Unionville-Indian Trail
Rd, Poplin Rd, and Ridge Rd.

People are urged to obey all barricades, even if flood waters
have receded, until crews can assess road safety.

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Indian Trail, Unionville, Lake Park, Hemby Bridge and
Fairview In Union County.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 052324</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 1015 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0096.000000T0000Z-250806T0215Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-05T22:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.64e4424a06df64608673ed272212cb0b40d25fa6.001.1,2025-08-05T16:37:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8ddef93432d585c79f0b022c1debe760c4af35af.001.1,2025-08-05T14:42:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.69cb0dac699bd9fda92543bb38c2e13ffb4940b6.001.1,2025-08-05T13:04:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a14af1236ac5edfbb40a6fbe0b958ff4a0029d87.001.1,2025-08-05T10:22:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Union, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.16,-80.55 35.18,-80.51 35.17,-80.48 35.15,-80.5 35.13,-80.53 35.1,-80.54 35.08,-80.56 35.06,-80.59 35.05,-80.62 35.09,-80.7 35.1,-80.69 35.11,-80.68 35.12,-80.66 35.11,-80.6 35.16,-80.55</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037179</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>