<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.892634cad035659754b51cf0bdab675644ffcfaa.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T12:36:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0e0917889ac1d730671da2f72bd89dae6d24846e.001.1,2025-08-05T10:31:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.3e4c74f8ad2384d26539c3fb02f4083dbe653c89.001.1,2025-08-05T11:27:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T12:36:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T12:36:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-05T16:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flash Flood Warning issued August 5 at 12:36PM EDT until August 5 at 4:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>At 1236 PM EDT, Doppler radar and automated gauges indicate moderate
to heavy rainfall across eastern portions of Mecklenburg County
affecting the McAlpine and Fourmile Creek watersheds.  As a result,
1 to 1.5 inches of rainfall has occurred over the past 60 minutes,
resulting in storm-total rainfall between 2.5 and 3.5 inches across
eastern Mecklenburg County.  Therefore, McMullen Creek, McAlpine
Creek, Irvins Creek, Fourmile Creek, and adjacent feeder streams,
which are already running high from earlier rainfall, are starting
to rapidly rise once again.  Expect areas of nuisance to Minor
flooding to develop in these watersheds over the next 60-90 minutes
as streams exceed their banks.

* Areas of developing concern include:
1) McMullen Creek from Sharon Memorial Park, along the McMullen
Creek Greenway, to Addison Dr, Arborway, and Colony Rd.
2) Irvins Creek from Idlwild Rd to Sam Newell Rd and along the
Irvins Creek Greenway.
3) McAlpine Creek along the McAlpine Creek Greenway and near
Monroe Rd to Old Providence Rd to Colony Rd.
4) Fourmile Creek along the Fourmile Creek Greenway.

* Across the remainder of southern Mecklenburg County, storm-total
rainfall over the past 6-8 hours has exceeding 3-5 inches across
much of southern Mecklenburg County.  The heaviest rainfall has
occurred along Little Sugar Creek, where isolated totals of 5-5.5"
have been observed, including near Starmount Forest and
Sedgefield.  Flash flooding is ongoing with additional areas of
flooding expected to develop, especially downstream of primary
streams in the southern Charlotte metro area.  Ongoing flooding
may worsen over the next 1-2 hours as the heaviest rain finally
departs the metro area.

* Areas of ongoing concern include:
1) along Little Sugar Creek and feeder drainages from near 36th
Street to Medical Center Drive to Hillsdale Ave and Seneca Place.
2) along Steele Creek and feeder drainages near John Price Rd,
Arrowood Mobile Home Park, and Carowinds Blvd.
3) along Briar Creek and feeder drainages from near Shamrock Dr to
Independence Blvd to Colony Rd.


HAZARD...Life-threatening flash flooding. Heavy rain producing
flash flooding.

SOURCE...Radar and automated gauges.

IMPACT...Life-threatening flash flooding of creeks and streams,
urban areas, highways, streets and underpasses.  Impacts
to structures adjacent to drainages and streams are
possible, and residents and businesses are urged to move
away from streams.

Some locations that may experience flash flooding include...
Uptown Charlotte, Central Charlotte, South Charlotte, Southwest
Charlotte, East Charlotte, Northeast Charlotte, Northwest
Charlotte, Matthews, Mint Hill, Pineville, Marvin, Southpark,
Freedom Park, The Arboretum, The Plaza, Hidden Valley, Carowinds,
Paw Creek and Steele Creek.

The heaviest rainfall is moving through the southern parts of
Charlotte, including from Pineville to Matthews, and will depart the
area over the next 30-45 minutes from west to east. Expect flooding
headwaters to crest and for conditions to gradually improve after
noon (closer to 2pm for eastern areas of Mecklenburg County) with
the resultant floodwave impacting downstream locations closer to the
SC state line over the next 1-4 hours.  The Flash Flood Warning will
remain in effect until most streams have crested and conditions have
significantly improved, with only nuisance flooding remaining.

Isolated areas of Moderate flooding, with significant inundation of
flood-prone roads and a few structural impacts, are still possible
over the next 1-2 hours.  Drivers are urged to exercise extreme
caution and obey all barricades.  Residents and businesses are urged
to protect life and move away from streams.
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS72 KGSP 051636</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLASH FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 415 PM EDT THIS AFTERNOON FOR SOUTHERN MECKLENBURG COUNTY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDetection</valueName>
            <value>RADAR AND GAUGE INDICATED</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDamageThreat</valueName>
            <value>CONSIDERABLE</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FF.W.0012.000000T0000Z-250805T2015Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-05T16:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Mecklenburg, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.11,-81.03 35.14,-81.05 35.16,-81.01 35.25,-80.99 35.28,-80.89 35.29,-80.81 35.26,-80.75 35.21,-80.71 35.16,-80.63 35.0,-80.84 35.11,-80.93 35.06,-81.06 35.11,-81.03</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037119</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC119</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>