<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.64e4424a06df64608673ed272212cb0b40d25fa6.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T16:37:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.69cb0dac699bd9fda92543bb38c2e13ffb4940b6.001.1,2025-08-05T13:04:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8ddef93432d585c79f0b022c1debe760c4af35af.001.1,2025-08-05T14:42:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T16:37:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T16:37:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-05T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 5 at 4:37PM EDT until August 5 at 7:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...Portions of central and northwestern Union County, North
Carolina.

* WHEN...Until 715 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 417 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicates that the heavy
rainfall responsible for nuisance flooding across the western
half of Union County has departed the area and additional
significant rainfall is not expected for the remainder of
today.  However, storm-total rainfall of 2-5 inches since
about 4am this morning has resulted in excessive runoff
producing high flows and areas of nuisance flooding.

Streams across southwestern portions of Union County have
receded back below critical levels, and the Flood Advisory
has been cancelled for these areas, including Weddington,
Mineral Springs, and Waxhaw within the Twelvemile Creek
watershed.  However, high flows continue along Goose Creek, N
Fork Crooked Creek, S Fork Crooked Creek, and the headwaters
of Richardson Creek near Monroe, including along Bearskin
Creek.  These streams are currently cresting, but they remain
above bankfull levels, resulting in nuisance flooding of
adjacent low-lying areas and potential shallow flooding of
adjacent roadways.  Therefore, the Flood Advisory remains in
effect from Monroe and points north and west towards Hemby
Bridge, Unionville, and Fairview.

Flooding along Goose Creek has ended along and near Stevens
Mill Rd, but the floodwave has moved downstream and is still
imapcting areas from near Mill Grove Rd to the Charlotte
National Golf Club, Howey Bottoms Rd, and NC 218.  Expect
conditions to improve quickly over the next 1-2 hours.

The streamgauge at Bearskin Creek and N Charlotte Ave is
above Action Stage, causing nuisance flooding of the Bearskin
Creek Greenway flooding from Dickerson Park downstream to
Belk Tonowonda Park near IB Shive Dr.  Floodwaters may also
be impacting the greenway and the baseball field at Don
Griffin Park near Meadow St.  Bearskin Creek is currently
cresting near 9.5 feet.  Action Stage is 8.0 feet.  Nuisance
flooding will continue near Dickerson Park for the next 2-4
hours.  Therefore, the Flood Advisory will continue into at
least the early evening hours to allow flood conditions to
improve.

Areas of ongoing concern include:
1) along Goose Creek near Mill Grove Rd to NC 218.
2) along North Fork Crooked Creek near Oakspring Rd, Idlewild
Rd and Indian Trail-Fairview Rd.
3) along Bearskin Creek near Dickerson Park, N Charlotte Ave,
and Creft Park.
4) along S Fork Crooked Creek near Unionville-Indian Trail
Rd, Poplin Rd, and Ridge Rd.

People are urged to obey all barricades, even if flood waters
have receded, until crews can assess road safety.

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Monroe, Matthews, Mint Hill, Indian Trail, Stallings,
Unionville, Wingate, Lake Park, Hemby Bridge and Fairview In
Union County.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 052037</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 715 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0096.000000T0000Z-250805T2315Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-05T19:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a14af1236ac5edfbb40a6fbe0b958ff4a0029d87.001.1,2025-08-05T10:22:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Union, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.02,-80.63 35.09,-80.7 35.21,-80.55 35.18,-80.5 35.18,-80.49 35.18,-80.48 35.17,-80.48 35.17,-80.47 35.17,-80.46 35.16,-80.44 35.17,-80.42 35.16,-80.41 35.13,-80.42 35.06,-80.44 34.98,-80.47 34.98,-80.61 35.02,-80.63</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037179</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>