<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.742fce6611b4525d90d0f694e002aa638732f263.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T15:05:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T15:05:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T15:05:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-07T00:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Los Angeles/Oxnard CA</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued August 5 at 3:05PM PDT by NWS Los Angeles/Oxnard CA</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The South Coast AQMD has extended an air quality alert due
to increased fine particle pollution from wildfire smoke.

* WHERE...San Bernardino Mountains, Angeles National Forest, San
Jacinto Mountains, Coachella Valley, the Santa Rosa Reservation,and
parts of the Inland Empire. Levels of particle pollution can vary
by time and location depending on fire activity and local weather
conditions.

* WHEN...Tuesday afternoon through Wednesday.

* IMPACTS...Particles in wildfire smoke can get deep into the lungs
and cause serious health problems such as heart attacks, strokes,
asthma attacks, and difficulty breathing. Everyone can be affected,
but people with lung or heart disease, older adults, people who are
pregnant, children, and those who spend a lot of time outdoors are
at greater risk.
</description>
        <instruction>To protect your health, if you smell or see smoke:

* Remain indoors with windows and doors closed
* Avoid intense outdoor physical activity
* Run your air conditioner and/or an air purifier
* If you must be outdoors, keep the time brief and wear a well-
fitting N-95 mask
* Do not use whole house fans or swamp coolers that bring in outside
air if you have other methods to stay cool
* Avoid other sources of pollution such as fireplaces, candles,
incense, grilling, and gasoline-powered lawn and garden equipment

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the South Coast
Air Quality Management District website at aqmd.gov or download the
mobile app at www.aqmd.gov/mobileapp. Additional details for this air
quality alert may be available at www.aqmd.gov/advisory.

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the Mojave Desert
Air Quality Management District website at mdaqmd.ca.gov.
Additional details for this air quality alert may be available at
www.mdaqmd.ca.gov/advisories.

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the antelope
Valley Air Quality Management District website at www.avaqmd.ca.gov.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQALOX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS76 KLOX 052205</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FOR HARMFUL FINE PARTICLE POLLUTION LEVELS DUE TO WILDFIRE SMOKE UNTIL MIDNIGHT PDT WEDNESDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Interstate 5 Corridor; Western San Gabriel Mountains and Highway 14 Corridor; Eastern San Gabriel Mountains</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006037</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ378</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ379</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ380</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>