<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f7e074ac6bd9b4cb46d4de2af309fbf87308c154.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T12:11:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7971d7e671b6c3ef3085451705a0b36b55ab7e65.001.1,2025-08-05T09:37:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T12:11:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T12:11:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-05T18:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 5 at 12:11PM EDT until August 5 at 6:30PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...Mecklenburg County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 630 PM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1156 AM EDT, Doppler radar indicates that the heaviest
rainfall is currently over extreme eastern Mecklenburg County
near Matthews and Mint Hill, slowly moving east into Union
County.  The southern half of Mecklenburg County is under a
Flash Flood Warning, where more significant flooding has
developed and water rescues are ongoing.  Across the
remainder of Mecklenburg County, storm-total rainfall of 1.5
to 3 inches over the past 6-8 hours has caused significant
rises on most area streams, with a few likely exceeding or
about to exceed bankfull, resulting in nuisance flooding of
adjacent low-lying areas.  For these areas, including from
Huntersville to Paw Creek to areas of northeast Charlotte, a
Flood Advisory remains in effect.  The Flood Advisory will
continue until area streams have crested and receded back
below bankfull levels.  Given the duration of excessive
runoff, it will take several hours for this to occur,
therefore, the Flood Advisory has been extended into this
evening.

Areas of greatest concern include:
1) along Mallard Creek from Old Potters Rd to W Sugar Creek
Rd to the Mallard Creek Greenway near US 29 to Pavilion Blvd.
2) along Torrence Creek near the Torrence Creek Greenway.
3) along McDowell Creek near Cook Regional Park and the
McDowell Creek Greenway.
4) along Back Creek near the Back Creek Greenway and McLean
Rd.
5) along Reedy Creek near the Reedy Creek Nature Preserve,
Plaza Rd Extension, and Hood Rd.

- Additional rainfall totals of up to a half inch are possible
across the northern half of Mecklenburg County as the
heaviest rain moves east.  This additional rainfall is not
expected to exacerbate ongoing flooding.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Uptown Charlotte, Huntersville, Central Charlotte, South
Charlotte, Northeast Charlotte, East Charlotte, Southwest
Charlotte, Northwest Charlotte, West Concord, Matthews,
Cornelius, Mint Hill, Davidson, Pineville, Harrisburg, Tega
Cay, Marvin, The Plaza, Hidden Valley and Freedom Park.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 051611</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL 630 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXT.KGSP.FA.Y.0094.000000T0000Z-250805T2230Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-05T18:30:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Mecklenburg, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.35,-80.69 35.27,-80.67 35.21,-80.55 35.0,-80.84 35.11,-80.93 35.04,-81.04 35.06,-81.06 35.11,-81.03 35.14,-81.05 35.16,-81.01 35.3,-81.0 35.35,-80.97 35.36,-80.92 35.36,-80.97 35.36,-80.98 35.37,-80.98 35.49,-80.95 35.51,-80.91 35.51,-80.78 35.4,-80.77 35.35,-80.69</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037119</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC119</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>