<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8ddef93432d585c79f0b022c1debe760c4af35af.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-05T14:42:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.69cb0dac699bd9fda92543bb38c2e13ffb4940b6.001.1,2025-08-05T13:04:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-05T14:42:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-05T14:42:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-05T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 5 at 2:42PM EDT until August 5 at 7:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...Eastern two-thirds of Union County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 715 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.


* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 209 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicates that the heavy
rainfall responsible for nuisance flooding across the eastern
half of Union County has departed the area and additional
significant rainfall is not expected for the remainder of
today.  However, storm-total rainfall of 2-5 inches of
rainfall since about 4am this morning has resulted in
excessive runoff producing high flows and areas of nuisance
flooding.  Union County Emergency Management reported several
roads had experienced nuisance flood inundation in the
Twelvemile Creek watershed from Weddington to Waxhaw.  People
are urged to obey all barricades, even if flood waters have
receded, until crews can assess road safety.

Areas of immediate concern are in the northwestern portion of
Union County, where heavy rainfall persisted the longest.
There, Goose Creek is cresting above Minor Flood Stage,
likely causing flooding of Stevens Mill Rd and extensive
flooding of adjacent wooded areas.  The streamgauge at
Bearskin Creek and N Charlotte Ave is above Action Stage,
causing nuisance flooding of the Bearskin Creek Greenway
flooding from Dickerson Park downstream to Belk Tonowonda
Park near IB Shive Dr.  Floodwaters may also be impacting the
greenway and the baseball field at Don Griffin Park near
Meadow St.

It will take about 1-3 more hours for streams area wide to
crest and recede back below critical levels.  Therefore, the
Flood Advisory will continue into at least the late afternoon
hours to allow flood conditions to improve.

Areas of ongoing concern include:
1) along Goose Creek near Stevens Mill Rd, Mill Grove Rd, and
W Lawyers Rd
2) along North Fork Crooked Creek Near Idlewild Rd and Indian
Trail-Fairview Rd
3) along Bearskin Creek near Dickerson Park, N Charlotte Ave,
and Creft Park
4) along the East Fork Twelvemile Creek near Waxhaw-Indian
Trail Rd
5) along Camp Branch near S Rocky River Rd

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Monroe, Indian Trail, Weddington, Stallings, Unionville,
Wesley Chapel, Wingate, Waxhaw, Lake Park, Mineral Springs,
Hemby Bridge, Marvin, Fairview In Union County, Jaars,
Trinity, and New Salem.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 051842</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 715 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0096.000000T0000Z-250805T2315Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-05T19:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a14af1236ac5edfbb40a6fbe0b958ff4a0029d87.001.1,2025-08-05T10:22:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Union, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.17,-80.36 34.97,-80.42 34.82,-80.52 34.82,-80.8 34.94,-80.78 35.0,-80.84 35.03,-80.8 35.03,-80.77 35.21,-80.55 35.16,-80.44 35.17,-80.42 35.17,-80.39 35.18,-80.37 35.17,-80.36</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037179</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>