<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 04 Jun 2023 07:23:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12664DF9FA2C.BeachHazardsStatement.12664E064D40NC.MHXCFWMHX.c2a82f147a38b15fb728254a40f14498</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-06-04T15:23:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for East Carteret; Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-06-04T15:23:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-06-04T20:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City (Eastern North Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued June 04 at 3:23PM EDT until June 04 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City</headline>
<description>...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 2 AM EDT
MONDAY...
...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS
EVENING...
* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, 1 to 2 feet of inundation
above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal
waterways. For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip
currents, large breaking waves expected, and strong longshore
currents in the surf zone.
* WHERE...East Carteret County, Northern Outer Banks and Hatteras
Island.
* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 2 AM EDT Monday.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, through this evening.
* IMPACTS...1 to 2 feet of inundation above ground level is
possible in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways
resulting in a low threat of property damage. Some roads and low
lying property including parking lots, parks, lawns, and homes
adjacent to the waterfront will experience shallow flooding.
High tide is in between 8 and 10 PM tonight. Rip currents can
sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper water.
Dangerous shore break can throw a swimmer or surfer head first
into the bottom causing neck and back injuries. Strong longshore
currents will create dangerous swimming conditions.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occurred around 2 PM this afternoon.
Time of high total tides are approximate to the nearest hour.
Beaufort Marine Lab NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 5.0 ft, Moderate 5.5 ft, Major 6.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor -0.8 ft, Moderate -0.3 ft, Major 0.7 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
04/09 PM     5.6       -0.2        1.6        1     Moderate
05/09 AM     3.8       -2.0        1.4        1       None
05/10 PM     4.8       -1.0        0.8        1       None
06/10 AM     3.4       -2.4        1.0        1       None
06/10 PM     4.4       -1.4        0.8        1       None
07/11 AM     3.3       -2.5        0.8        1       None
Duck NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 5.5 ft, Moderate 6.0 ft, Major 6.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor 1.8 ft, Moderate 2.3 ft, Major 2.8 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
04/08 PM     5.9        2.2        1.7        6      Minor
05/09 AM     4.2        0.5        1.2        4       None
05/09 PM     5.3        1.6        1.0        3       None
06/10 AM     3.3       -0.4        0.2        3       None
06/10 PM     4.4        0.7        0.2       2-3      None
07/11 AM     3.5       -0.2        0.4        2       None
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.
Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.
Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.
Strong longshore currents can sweep swimmers and surfers into rip
currents, piers, jetties and other hazardous areas. In many
cases, the longshore current is strong enough to prevent swimmers
from being able to keep their feet on the bottom making it
difficult to return to shore.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ196-203-205</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMHX.CF.Y.0008.000000T0000Z-230605T0600Z/
/O.CON.KMHX.BH.S.0028.000000T0000Z-230605T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>East Carteret; Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ196</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ205</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>