<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 30 Aug 2023 06:15:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AL12665B724C7C.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B7F1DBCAL.TAEHLSTAE.b0d64e445330838de0660d3a9a9bee94</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-30T13:15:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coffee; Dale; Geneva; Henry; Houston (Alabama) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-30T13:15:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-30T21:15:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Tallahassee (the Florida Peninsula)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 30 at 1:15PM CDT  by NWS Tallahassee</headline>
<description>This product covers eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend, southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia
**IDALIA`S CORE MOVING ACROSS SOUTHEASTERN GEORGIA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning has been issued and the Hurricane
Warning has been cancelled for Brooks, Coastal Dixie, Coastal
Jefferson, Coastal Taylor, Coastal Wakulla, Inland Dixie,
Inland Jefferson, Inland Taylor, Lafayette, Madison, and Thomas
- The Hurricane Warning has been cancelled for Coastal Franklin,
Inland Wakulla, and Leon
- The Tropical Storm Warning has been cancelled for Baker,
Decatur, Dougherty, Gadsden, Grady, Inland Franklin, Lee,
Liberty, and Mitchell
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Coastal Dixie and Coastal Taylor
- A Hurricane Warning is in effect for Berrien, Cook, Lanier, and
Lowndes
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Ben Hill, Brooks,
Coastal Jefferson, Coastal Wakulla, Colquitt, Inland Dixie,
Inland Jefferson, Inland Taylor, Irwin, Lafayette, Madison,
Thomas, Tift, Turner, and Worth
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 130 miles north-northeast of Keaton Beach or about 60
miles northeast of Valdosta
- 31.4N 82.5W
- Storm Intensity 75 mph
- Movement Northeast or 35 degrees at 20 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
As of 2PM EDT, the center of Hurricane Idalia was moving northeast
through Southeast Georgia near 20 mph. Max sustained winds are now
around 75 mph - category one strength. Idalia continues to produce
areas of tropical storm force winds mostly along and east of the I-
75 corridor with embedded heavy rainfall making for a persisting flood
threat.
Impacts from strong winds and heavy rain will continue until Idalia
pulls farther away from the region later this afternoon. The threat
for dangerous storm surge also remains in place for the Nature Coast
where a Storm Surge Warning remains in effect. From Keaton Beach to
Suwannee River, forecast values are 5-8 feet with 2-4 feet forecast
from Aucilla River to Keaton Beach. Although water levels may be
subsiding a bit now, onshore flow from the south side of Idalia along
with high tide this afternoon could cause another peak in storm surge.
Adjustments will continue to be made as conditions improve.
Regardless, please continue to heed evacuation orders and advice from
local officials.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
South-Central Georgia. Remain well sheltered from life-threatening wind
having additional extensive impacts. If realized, these impacts
include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Elsewhere across eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend,
southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia, little to no additional
impact is anticipated.
* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are now unfolding across
the Eastern Florida Big Bend. Remain well away from life-threatening
surge having additional extensive impacts. If realized, these impacts
include:
- Large areas of deep inundation with storm surge flooding
accentuated by battering waves. Structural damage to buildings,
with several washing away. Damage compounded by floating
debris. Locations may be uninhabitable for an extended period.
- Large sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads
washed out or severely flooded. Flood control systems and
barriers may become stressed.
- Severe beach erosion with significant dune loss.
- Major damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers. Many
small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages with some lifted onshore and stranded.
Elsewhere across eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend,
southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia, little to no additional
impact is anticipated.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
South-Central Georgia. Remain well guarded against life-threatening
flood waters having additional extensive impacts. If realized, these
impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, and ditches may become
dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and barriers may become
stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Elsewhere across eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend,
southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia, little to no additional
impact is anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials
have given the all clear to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Keep your cell phone charged and in power-saving mode. If you lose
power, use it sparingly and mainly for personal emergencies and
check-ins.
Do not be a thrill seeker or risk your life for senseless photos or
videos.
Quickly move to the safest place within your shelter if it begins to
fail, preferably an interior room on the lowest floor as long as
flooding is not a concern.
If you are prone to flooding or in an area under a storm surge watch
or warning, be prepared for the possibility of a quick and dramatic
rise in water levels.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tallahassee FL around 5 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ065>069-FLZ007>019-026>029-034-108-112-114-115-118-127-128-134-GAZ120>131-142>148-155>161</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coffee; Dale; Geneva; Henry; Houston</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>001031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>001045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>001061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>001067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>001069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ066</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ069</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>