<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 30 Aug 2023 03:05:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12665B71D364.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B730FCCFL.TBWHLSTBW.6f27625c8cc9199e584dd5a666d96cd3</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-30T11:05:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Charlotte; Coastal Citrus; Coastal Hernando; Coastal Hillsborough; Coastal Lee; Coastal Levy; Coastal Manatee; Coastal Pasco; Coastal Sarasota; DeSoto; Hardee; Highlands; Inland Charlotte; Inland Citrus; Inland Hernando; Inland Hillsborough; Inland Lee; Inland Levy; Inland Manatee; Inland Pasco; Inland Sarasota; Pinellas; Polk; Sumter (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-30T11:13:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-30T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Tampa Bay (West Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 30 at 11:05AM EDT  by NWS Tampa Bay</headline>
<description>This product covers West Central and Southwest Florida
**LIFE-THREATENING STORM SURGE, TROPICAL STORM FORCE CONDITIONS
CONTINUE AS IDALIA MOVES AWAY**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning has been issued and the Hurricane
Warning has been cancelled for Coastal Citrus, Coastal
Hernando, Coastal Hillsborough, Coastal Levy, Coastal Manatee,
Coastal Pasco, Inland Citrus, Inland Hernando, Inland
Hillsborough, Inland Levy, Inland Manatee, Inland Pasco,
Pinellas, and Sumter
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Coastal Citrus, Coastal Hernando, Coastal Hillsborough,
Coastal Levy, Coastal Manatee, Coastal Pasco, Coastal Sarasota,
Inland Citrus, and Pinellas
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Coastal Charlotte and Coastal Lee
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for DeSoto, Hardee,
Inland Charlotte, Inland Hernando, Inland Hillsborough, Inland
Lee, Inland Levy, Inland Manatee, Inland Pasco, Inland
Sarasota, Polk, and Sumter
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 100 miles north of Cedar Key FL
- 30.6N 83.2W
- Storm Intensity 90 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 20 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Hurricane Idalia made landfall this morning as a Major Hurricane
near Keaton Beach, Florida. As Idalia continues move away, Tropical
Storm Force conditions continue across West Central and Southwest
Florida.
The following are the primary hazards of concern with Idalia:
* Storm Surge - Areas across West Central and Southwest Florida should
expect surge levels to remain nearly steady through the day as an
onshore wind keeps water piled up along the coast.
* Wind - Tropical storm force winds remain possible as outer rain
bands from Idalia move across the region.
* Rainfall - Heavy rainfall remains possible, with area rivers rising
into action of flood stage. Minor inland flooding in low- lying areas
with poor drainage remains possible. A Flood Watch also remains in
effect.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are now unfolding across
West Central and Southwest Florida. Remain well away from life-
threatening surge having additional devastating impacts. If realized,
these impacts include:
- Widespread deep inundation, with storm surge flooding greatly
accentuated by powerful battering waves. Structural damage to
buildings, with many washing away. Damage greatly compounded
from considerable floating debris. Locations may be
uninhabitable for an extended period.
- Near-shore escape routes and secondary roads washed out or
severely flooded. Flood control systems and barriers may become
stressed.
- Extreme beach erosion. New shoreline cuts possible.
- Massive damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers. Numerous
small craft broken away from moorings with many lifted onshore
and stranded.
* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
West Central and Southwest Florida. Remain well sheltered from
dangerous wind having additional significant impacts. If realized,
these impacts include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent in
areas with above ground lines.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
West Central and Southwest Florida. Remain well guarded against
dangerous flood waters having additional significant impacts. If
realized, these impacts include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with swifter
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams, creeks, canals, and
ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid inundation
at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage areas. Some
streets and parking lots take on moving water as storm drains and
retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions become hazardous.
Some road and bridge closures.
* TORNADOES:
Potential impacts from tornadoes are still unfolding across West
Central and Southwest Florida. Remain well braced against a tornado
event having additional limited impacts. If realized, these impacts
include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and boats pulled
from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Do not be a thrill seeker or risk your life for senseless photos or
videos.
If a tornado warning is issued for your area, quickly move to the
safest place within your shelter. Protect your head and body.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tampa Bay Ruskin FL around 6PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ043-050-052-056-057-061-139-142-148-149-151-155-160-162-165-239-242-248-249-251-255-260-262-265</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Charlotte; Coastal Citrus; Coastal Hernando; Coastal Hillsborough; Coastal Lee; Coastal Levy; Coastal Manatee; Coastal Pasco; Coastal Sarasota; DeSoto; Hardee; Highlands; Inland Charlotte; Inland Citrus; Inland Hernando; Inland Hillsborough; Inland Lee; Inland Levy; Inland Manatee; Inland Pasco; Inland Sarasota; Pinellas; Polk; Sumter</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012105</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012115</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012119</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ050</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ052</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ056</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ139</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ142</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ148</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ151</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ155</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ160</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ162</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ165</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ239</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ242</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ248</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ249</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ251</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ255</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ260</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ262</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ265</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>