<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 30 Aug 2023 09:26:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GA12665B70F138.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B722B48GA.FFCHLSFFC.9120ee9a6e16deb825aac364340b0d17</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-30T05:26:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Baldwin; Bibb; Bleckley; Crawford; Crisp; Dodge; Dooly; Emanuel; Glascock; Hancock; Houston; Jefferson; Johnson; Jones; Laurens; Macon; Montgomery; Peach; Pulaski; Schley; Sumter; Taylor; Telfair; Toombs; Treutlen; Twiggs; Warren; Washington; Wheeler; Wilcox; Wilkinson (Georgia) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-30T23:10:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-30T13:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Atlanta (Northern and Central Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 30 at 5:26AM EDT  by NWS Atlanta</headline>
<description>This product covers NORTH AND CENTRAL GEORGIA
**IDALIA IS EXPECTED TO BRING IMPACTS TO THE REGION TODAY THROUGH
THURSDAY MORNING**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Watch has been upgraded to a Tropical Storm
Warning for Baldwin, Bibb, Crawford, Hancock, Jones, Taylor,
and Warren
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Baldwin, Bibb,
Bleckley, Crawford, Crisp, Dodge, Dooly, Emanuel, Glascock,
Hancock, Houston, Jefferson, Johnson, Jones, Laurens, Macon,
Montgomery, Peach, Pulaski, Schley, Sumter, Taylor, Telfair,
Toombs, Treutlen, Twiggs, Warren, Washington, Wheeler, Wilcox,
and Wilkinson
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 260 miles south of Macon GA or about 240 miles
south-southwest of Vidalia GA
- 29.1N 84.1W
- Storm Intensity 130 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 25 degrees at 18 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Hurricane Idalia has become a major hurricane and will continue to
track northward across the eastern Gulf of Mexico with additional
strengthening expected before landfall this morning. Idalia is
forecast to track over portions of central and east Georgia late this
morning and through the afternoon.
Local impacts from Idalia will begin as early as this morning as heavy
rainfall begins to overspread southeast central Georgia from southwest
to northeast. Heavy rainfall will then continue through this afternoon
and tonight across the region with 4 to 9 inches of rainfall forecast,
with locally higher amounts possible. Tropical Storm force winds are
expected to occur across portions of central and east Georgia this
afternoon and evening. Tornadoes will be possible primarily across
southeast Georgia this morning and afternoon, particularly in tropical
rainbands.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Protect against dangerous wind having possible significant impacts
across portions of central and east Georgia. Potential impacts in this
area include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent
in areas with above ground lines.
Also, protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts
across west-central Georgia.
Elsewhere across NORTH AND CENTRAL GEORGIA, little to no impact is
anticipated.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across portions of central and east Georgia.
Potential impacts include:
- Major flooding from heavy rainfall may prompt many evacuations
and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, and ditches may become
dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and barriers may become
stressed.
- In areas experiencing the most significant flooding, flood waters
may enter structures, with some becoming uninhabitable. Roadways,
including escape routes, may become impassable where significant
flooding occurs. Streets and parking lots may become rivers of
moving water with underpasses submerged. Driving conditions will
become dangerous. Flooding may result in the closures of many
roads and bridges, with some becoming weakened or washed out.
Protect against dangerous flooding having possible limited to
significant impacts in portions of west-central Georgia.
Elsewhere across NORTH AND CENTRAL GEORGIA, little to no impact is
anticipated.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a dangerous tornado event having possible significant
impacts across southeast Georgia. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of scattered tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- Several places may experience tornado damage with a few spots
of considerable damage, power loss, and communications failures.
- Locations could realize roofs torn off frame houses, mobile
homes demolished, boxcars overturned, large trees snapped or
uprooted, vehicles tumbled, and small boats tossed about.
Dangerous projectiles can add to the toll.
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across central Georgia.
Elsewhere across NORTH AND CENTRAL GEORGIA, little to no impact is
anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
If heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or have
pets. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.
Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.
Keep cell phones well charged. Cell phone chargers for automobiles
can be helpful, but be aware of your risk for deadly carbon monoxide
poisoning if your car is left idling in a garage or other poorly
ventilated area.
If you are a visitor, be sure to know the name of the city or town in
which you are staying and the name of the county or parish in which
it resides. Listen for these locations in local news updates. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
If a Tornado Warning is issued for your area, be ready to shelter
quickly, preferably away from windows and in an interior room not
prone to flooding. If driving, scan the roadside for quick shelter
options.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, consider moving to a safer shelter before the onset of
strong winds or flooding.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on creating an emergency plan see ready.ga.gov
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Peachtree City GA around 11 AM, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ061-062-072>076-080>086-092>098-104>113</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Baldwin; Bibb; Bleckley; Crawford; Crisp; Dodge; Dooly; Emanuel; Glascock; Hancock; Houston; Jefferson; Johnson; Jones; Laurens; Macon; Montgomery; Peach; Pulaski; Schley; Sumter; Taylor; Telfair; Toombs; Treutlen; Twiggs; Warren; Washington; Wheeler; Wilcox; Wilkinson</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013125</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013153</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013163</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013167</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013169</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013175</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013193</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013209</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013225</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013235</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013249</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013261</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013269</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013271</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013279</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013283</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013289</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013301</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013303</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013309</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013315</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013319</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ062</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ072</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ074</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ076</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ082</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ083</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ084</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ086</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ092</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ094</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ096</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ098</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ104</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ105</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ106</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ108</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ110</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ112</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ113</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>