<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.bfe81ddae0b81267271cd8ba5269891d0fbd4ffc.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-24T15:21:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-24T15:21:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-24T15:21:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-24T18:30:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Hanford CA</senderName>
        <headline>Flash Flood Warning issued August 24 at 3:21PM PDT until August 24 at 6:30PM PDT by NWS Hanford CA</headline>
        <description>FFWHNX

The National Weather Service in Hanford has issued a

* Flash Flood Warning for...
North Central Tulare County in central California...

* Until 630 PM PDT.

* At 321 PM PDT, Doppler radar indicated thunderstorms producing
heavy rain across the warned area. Between 1 and 2 inches of rain
have fallen. The expected rainfall rate is 0.25 to 0.75 inches in
1 hour. Additional rainfall amounts of 0.5 to 2 inches are
possible in the warned area. Flash flooding is ongoing or expected
to begin shortly.

HAZARD...Flash flooding caused by thunderstorms.

SOURCE...Radar.

IMPACT...Flash flooding of small creeks and streams, urban
areas, highways, streets and underpasses as well as
other poor drainage and low-lying areas.

* Some locations that will experience flash flooding include...
Atwell Mill Campground, Cold Springs Campground, Mineral King
Ranger Station, Wolverton Point, Redwood Meadow Patrol Cabin,
Hockett Meadow Ranger Station, Farewell Gap, Bearpaw Ranger
Station, Little Five Lakes Ranger Station, Wet Meadows, South Fork
Campground, Pear Lake Ranger Station, Marble Fork Kaweah,
Lodgepole Campground and Lodgepole.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.

Remain alert for flooding even in locations not receiving rain.
Arroyos, streams, and rivers can become raging killer currents in a
matter of minutes, even from distant rainfall.

Move away from recently burned areas. Life-threatening flooding of
creeks, roads and normally dry arroyos is possible. The heavy rains
can trigger rockslides, mudslides and debris flows in steep terrain,
especially in and around these areas.

Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.

Please report observed flooding to local emergency services or law
enforcement and request they pass this information to the National
Weather Service when you can do so safely.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFWHNX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS56 KHNX 242221</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDetection</valueName>
            <value>RADAR INDICATED</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KHNX.FF.W.0007.250824T2221Z-250825T0130Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-24T18:30:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Tulare, CA</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.61,-118.56 36.42,-118.51 36.27,-118.64 36.34,-118.78 36.61,-118.74 36.61,-118.56</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006107</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAC107</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>