<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8460f08627d3d0a776c6105dbaa470af1a9e1914.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-13T05:46:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7e20cce8d1366bef89b66461317b3048e9a5536a.001.1,2025-08-12T21:58:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.926381d165755968a859dfa8a9a29a93c9dcc0b8.001.1,2025-08-13T00:53:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6b8e47c1a35a731e100bf4ab4e7f378b39715a13.001.1,2025-08-13T04:00:00-08:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-13T05:46:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-13T05:46:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-13T14:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued August 13 at 5:46AM AKDT until August 14 at 8:00AM AKDT by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>USGS laser gauge data from Suicide basin and a rise in Mendenhall
Lake levels indicates a release from the basin is ongoing. The
Mendenhall River crossed into Major Flood stage of 14ft as of 1225AM
Wednesday and has crossed 2024 record flood stage of 16ft as of
520am. A crest is expected Wednesday morning with near record levels
around 16.75 feet.

* WHAT...Flooding caused by a glacier-dammed lake outburst continues.

* WHERE...The Mendenhall Lake and River near areas around the
glacier visitor center, the Mendenhall campground, Skaters Cabin
Road, View Drive and possibly below Back Loop bridge.

* WHEN...Until 800 AM AKDT Thursday.

* IMPACTS...Flooding near Mendenhall Lake and River locations is
occurring.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 545 AM AKDT, gauge reports indicated a glacier-dammed lake
outburst across the warned area. Major Flooding is ongoing,
especially near the Mendenhall Lake and River.

- The outburst flood forecast is based on an estimated volume
of water in the glacier dammed lake and an estimated release
rate based on previous events.  The extent of water drainage
within the basin (partial or full) can vary widely between
outburst flood events and is a major source of uncertainty in
the forecast, particularly with regard to the peak flood
stage.

- For Mendenhall Lake:
At 5:30am the stage was 16.1 feet and rising, in Major Flood
Stage, exceeding the previous record flood stage from 2024.
Flood Stage is 9.0 feet.
Forecast: A record crest between 16.25 and 16.75 feet is
expected between 8am and 12pm Wednesday, with increased
forecast confidence of river crest around 8am near 16.75
feet.
Water levels will go below major flood stage around Wednesday
night.

Impacts:
At 11.0 feet: Some homes along View Dr will have up to 1.5
feet of water in yards. Locations below back loop bridge will
see bank erosion along unreinforced river banks along with
hazardous navigation from debris in the river. Homes along
the river on Meander Way will begin to see flooding of some
backyards on the outside of the HESCO levee. Portions of the
Dredge Lake Trail System will be impassable. Flood waters
start to reach Dredge Lake.

At 11.5 feet: The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
begin to flood along with water approaching some homes
towards the end of road.

At 12.0 feet: Significant bank erosion along unreinforced
river banks. The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
be flooded with up to 0.5 feet of water. Some houses on the
south side and the east end of View Dr will start to flood.
Water begins to flood some backyards of homes on the
northside of View Dr as well as other low lying areas. Back
Loop Rd Bridge will be closed during outburst events.

At 12.5 feet: 2 to 4 feet of water in some backyards along
Meander Way on the the river side of the HESCO levee.

At 13.0 feet: The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
be flooded with 2 ft of water. Water begins to flow through
some backyards of homes on the northside of View Dr and flood
low lying areas. A few locations on View Dr will see depths
of 1 to 2 feet of water in homes.

At 13.5 feet: Water starts to back up behind homes between
Riverside Dr at Tournure St and Mendenhall River School.
Locations on River Rd with low river banks will begin to see
water inundate yards. Severe bank erosion along unreinforced
river banks.

At 14.0 feet: The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
be significantly flooded and impassable. Water will begin to
flow over the road from water flowing behind homes on the
north side of View Dr. More homes along View Dr will begin to
see moderate to major flooding. Locations on River Rd with
low river banks will begin to see water approach driveways.

At 15.0 feet: Major flooding of multiple homes along View Dr.
Water will begin to approach a few homes along River Rd with
low river banks with possible flooding of driveways and 1 to
2 feet of water in backyards. Up to 1 foot of water covering
Riverside Dr at Tournure St and Mendenhall River School.

At 16.0 feet: Water starts to overtop the bank and flood low
lying areas near Wildmeadow Ln. Up to 0.5 feet of water will
be in the intersection of Skaters Cabin Rd and Arctic Cir.
Some backyards of homes between Tamarack Ct and Whitewater Ct
will start to see flood waters along with water approaching
River Rd near homes with low river banks and possibly
flooding those homes. Water will start to flood backyards of
homes on Meadow Ln and Stikine St.

At 17.0 feet: This is an estimate that water will be
overtopping the river banks and flooding into the homes
around Wildmeadow Ln. Businesses in the Vintage Park Blvd
area will be surrounded and potentially inundated by flood
waters. Homes on Meadow Ln from Stikine St to Eagle St will
be inundated with flood water. Water will be covering
Tournure St from Riverside Dr to Columbia Blvd. Black Wolf
Way and Pond Vista Dr will have water across the roads. All
parts of View Dr will be covered by flood water.
</description>
        <instruction>Please report observed flooding to local emergency services or law
enforcement via 911 or the Flood Hotline at 500-0890 when you can do
so safely.

Mariners within Stephens Passage should be advised and exercise
caution as numerous trees and and debris have been reported in the
river and may have washed downstream.

The cold water temperatures can increase the threat of hypothermia
and lower the time required to cause hypothermia.

Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK87 PAJK 131346</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING FOR A GLACIER-DAMMED LAKE OUTBURST REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 AM AKDT THURSDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PAJK.FA.W.0002.000000T0000Z-250814T1600Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-14T08:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.45377cd1f535a47e0bb87e591e884c8b9c37e636.001.1,2025-08-12T18:44:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.4f6d0305c76e4c7ed8ef5926239e855f93b2c7f8.001.1,2025-08-12T18:29:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a3f418437a93b688d2866afebf0414bfb3954fda.001.1,2025-08-12T17:03:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6531ad51c5205a9849a8788e5d714717e792e360.001.1,2025-08-12T16:59:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7f45b8f056c815e605d0c03ae07ff830c2e383b6.001.1,2025-08-12T12:48:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.3df44b6250316e7ed5b6b5e9df6925472f013848.001.1,2025-08-12T10:31:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>City and Borough of Juneau</areaDesc>
            <polygon>58.41,-134.6 58.42,-134.6 58.45,-134.6 58.47,-134.56 58.46,-134.52 58.44,-134.47 58.43,-134.47 58.4,-134.54 58.36,-134.59 58.35,-134.6 58.36,-134.62 58.41,-134.6</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ325</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>