<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.9510ffc65723898da00c69de192093aeb2527324.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-13T00:58:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Blowing Dust Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>DUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-13T00:58:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-13T17:00:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-13T15:30:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Phoenix AZ</senderName>
        <headline>Blowing Dust Advisory issued August 13 at 12:58AM MST until August 13 at 9:00PM MST by NWS Phoenix AZ</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Extreme Heat Warning, dangerously hot conditions.
Afternoon temperatures 105 to 111. Major Heat Risk. For the
Blowing Dust Advisory, visibility between one-quarter and one mile
in blowing dust expected.

* WHERE...Northwest Pinal County.

* WHEN...For the Extreme Heat Warning, until 8 PM MST this evening.
For the Blowing Dust Advisory, from 5 PM this afternoon to 9 PM
MST this evening.

* IMPACTS...Hazardous driving conditions due to reduced visibility.
Heat related illnesses increase significantly during extreme heat
events. Overexposure can cause heat cramps and heat exhaustion to
develop and, without intervention, can lead to heat stroke.
</description>
        <instruction>Persons with respiratory problems should make preparations to stay
indoors until the storm passes. Be ready for a sudden drop in
visibility to near zero. If you encounter blowing dust or blowing
sand on the roadway or see it approaching, pull off the road as far
as possible and put your vehicle in park. Turn the lights all the
way off and keep foot off the brake pedal. Remember, 'Pull Aside,
Stay Alive'.

An Extreme Heat Warning means that a period of very hot
temperatures, even by local standards, will occur. Actions should be
taken to lessen the impact of the extreme heat.

Take extra precautions if you work or spend time outside. When
possible, reschedule strenuous activities to early morning or
evening. Know the signs and symptoms of heat exhaustion and heat
stroke. Wear lightweight and loose-fitting clothing when possible
and drink plenty of water.

To reduce risk during outdoor work, the Occupational Safety and
Health Administration recommends scheduling frequent rest breaks in
shaded or air conditioned environments. Anyone overcome by heat
should be moved to a cool and shaded location. Heat stroke is an
emergency! Call 9 1 1.

Public cooling shelters are available in some areas. Consult county
officials for more details.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>NPWPSR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS75 KPSR 130758</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>EXTREME HEAT WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM MST THIS EVENING... ...BLOWING DUST ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 5 PM THIS AFTERNOON TO 9 PM MST THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KPSR.DU.Y.0007.250814T0000Z-250814T0400Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-13T21:00:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northwest Pinal County</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004021</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ553</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>