<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.4e8e596e0f10a06dc19da375043c8ec9d256ba75.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-13T00:47:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Blowing Dust Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>DUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-13T00:47:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-13T14:00:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-13T23:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tucson AZ</senderName>
        <headline>Blowing Dust Advisory issued August 13 at 12:47AM MST until August 13 at 11:00PM MST by NWS Tucson AZ</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Strong and gusty thunderstorm outflows between 40-45 mph
are expected to produce blowing dust today, possibly developing
into a haboob. Organized outflows will generally move west across
Southeast Arizona with locations south and east of Tucson impacted
this afternoon, then locations across Pima and Southeast Pinal
counties impacted during the late afternoon and evening hours.
Visibility between one-quarter and one mile in blowing dust are
expected.

* WHERE...Eastern Cochise County below 5000 feet, South Central
Pinal County, Southeast Pinal County, Tohono O'odham Nation,
Tucson Metro Area, Upper Gila River Valley, Upper San Pedro River
Valley, Upper Santa Cruz River Valley/Altar Valley, and Western
Pima County.

* WHEN...From 2 PM this afternoon to 11 PM MST this evening.

* IMPACTS...Blowing dust can restrict visibilities below a mile
posing a significant hazard to motorists, especially those
traveling along Interstate 10 through the San Simon Valley near
the Arizona and New Mexico border this afternoon...and between
Tucson and Phoenix late this afternoon and evening. In addition,
strong and gusty winds will likely suspend dust into the air that
people and animals breathe. Individuals with heart disease and
respiratory sensitivities may want to reduce their level of
exertion to limit the dust they breathe into their lungs,
especially if they are near dust prone locations. Those most at
risk may feel better if they avoid outside exercise today, keeping
windows and doors closed to help reduce exposure.
</description>
        <instruction>Persons with respiratory problems should make preparations to stay
indoors until the storm passes. Be ready for a sudden drop in
visibility to near zero. If you encounter blowing dust or blowing
sand on the roadway or see it approaching, pull off the road as far
as possible and put your vehicle in park. Turn the lights all the
way off and keep foot off the brake pedal. Remember, 'Pull Aside,
Stay Alive'.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>NPWTWC</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS75 KTWC 130747</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BLOWING DUST ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM THIS AFTERNOON TO 11 PM MST THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KTWC.DU.Y.0014.250813T2100Z-250814T0600Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-13T23:00:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Western Pima County Including Ajo/Organ Pipe Cactus National Monument; Tohono O'odham Nation including Sells; Upper Santa Cruz River and Altar Valleys including Nogales; Tucson Metro Area including Tucson/Green Valley/Marana/Vail; South Central Pinal County including Eloy/Picacho Peak State Park; Southeast Pinal County including Kearny/Mammoth/Oracle; Upper San Pedro River Valley including Sierra Vista/Benson; Eastern Cochise County Below 5000 Feet including Douglas/Willcox; Upper Gila River and Aravaipa Valleys including Clifton/Safford</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004021</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004003</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ501</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ502</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ503</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ504</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ505</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ506</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ507</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ508</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZZ509</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>