<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 18 Apr 2022 09:02:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SD1263EED664D8.ExtremeFireDanger.1263EED6DF1CSD.FSDRFDFSD.303ed5331d4368b568678d71fe30769f</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-04-18T03:02:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Clay; Union (South Dakota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Extreme Fire Danger</event>
<urgency>Unknown</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Unknown</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-04-18T12:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-04-18T06:15:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Sioux Falls (Southeastern SD, Southwestern MN, and Northwestern IA)</senderName>
<headline>Extreme Fire Danger issued April 18 at 3:02AM MDT  by NWS Sioux Falls</headline>
<description>.DISCUSSION...
High to extreme fire weather conditions return to the region due to
breezy and dry winds from the northwest. Shortly after sunrise, wind
gusts 30 to 40 mph will be common across majority of the region,
though areas west of the James will likely remain below 30 mph. As
drier air is mixed down from the mid-levels during the afternoon
hours resulting in relative humidity values of 20 to 30 percent for
areas outside of SW MN, winds will be decreasing from west to east
during the afternoon hours, and should keep Red Flag conditions from
occurring for portions of central SD. Area of most concern is along
the SD/NE/IA border where RH`s could dip down into the upper teens,
and have thus issued a Red Flag Warning for those locations.
Tuesday will be another day where high to very high fire danger is
likely as SE winds will likely gust to 45 mph in central SD, with
low relative humidity values at or below 30 percent. Cloud coverage
will likely help limit deep mixing keeping RH values above the
critical thresholds, but the strong winds will still result in high
to very high fire danger. Chances for light rain return Tuesday
evening into Wednesday.
People are urged to exercise extreme care with respect to outdoor
activities that could cause grass fires. Avoid equipment that can
cause sparks near dry grass or brush. Do not toss cigarettes on
the ground. Report new fires quickly to the nearest fire
department or law enforcement office.
...EXTREME FIRE DANGER...
The Grassland Fire Danger Index will reach the extreme category
this afternoon. Extreme weather conditions and very low
moisture content of grasses, and other dry organic material
on the ground, indicate that critical burning conditions exist.
All fires have the potential to become large and spread quickly,
becoming erratic with extreme behavioral characteristics.
No outdoor burning should take place.
OUTLOOK FOR TUESDAY AFTERNOON...The Grassland Fire Danger Index
will reach the high category.
The grassland fire danger product reflects fire danger for native
grasses. It is not intended for cured agricultural crops, nor
will it reflect conditions in road ditches which have been mowed.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>IAZ020-031-NEZ013-014-SDZ070-071</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Clay; Union</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>046027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>046127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SDZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SDZ071</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>