<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5ffa268ce57cb69a4f4c423a40d583feb47f1efd.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-12T16:01:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-12T16:01:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-12T16:01:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-12T21:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 12 at 4:01PM EDT until August 12 at 9:45PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
developing.

* WHERE...A portion of central Union County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 945 PM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 343 PM EDT, The NCEM streamgauge on Bearskin Creek at N
Charlotte Ave in Monroe has exceeded the Action Stage of 8.0
feet, indicating nuisance flooding is developing in isolated
areas adjacent to the creek, especially in Dickerson Park
along the greenway.  This is response to earlier moderate
rainfall in the headwaters of the Bearskin Creek watershed
near Monroe Regional Airport, where isolated 1-1.25"
accumulations occurred between 11AM and noon.

Bearskin Creek is currently at 8.16' and rising.  Expect
Bearskin Creek to crest between 8.5 and 9.0 feet within the
next 1-2 hours.  A crest slightly above 9.0 feet is possible.
At 9.0 feet, Bearskin Creek Greenway flooding is expanding
from Dickerson Park downstream to Belk Tonowonda Park near IB
Shive Dr.  Floodwaters are beginning to impact the greenway
and the baseball field at Don Griffin Park near Meadow St.

- Saturated soils and ongoing runoff from multiple days of
rainfall are making area streams extremely sensitive to
enhanced runoff.  Areas of nuisance flooding adjacent to
small streams are possible for rainfall accumulations that
are typically too low to cause significant rises.  Maintain
awareness when adjacent to streams, including along greenways
and in parks, whenever rainfall is occurring, and be aware of
rapidly rising streams.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Monroe.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 122001</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 945 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0104.250812T2001Z-250813T0145Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-12T21:45:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Union, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>34.98,-80.55 34.98,-80.58 34.98,-80.61 35.0,-80.62 35.01,-80.6 35.01,-80.59 35.0,-80.56 35.0,-80.51 34.99,-80.51 34.98,-80.55</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037179</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>