<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8b8ce0c76d551733d45ce82d9b9e3f70066b93e4.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-12T02:11:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-12T02:11:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-12T02:11:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-12T10:15:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 12 at 2:11AM AKDT until August 12 at 12:00PM AKDT by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>Long duration moderate to heavy rainfall that started over the
weekend and lasted through Monday has resulted in a rise on the
Mendenhall River into Minor Flood stage. Similar rises are being
seen on rivers around the area like the Herbert and Taku River. The
rise on the Mendenhall River is NOT related to a Glacial Lake
Outburst Flood (GLOF). The rise on the Mendenhall River is due to
heavier rainfall and runoff, it is NOT due to a Glacial Lake
Outburst Flood (GLOF) from Suicide Basin.  Suicide Basin is NOT
releasing and continues to be monitored. The heaviest rainfall will
come to an end through early Tuesday morning, with the Mendenhall
River expected to fall back below Flood Stage through Tuesday
morning. Drier conditions expected for Tuesday and Wednesday,
allowing for the Mendenhall River to continue to fall.

* WHAT...Minor Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is ongoing.

* WHERE...Mendenhall Lake and River near areas around Skaters Cabin
Road, Mendenhall campground, and View Drive.

* WHEN...Until noon AKDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in low-lying and poor drainage areas.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 200 AM AKDT, gauge reports indicated moderate to heavy
rain ongoing across the advisory area. Minor flooding is
ongoing  especially near Mendenhall Lake and River area.
Between 1.5 and 3 inches of rain have fallen in the last
24hrs and between 3 to 5 inches in the last 72hrs across the
Advisory area. Additional rainfall amounts of 0.25 to 0.75
inches possible through early Tuesday morning. Rainfall
intensity and amounts will decrease through early Tuesday
morning, with drier conditions expected through the day
Tuesday and Wednesday.
- The rise into flood stage on the Mendenhall River is due to
excessive rainfall from the long duration rain event from the
previous weekend.  This is NOT the result of a Glacial Lake
Outburst Flood (GLOF) from Suicide Basin.  Suicide Basin is
NOT releasing and continues to be monitored. Similar rises
are being seen on rivers around the area like the Herbert and
Taku River.

- For Mendenhall Lake :
-At 2:00am the stage was 9 feet and slowly rising.
-Flood Stage is 9 feet.
-Forecast: A crest around 9.2 feet is expected around 4:00am
Tuesday.
-Water levels should go below Minor Flood Stage around 8:00am
Tuesday.
-Water levels should go below Action Stage stage around
3:00pm Tuesday.
</description>
        <instruction>Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.

Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding like bank erosion and fallen trees.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK87 PAJK 121011</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL NOON AKDT TODAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.PAJK.FA.Y.0011.250812T1011Z-250812T2000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-12T12:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>City and Borough of Juneau</areaDesc>
            <polygon>58.45,-134.62 58.44,-134.55 58.43,-134.53 58.42,-134.53 58.41,-134.53 58.4,-134.55 58.38,-134.57 58.37,-134.58 58.35,-134.6 58.35,-134.61 58.38,-134.65 58.45,-134.62</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ325</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>