<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2635bfa440971bd6e5dbc5c6b6a9a34efb8fd7b1.002.3</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-17T20:24:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b43b068f458430b83180b2eae01e962e8a1bab4f.002.2,2025-08-17T14:00:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>CFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-17T20:24:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T12:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-18T08:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Watch issued August 17 at 8:24PM EDT until August 22 at 8:00AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents. For
the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 15 to 20+ feet
expected in the surf zone. For the Coastal Flood Watch,
significant oceanside inundation above ground level likely in
low- lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways.

* WHERE...East Carteret County, and Northern Outer Banks,
Ocracoke Island and Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 7 AM EDT Monday
through Monday evening. For the High Surf Advisory, from noon
Tuesday to 8 AM EDT Friday. For the Coastal Flood Watch, from
Tuesday afternoon through Friday morning.

* IMPACTS...Extreme beach and coastal damage is likely along the
oceanside, resulting in a significant threat to life and
property. Large dangerous waves will likely inundate and destroy
protective dune structures. Severe flooding will likely extend
inland from the waterfront causing flooding of many homes and
businesses with some structural damage possible. Numerous roads
will likely be impassable under several feet of water and
vehicles will likely be submerged. Actions will need to be taken
to protect life and property. Very dangerous swimming and
surfing conditions expected, as well as the wave action
resulting in significant beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep
even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper water.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...This is expected to be a prolonged duration
event, with the potential for portions of NC-12 and secondary
roads along the Outer Banks, in particular on Hatteras and
Ocracoke Islands, to be impassable and/or inaccessible for
several days due to significant wave run up. Minor soundside
flooding will also be possible if stronger winds develop over
the Pamlico Sound.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 180024</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT FROM 7 AM EDT MONDAY THROUGH MONDAY EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM NOON TUESDAY TO 8 AM EDT FRIDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH FRIDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KMHX.CF.A.0001.250819T1600Z-250822T1200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-22T08:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Carteret; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>