<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 09 Jan 2024 02:30:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-OR1268848403D8.WinterStormWarning.126884A059C0OR.MFRWSWMFR.331718982a8e9a1a8ebd8922a1d95843</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-09T06:30:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Central Douglas County; Eastern Curry County and Josephine County; Jackson County (Oregon) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-09T06:30:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-10T16:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Medford (Southwest Oregon and Northern California)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Warning issued January 09 at 6:30AM PST until January 10 at 4:00PM PST by NWS Medford</headline>
<description>...WINTER STORM WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 4 PM PST
WEDNESDAY ABOVE 2000 FEET...
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 10 PM THIS
EVENING TO 9 AM PST WEDNESDAY...
* WHAT...Heavy snow and blowing snow expected above 2000 feet.
Total snow accumulations of up to 12 inches, with up to 24
inches possible over the highest terrain. Winds gusting as high
as 55 mph. For the Winter Weather Advisory, snow expected. Total
snow accumulations of 1 to 3 inches with local amounts up to 5
inches. Snow impacts will be above 3000 feet elevation this
morning, lowering to 2000 feet by this evening and down to
around 1500 feet and locally lower tonight into Wednesday.
* WHERE...For the Winter Storm Warning, the foothills of the
Cascade, Siskiyou, and the high terrain of the Kalmiopsis
wilderness mountains in Douglas, Jackson, and eastern Curry
counties, including the Tiller-Trail highway and portions of
Interstate 5 and highways 62 and 140 above 2000 feet. For the
Winter Weather Advisory, portions of Interstate 5 from Ashland
to Rogue River and the passes between Grants Pass and
Roseburg, Hays Hill Summit, Jacksonville Hill, highways 62,
234, 140, 238, 42 near Camas Mountain, and 46 east of Cave
Junction. This includes the cities of Ashland, Medford,
Talent, White City, Eagle Point, Gold Hill, Rogue River, and
Applegate.
* WHEN...For the Winter Storm Warning, from 1 AM Tuesday to 4 PM
PST Wednesday. For the Winter Weather Advisory, from 10 PM
Tuesday to 9 AM PST Wednesday.
* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult to impossible. Patchy
blowing snow could significantly reduce visibility. The
hazardous conditions could impact the morning or evening
commute. Gusty winds could bring down tree branches.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for this to occur
will be Tuesday night into Wednesday evening. Snow
accumulations in the valleys will be tricky and much will
depend on the intensity of precipitation that comes in later
Tuesday night into Wednesday morning.
* View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr</description>
<instruction>* Travel is strongly discouraged because of dangerous
conditions. Do not detour during winter storms.
* If you must travel, keep tire chains, a flashlight, blankets,
food, water, medications, and a fully charged phone with you.
* The safest place during a winter storm is indoors.
* A Winter Storm Warning means that severe winter weather is
likely and poses a threat to life and property. Take
protective action now.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ023-024-026</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMFR.WS.W.0003.000000T0000Z-240111T0000Z/
/O.CON.KMFR.WW.Y.0002.240110T0600Z-240110T1700Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Central Douglas County; Eastern Curry County and Josephine County; Jackson County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ024</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ026</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>