<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 10 Jan 2024 02:11:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-WY1268849169EC.SnowSquallWarning.126884918CB0WY.RIWSQWRIW.74dbf67ab4282bb4b4b428539b8e41a2</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-09T19:11:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Sweetwater (Wyoming) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Snow Squall Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Extreme</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SQW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-09T19:11:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-09T20:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Riverton (Western Wyoming)</senderName>
<headline>Snow Squall Warning issued January 09 at 7:11PM MST until January 09 at 8:00PM MST by NWS Riverton</headline>
<description>The National Weather Service in Riverton has issued a
* Snow Squall Warning for...
Southwestern Sweetwater County in south central Wyoming...
* Until 800 PM MST.
* At 710 PM MST, a dangerous snow squall was located along a line
extending from Rock Springs to 6 miles east of Little America,
moving southeast at 30 mph.
HAZARD...Intense bursts of heavy snow. Gusty winds leading to
blowing snow and rapidly falling visibility. Wind gusts
greater than 50 mph could knock down tree limbs and blow
around unsecured objects.
SOURCE...Radar and webcams.
IMPACT...Travel will become difficult and potentially dangerous
within minutes.
This includes Interstate 80 between mile markers 77 and 119.
Locations impacted include...
Rock Springs, Green River, Buckboard Marina, Squaw Hollow Boat Ramp
On Flaming Gorge, Southwest Wyoming Regional Airport, and Flaming
Gorge National Recreation Area.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
Slow Down! Rapid changes in visibility and road conditions are
expected with this dangerous snow squall. Be alert for sudden
whiteout conditions.
Reduce speed and turn on headlights! During snow squalls, the
visibility may suddenly drop to near zero in whiteout conditions.
Consider avoiding or delaying travel until the snow squall passes
your location. If you must travel, use extra caution and allow extra
time. Rapid changes in visibility and slick road conditions may lead
to accidents.
If traveling on a highway, find the nearest exit or rest area and
park safely away from traffic. Allow snow squalls to pass before
attempting to resume travel.
There is no safe place on a highway when a snow squall hits.
Visibility and traction are immediately lost in whiteout conditions,
making it difficult or impossible to slow down and avoid stopped
vehicles. Delay travel or safely exit the highway before the snow
squall arrives.
Serious injuries and deaths may result from people exiting their
vehicles during a snow squall. Drivers may not be able to see you or
stop! If you have been involved in an accident or pulled to the side
of the roadway, quickly exit your vehicle and move as far away from
the roadway as possible ONLY when it is safe to do so. Do not stand
along or near the roadway, since approaching vehicles may be unable
to maintain control.
SNOW SQUALL...OBSERVED</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WYC037</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KRIW.SQ.W.0002.240110T0211Z-240110T0300Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Sweetwater</areaDesc>
<polygon>41.25,-108.7 41.09,-109.69 41.56,-109.71 41.6,-109.31 41.68,-108.99 41.25,-108.7 41.25,-108.7</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>056037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WYC037</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>