<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 11 Aug 2022 04:16:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-OR126406425B40.RedFlagWarning.126406519740OR.MFRRFWMFR.f1f995129415a042f8fb37a759c95400</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-08-10T21:16:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Klamath Basin and the Fremont-Winema National Forest (Oregon) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Red Flag Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FRW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-08-11T14:00:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2022-08-11T21:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Medford (Southwest Oregon and Northern California)</senderName>
<headline>Red Flag Warning issued August 10 at 9:16PM PDT until August 11 at 9:00PM PDT by NWS Medford</headline>
<description>...Very Low RH and Gusty Winds in FWZs 284, 285, and 624 Thu &amp; Fri
PMs...
.Gusty south to southwest winds combined with very low RH will
lead to critical fire weather conditions Thursday afternoon and
evening and, likely, again Friday afternoon and evening across
portions of south central Oregon and northeastern California.
...RED FLAG WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM TO 9 PM PDT THURSDAY FOR
STRONG GUSTY WIND WITH LOW RH FOR PORTIONS OF FIRE WEATHER ZONES
284 AND 285 IN CALIFORNIA AND PORTIONS OF FIRE WEATHER ZONE 624 IN
OREGON...
...FIRE WEATHER WATCH IN EFFECT FROM FRIDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH
FRIDAY EVENING FOR STRONG GUSTY WIND WITH LOW RH FOR PORTIONS OF
FIRE WEATHER ZONES 284...285 AND 624...
The National Weather Service in Medford has issued a Fire Weather
Watch...which is in effect from Friday afternoon through Friday
evening.
* Impacts: Strong, gusty wind with low relative humidity and
critically dry vegetation will greatly increase the spread
potential of any new and existing fires.
* Affected area:
- In Northern CA, the northeastern portion of Fire Weather Zone
284 including Lava Beds and Tule Lake as well as northern and
eastern portions of Fire Weather Zone 285 including the Modoc
Plateau, areas near and east of Alturas, and the Warner
Mountains.
- In South Central OR, the southeastern portion of Fire Weather
Zone 624 including much of Winter Rim, Bonanza, Bly, Lakeview,
and Valley Falls.
* Wind: South 10 to 20 mph with gusts 25 to 35 mph.
* Humidity: 7 to 15 percent.
* View the hazard area in detail at:
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/mfr/HAZARD
Precautionary/preparedness actions...
Avoid tossing burning cigarettes on the ground, parking hot
vehicles on dry vegetation, and using equipment that can cause
sparks. Follow all fire restrictions. Find links to restrictions
at weather.gov/medford/wildfire. One less spark, one less
wildfire.
Gather your fire evacuation kit now. Collect essentials you don`t
want to lose and prioritize your checklist. Visit ready.gov/kit
for more information.
Familiarize yourself with your evacuation plan. Where will you go?
How will you get there? Who will you call to let others know your
are safe? Visit ready.gov/wildfires for more information.
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ284-285-ORZ624</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXP.KMFR.FW.W.0017.000000T0000Z-220811T0400Z/
/O.NEW.KMFR.FW.A.0015.220812T2100Z-220813T0300Z/
/O.CON.KMFR.FW.W.0018.220811T2100Z-220812T0400Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Klamath Basin and the Fremont-Winema National Forest</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ624</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>