<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a4d5086dd87607bfa55150c1ccacf8850bebfe9d.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-03T16:10:00-06:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-03T16:10:00-06:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-03T16:10:00-06:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-04T09:00:00-06:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Grand Junction CO</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued August 3 at 4:10PM MDT by NWS Grand Junction CO</headline>
        <description>The Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment has
issued the following...

WHAT...Air Quality Health Advisory for Wildfire Smoke.

WHERE...Central and eastern Rio Blanco, eastern Garfield, and
western Eagle Counties. Locations include, but are not limited to
Meeker, Carbondale, El Jebel, and along Highway 82 south of
Glenwood Springs.

WHEN...400 PM Sunday August 03 to 900 AM Monday August 04

IMPACTS...Smoke from the Grease fire and the Elk fire in central
and southeastern Rio Blanco County, and the Coulter Creek fire in
southeastern Garfield County will produce areas of moderate to
heavy smoke Sunday evening and Monday morning. The greatest
impacts are expected in areas in the immediate vicinity of these
fires including mainly rural areas of Rio Blanco County south and
southeast of Meeker; and in southeastern portions of Garfield
County in the roaring Fork Valley along Highway 82 near Carbondale
and El Jebel; south of Glenwood Springs. Additional smoke impacts
may be experienced across the advisory area due to transport of
smoke on Sunday and Monday.

HEALTH INFORMATION...Public Health Recommendations: If smoke is
thick or becomes thick in your neighborhood you may want to remain
indoors. This is especially true for those with heart disease,
respiratory illnesses, the very young, and older adults. Consider
limiting outdoor activity when moderate to heavy smoke is present.
Consider relocating temporarily if smoke is present indoors and is
making you ill. If visibility is less than 5 miles in smoke in
your neighborhood, smoke has reached levels that are unhealthy.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAGJT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS75 KGJT 032210</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY HEALTH ADVISORY FOR WILDFIRE SMOKE FROM 400 PM SUNDAY UNTIL 900 AM MONDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Garfield, CO; Rio Blanco, CO; Eagle, CO</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>008045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>008103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>008037</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>COC045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>COC103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>COC037</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>