<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 21 May 2023 11:27:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MP12664906487C.TyphoonWatch.126649079D80MP.GUMHLSPQ1.e8c565f4630b5e0a2567affda72608e0</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-05-21T21:27:00+10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Rota; Saipan; Tinian (Marianas) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Typhoon Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-05-21T21:27:00+10:00</effective>
<expires>2023-05-22T06:00:00+10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Guam (Guam)</senderName>
<headline>Typhoon Watch issued May 21 at 9:27PM ChST until further notice by NWS Guam</headline>
<description>...TROPICAL STORM MAWAR MOVING NORTH-NORTHWEST...
.NEW INFORMATION...
None.
.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and recommended
actions for people in Guam and the Northern Marianas.
.Watches/Warnings...
A Tropical Storm Warning remains in effect for the following
locations, Ulul and Polowat in western Chuuk State and Satawal in
eastern Yap State.
A Typhoon Watch continues for the following locations, Guam,
Rota, Tinian, and Saipan in the Mariana Islands.
.STORM INFORMATION...
At 7 PM ChST...the center of Tropical Storm Mawar (02W) was
located near Latitude 7.9N...Longitude 148.5E. This was about 460
miles south-southeast of Guam. Storm motion was north-northwest at
10 mph. Storm intensity was 70 mph.
.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
When making decisions, do not focus on the exact forecast track. TS
Mawar(02W) continues to strengthen over western Chuuk State. It
is too early to provide exact wind and surge forecast values for
specific locations in the Marianas. A general concern should be
for the possibility of at least extensive damage somewhere within
Mariana Islands.
.PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
For those under a watch...now is the time to begin preparing your
home or business according to your typhoon disaster plan. Listen
for possible warnings and be ready to evacuate if necessary. Heed
the advice of local officials and comply with any orders that are
issued.
For interests at ports...docks...and marinas...it is recommended
that you perform the prescribed preparations according to your
emergency operations plan for tropical cyclones. If you live on a
boat...begin to safely secure your craft and make plans to leave
it for adequate land based shelter. Listen for possible warnings.
Regarding the coastal waters under a watch...small craft should
return to port or seek safe harbor.
Closely monitor NOAA weather radio or other local news outlets
for official storm information. Listen for possible changes to
the forecast.
For additional precautionary and preparedness information...
Please refer to the detailed recommendations relative to your
location as further described by your local National Weather
Service office and your local emergency management.
&amp;&amp;
.NEXT UPDATE...
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tiyan around 3 AM ChST...or sooner if conditions
warrant.
...TYPHOON WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...New Information...
Tropical Storm Mawar (02W) continues to strengthen.
...PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
Stay calm and keep informed. Comply with any evacuation orders
that are issued for your area. If your home is vulnerable to high
winds, or you live in a surge zone or any location prone to
flooding, evacuate to a designated shelter or ride out the storm
in the sturdy home of family or friends.
As of 8 PM Sunday, the governor of Guam has placed Guam under COR
2. The CNMI remains in COR 3.
Items to bring to a shelter include a first aid kit, medicines and
prescriptions, baby food and diapers, games and books, toiletries, a
battery powered radio, a cell phone, flashlights with extra
batteries, a blanket or sleeping bag for each person, personal
identification, copies of key papers such as insurance policies,
available cash and credit cards. Remember, pets are not allowed in
most public shelters, so check ahead with your intended shelter.
Regarding your home or business, cover all windows and doors with
shutters or plywood. Move patio furniture and other loose objects
indoors. Brace all exterior doors, including garage doors. Do this as
early as possible.
If you need to make a trip to the hardware store, the grocery
store, or the gas station, do so as early as possible.
&amp;&amp;
...Probability of tropical storm/typhoon conditions...
The onset of tropical storm conditions could start as early as
Tuesday morning, but are more likely Tuesday evening. Typhoon
conditions are possible by Wednesday morning.
...Winds...
As Tropical Storm Mawar moves closer, the threat for sustained
high winds will increase. Tropical storm force winds are
currently forecast to begin affecting the area Tuesday evening. A
general concern should be for the possibility of widespread damage
somewhere within the Marianas. The latest forecast is for typhoon
force winds from Wednesday morning into Wednesday evening.
...Storm surge and storm tide...
Dangerous surf conditions are possible Monday night through at least
Thursday night. Additional details on surf and possible inundation
will be added later as the exact track and intensity information are
refined.
...Inland flooding...
A Flood Flash Watch is in effect for the entire area. See latest
forecast for latest information. Listen for possible flood
warnings for your location...and be ready to act if flooding
rains occur.
Heavy rainfall is likely through most of the week. Rainfall amounts
of 9 to 15 inches are possible with locally heavier amounts. Monitor
conditions for possible flood watches, advisories or warnings.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUZ001-MPZ001>003</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.PGUM.TY.A.4002.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Rota; Saipan; Tinian</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>069100</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>069110</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>069120</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MPZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MPZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MPZ003</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>