<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.e7486b9676df7a1e291fe2baad8a29b3d851415b.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-16T15:03:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-16T15:02:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-16T15:02:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-16T20:30:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Memphis TN</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued September 16 at 3:02PM CDT by NWS Memphis TN</headline>
        <description>AQAMEG

The Shelby County Health Department has issued a Code Orange Ozone
Forecast effective for Shelby County Tennessee, Crittenden County
Arkansas, and DeSoto County Mississippi, including the city of
Memphis for Today. This ozone forecast is due to forecasted ozone
values that will be unhealthy for sensitive groups. These values
will exceed the Environmental Protection Agency's federal safe
health standard. The Shelby County Health Department recommends that
sensitive groups which include active children and adults, and
people with respiratory disease, such as asthma, limit prolonged
outdoor exertion. Please continue to check the latest air quality
forecasts and updates until monitored values return to safe levels.
For more information go to www.airnow.gov.

In addition to the advisory, the Shelby County Health Department has
issued a Code Orange Ozone Forecast effective for Shelby County
Tennessee, Crittenden County Arkansas, and DeSoto County
Mississippi, including the city of Memphis for Wednesday. This ozone
forecast is due to forecasted ozone values that will be unhealthy for
sensitive groups. These values will exceed the Environmental
Protection Agency's federal safe health standard. The Shelby County
Health Department recommends that sensitive groups which include
active children and adults, and people with respiratory disease,
such as asthma, limit prolonged outdoor exertion. Please continue to
check the latest air quality forecasts and updates until monitored
values return to safe levels. For more information go to
www.airnow.gov.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAMEG</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS74 KMEG 162003</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>Code Orange Ozone Forecast for Today and Tomorrow</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Crittenden; DeSoto; Shelby</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005035</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>028033</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>047157</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARZ036</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MSZ001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>TNZ088</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>