<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:14:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-IN12663C24AFB8.FloodWarning.12663C9021F8IN.INDFLSIND.617ad0f735085c748c9bacc5814b8884</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-03-04T19:14:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Lawrence; Martin (Indiana) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-03-06T02:30:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2023-03-11T23:30:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Indianapolis (Central Indiana)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued March 04 at 7:14PM EST until March 11 at 11:30PM EST by NWS Indianapolis</headline>
<description>...The Flood Warning continues for portions of the following rivers
and creeks in Indiana...Illinois...
Mill Creek, Youngs Creek, White River, Flatrock River, Sugar
Creek, Driftwood River, East Fork White River, Tippecanoe River,
Mississinewa River, Wildcat Creek, Wabash River, and Eel River.
...The Flood Warning is extended for the following river and
location in Indiana...
East Fork White River at Williams.
.Minor flooding is ongoing or expected along the main stem rivers
and several tributaries across central and southern Indiana.
Moderate flooding was in progress Saturday evening on the
Mississinewa River at Ridgeville.  Crests are expected to be very
close to moderate flood stage at Lafayette, Montezuma, and Mount
Carmel on the Wabash River, Elliston, Newberry, and Petersburg on
the White River, Edinburgh on the Driftwood River, and Seymour on
the East Fork White River.
Rainfall of 1.5 to 3 inches fell over the course of Friday March 3rd,
which has brought the widespread flooding to the area.
Flooding is ongoing along the full length of the Wabash River and
most of the White River, with levels rising at a large majority of
the gage sites.  Flooding along the East Fork White river is
expected from Columbus to Williams, with river levels rising along
the large majority of the gage locations.
Flooding along smaller tributaries will end by Tuesday with flooding
continuing through the week along much of the Wabash, White, and
East Fork White rivers.
...FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM LATE SUNDAY NIGHT TO LATE
SATURDAY EVENING...
* WHAT...Minor flooding is forecast.
* WHERE...East Fork White River near Rivervale.
* WHEN...From late Sunday night to late Saturday evening.
* IMPACTS...At 25.0 feet, During the late March 2008 flood, the
Bedford Times reported the following county roads still under
water: River Road, Bartlettsville Road by the bridge and in the
bottoms, Judah-Logan Road by the bridge, the gravel part of Logan
Bottoms, Donica Church Road between Logan Bottoms and the hill,
Peerless Road by Mica Metals, Little Salt Creek Run, Stumphole
Bridge Road near SR 450, Huron-Williams Road, Lawrenceport Road,
Rivervale Road and Earl Road.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 6:30 PM EST Saturday the stage was 17.3 feet.
- Forecast...The river is expected to rise above flood stage
early Monday morning to a crest of 24.8 feet early Wednesday
morning. It will then fall below flood stage late Saturday
morning.
- Flood stage is 20.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>To escape rising water, take the shortest path to higher ground.
Please report observed flooding to local emergency services or law
enforcement and request they pass this information to the National
Weather Service when you can do so safely.
Additional information is available at www.weather.gov/ind.
This statement will be updated within the next 12 to 24 hours.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>INC093-101</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KIND.FL.W.0036.230306T0730Z-230312T0430Z/
/BEDI3.1.ER.230306T0730Z.230308T0600Z.230311T1630Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Lawrence; Martin</areaDesc>
<polygon>38.78,-86.13 38.72,-86.31 38.77,-86.46 38.82,-86.43 38.78,-86.31 38.8,-86.18 38.78,-86.13</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>018093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>018101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>INC093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>INC101</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>