<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.82e85b3b4f4f9f9a82cb5046a6b82f70d6b696b0.004.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-20T09:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued August 19 at 9:05PM EDT until August 20 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents
and large breaking waves in the surf zone. For the High Surf
Advisory, large breaking waves of 5 to 19 feet in the surf
zone.

* WHERE...The beaches from Duck to Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, through Wednesday
evening. For the High Surf Advisory, until midnight EDT Friday
night.

* IMPACTS...Extreme beach and coastal damage is likely along the
oceanside, resulting in a significant threat to life and
property. Large dangerous waves will likely inundate and destroy
protective dune structures. Severe flooding will likely extend
inland from the waterfront causing flooding of many homes and
businesses with some structural damage possible. Numerous roads
will likely be impassable under several feet of water and
vehicles will likely be submerged. Actions will need to be taken
to protect life and property. Very dangerous swimming and
surfing conditions expected, as well as the wave action
resulting in significant beach erosion. Minor inundation of 1 to
2 feet above ground level expected for soundside areas adjacent
to the Pamlico Sound from Buxton south.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...A Storm Surge Warning remains in effect
for the Outer Banks. This is expected to be a prolonged duration
event, with the potential for portions of NC-12 and secondary
roads along the Outer Banks, in particular on Hatteras and
Ocracoke Islands, to be impassable and/or inaccessible for at
least several days due to significant wave run up.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions, life-threatening rip currents, and
dangerous shore break.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 200105</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT THROUGH WEDNESDAY EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT FRIDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.BH.S.0053.250820T0105Z-250821T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-20T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Outer Banks; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>