<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.3e24bde08cbb11ea33ecfe3a5c42963cbcdf9c4e.005.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-19T22:43:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.97f22e072b215dfb7e28ba530b7593543b014262.003.1,2025-08-19T16:58:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-19T22:43:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T22:43:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-20T06:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wakefield VA</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued August 19 at 10:43PM EDT by NWS Wakefield VA</headline>
        <description>* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Corolla

* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Below tropical storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 25-35 mph with gusts to 50 mph

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- The wind threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Efforts to protect property should now be
underway. Prepare for limited wind damage.
- ACT: Act now to complete preparations before the wind
becomes hazardous.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, especially if soils are saturated. Some roadway
signs will sustain damage.
- A few roads will be impassable from debris. Hazardous
driving conditions on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.

* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Localized storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 1-3 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: Wednesday afternoon until Friday evening

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 1 foot above ground
- The storm surge threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for storm surge flooding greater than 1 foot
above ground.
- PREPARE: Complete preparations for storm surge flooding,
especially in low-lying vulnerable areas, before conditions
become unsafe.
- ACT: Leave immediately if evacuation orders are given for
your area.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Widespread storm surge flooding of vulnerable areas will
result in an elevated threat of property damage to homes
and businesses near the waterfront and shoreline.
- Sections of low-lying vulnerable roads, parking lots and
property will likely become flooded. Driving conditions
could become dangerous in places where flooding covers the
road.
- Moderate to severe beach erosion is likely, including heavy
surf possibly breaching dunes, especially in vulnerable
locations. Strong and dangerous rip currents are likely.
- Minor to moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and
piers is likely. A few small craft broken away from
moorings.

* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: No additional significant rainfall
forecast

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
localized flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
localized flooding from heavy rain.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Localized flooding from heavy rainfall may prompt a few
evacuations
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swift
currents. Small streams, creeks, and ditches may become
swollen and overflow.
- Flood waters may enter a few structures, especially in
usually vulnerable spots. Rapid ponding of water is
possible at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some storm drains and retention ponds could become
near-full and begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge
closures can be expected.

* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is unfavorable for tornadoes

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Tornadoes not expected
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Tornadoes are not expected. Showers and thunderstorms
with gusty winds may still occur.
- PREPARE: Little to no preparations needed to protect
against tornadoes at this time. Keep informed of the latest
tornado situation.
- ACT: Listen for changes in the forecast.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Little to None
- Little to no potential impacts from tornadoes.

* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes
- readync.org
- weather.gov/akq
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>TCVAKQ</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS81 KAKQ 200243</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KAKQ.TR.A.1005.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ce97080635e65ff757124693e91ac81da07b314c.003.1,2025-08-19T11:06:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Eastern Currituck</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.345,-75.815 36.232,-75.773 36.228,-75.789 36.229,-75.795 36.232,-75.821 36.295,-75.856 36.335,-75.852 36.345,-75.823 36.356,-75.833 36.368,-75.829 36.371,-75.837 36.375,-75.834 36.373,-75.850 36.400,-75.852 36.424,-75.848 36.425,-75.856 36.430,-75.862 36.435,-75.859 36.439,-75.891 36.461,-75.900 36.477,-75.904 36.511,-75.881 36.511,-75.902 36.522,-75.905 36.542,-75.904 36.545,-75.907 36.551,-75.904 36.551,-75.867 36.345,-75.815</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037053</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ102</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>