<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.fc03d18d7d4bec34ac441e27c9ac95deea37ab55.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-19T11:09:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-19T11:09:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T11:09:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-19T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued August 19 at 11:09AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>HLSMHX

This product covers Eastern North Carolina

**STORM SURGE AND TROPICAL STORM WARNINGS ISSUED FOR THE NORTH
CAROLINA OUTER BANKS**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Storm Surge Watch has been upgraded to a Storm Surge
Warning and the Tropical Storm Watch has been upgraded to a
Tropical Storm Warning for East Carteret, Hatteras Island,
Northern Outer Banks, and Ocracoke Island

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for East Carteret, Hatteras Island, Northern Outer Banks, and
Ocracoke Island

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 690 miles south-southeast of Buxton NC or about 680 miles
south-southeast of Morehead City NC
- 25.6N 72.4W
- Storm Intensity 105 mph
- Movement Northwest or 325 degrees at 9 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Hurricane Erin is expected to remain a major hurricane as it moves
northward through mid week. While the center of Erin is expected to
remain a couple hundred miles off the North Carolina coast, it will
bring significant coastal impacts to eastern North Carolina due to
its large size.

Moderate to significant storm surge inundation of 2 to 4 feet above
ground level is expected along the oceanside, resulting in a
significant threat to life and property. The worst impacts will
likely be felt along the Outer Banks, from Duck to Cape Lookout,
with more moderate impacts south of Cape Lookout. This is expected
to be a prolonged duration event beginning later today, peaking
Wednesday into Thursday, then gradually improving late week, with
water levels peaking during the high tides. Portions of NC-12 and
secondary roads along the Outer Banks, in particular on Hatteras and
Ocracoke Islands, will likely be impassable or inaccessible through
much of this week due to significant ocean overwash. Minor storm
surge inundation, 1 to 3 ft, will also be possible for soundside
areas adjacent to the southern Pamlico Sound on Thursday and
possibly into Friday.

Erin is expected to increase in size over the next few days and
tropical storm force winds will be felt Wednesday night into
Thursday along the Outer Banks.

Stronger and more frequent rip currents are expected along area
beaches through the week. Extensive beach erosion is also likely due
to strong long period wave energy with 10 to 20 foot waves in the
surf zone.

Very dangerous marine conditions will continue for the coastal
waters, sounds and rivers, with gusty winds and dangerous seas.
This will create treacherous conditions for mariners.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across the Outer Banks from Duck southward to Hatteras,
Ocracoke, and Core Banks. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.

Also, protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across the Crystal Coast.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
Outer Banks from Duck southward to Hatteras, Ocracoke, Core Banks, and
portions of Down East Carteret. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across Coastal Eastern North Carolina. Potential
impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding may prompt a few evacuations.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swifter currents.
Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may become swollen
and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter a few structures, especially in usually
vulnerable spots. A few places where rapid ponding of water
occurs at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Several storm drains and retention ponds become
near-full and begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge
closures.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Life threatening rip currents and marine conditions will persist
through the week.

* TORNADOES:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time
across Eastern North Carolina.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.

If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible.
Allow extra time to reach your destination. Many roads and bridges
will be closed once strong winds arrive. Check the latest weather
forecast before departing and drive with caution.

If heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or have
pets. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.

Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.

Keep cell phones well charged. Cell phone chargers for automobiles
can be helpful, but be aware of your risk for deadly carbon monoxide
poisoning if your car is left idling in a garage or other poorly
ventilated area.

If you are a visitor, be sure to know the name of the city or town in
which you are staying and the name of the county or parish in which
it resides. Listen for these locations in local news updates. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.

Storm surge is the leading killer associated with tropical storms and
hurricanes! Make sure you are in a safe area away from the surge
zone. Even if you are not in a surge-prone area, you could find
yourself cutoff by flood waters during and after the storm. Heed
evacuation orders issued by the local authorities.

Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.


* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Newport/Morehead City NC around 5 PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMHX 191509</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>STORM SURGE AND TROPICAL STORM WARNINGS ISSUED FOR THE NORTH
CAROLINA OUTER BANKS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Carteret; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>