<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.82e85b3b4f4f9f9a82cb5046a6b82f70d6b696b0.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T21:05:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-20T09:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued August 19 at 9:05PM EDT until August 20 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents
and large breaking waves in the surf zone. For the High Surf
Advisory, large breaking waves of 10 to 20 feet expected in the
surf zone north of Cape Lookout, and 6 to 9 feet south of Cape
Lookout for Shackleford Island. For the Coastal Flood Warning, 2
to 4 feet of inundation above ground level expected north of
Cape Lookout, and 2 to 3 feet above ground level south of Cape
Lookout. Minor inundation of 1 to 3 feet above ground level
expected for soundside areas adjacent to the southern Pamlico
Sound and Core Sound.

* WHERE...East Carteret County.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, through Wednesday
evening. For the Coastal Flood Warning, until 8 PM EDT
Thursday. For the High Surf Advisory, until midnight EDT
Friday night.

* IMPACTS...Moderate to major beach damage is likely along the
oceanside north of Cape Lookout, resulting in a significant
threat to life and property. Large dangerous waves will likely
inundate and destroy protective dune structures. Minor soundside
flooding expected for areas adjacent to the southern Pamlico
Sound. Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and significant
beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers
away from shore into deeper water. Dangerous shore break can
throw a swimmer or surfer head first into the bottom causing
neck and back injuries.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...This is expected to be a prolonged
duration event for the oceanside, impacting several high tide
cycles.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions, life-threatening rip currents, and
dangerous shore break.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 200105</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT THROUGH WEDNESDAY EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THURSDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT FRIDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.BH.S.0053.250820T0105Z-250821T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-20T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Carteret</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>