<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7cd460581382d050104be4dfc502e18925729290.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-19T05:20:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-19T05:20:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-19T05:20:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-19T17:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued August 19 at 5:20AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>HLSMHX

This product covers Eastern North Carolina

...HURRICANE ERIN FORECAST TO PASS OFFSHORE, BUT WITH SIGNIFICANT COASTAL
IMPACTS EXPECTED...

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Watch and Tropical Storm Watch are in effect for
East Carteret, Hatteras Island, Northern Outer Banks, and
Ocracoke Island

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 750 miles south-southeast of Buxton NC or about 740 miles
south-southeast of Morehead City NC
- 24.8N 72.0W
- Storm Intensity 115 mph
- Movement Northwest or 325 degrees at 7 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Hurricane Erin is expected to remain a major hurricane as it moves
northward through mid week. While the center of Erin is expected to
remain a couple hundred miles off the North Carolina coast, it will
bring significant coastal impacts to eastern North Carolina due to its
large size.

Moderate to significant storm surge inundation of 2 to 4 feet above
ground level is expected along the oceanside, resulting in a
significant threat to life and property. The worst impacts will likely
be felt along the Outer Banks, from Duck to Cape Lookout, with more
moderate impacts south of Cape Lookout. This is expected to be a
prolonged duration event beginning Tuesday, peaking Wednesday into
Thursday then gradually improving late week, with water levels peaking
during the high tides. Portions of NC-12 and secondary roads along the
Outer Banks, in particular on Hatteras and Ocracoke Islands, will
likely be impassable or inaccessible through much of this week due to
significant ocean overwash. Minor storm surge inundation, 1 to 2 ft,
will also be possible for soundside areas adjacent to the southern
Pamlico Sound on Thursday and possibly into Friday.

Erin is expected to increase in size over the next few days and
tropical storm force winds will be felt Wednesday night into Thursday
along the Outer Banks.

Stronger and more frequent rip currents are expected along area
beaches through the week. Extensive beach erosion is also likely due
to strong long period wave energy with 10 to 20 foot waves in the
surf zone.

Very dangerous marine conditions will continue for the coastal waters,
sounds and rivers, with gusty winds and dangerous seas. This will
create treacherous conditions for mariners.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* SURGE:
Prepare for life-threatening surge having possible significant impacts
across the Outer Banks from Duck southward to Hatteras, Ocracoke, and
Core Banks. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.

Also, prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across the Crystal Coast.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across the
Outer Banks from Duck southward to Hatteras, Ocracoke, Core Banks, and
portions of Down East Carteret. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across Coastal Eastern North Carolina. Potential
impacts include:
- Ponding of water on roadways may cause instances of localized
flooding.
- 1 to 2 inches of rain is possible Wednesday into Thursday, with
locally higher amounts to 4 inches if heavier rain bands develop.

Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials. Portions of Dare and Hyde
counties are under mandatory evacuation orders.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and emergency supplies
kit and take necessary actions to protect your family and secure your
home or business.

When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.

If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, plan to move to safe shelter.

If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low-lying or poor
drainage area, in a valley, or near an already swollen river, plan to
move to safe shelter on higher ground.

Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.

When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.

Check on those who may not be fully aware of the situation or who are
unable to make personal preparations.

If you are a visitor, know the name of the county or parish in which
you are located and where it is relative to current watches and
warnings. If staying at a hotel, ask the management staff about their
onsite disaster plan. Listen for evacuation orders, especially
pertaining to area visitors.

Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Newport/Morehead City NC around 11 AM, or sooner if
conditions warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMHX 190920</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Carteret; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>