<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.709a37bb5e561886e3402d3a225794147a75a0a5.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-18T14:25:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-18T14:25:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-18T14:25:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-18T17:30:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Flagstaff AZ</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued November 18 at 2:25PM MST until November 18 at 5:30PM MST by NWS Flagstaff AZ</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of west central Arizona, including the following
county, Yavapai.

* Until 530 PM MST.

* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in creeks and normally dry washes is
imminent or occurring.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 224 PM MST, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges
indicated heavy rain due to thunderstorms. Minor flooding is
ongoing or expected to begin shortly in the advisory area.
Between 0.5 and 1 inch of rain has fallen.
- This includes the following creeks, washes and rivers...
French Creek, Sycamore Creek, Jim Creek, Black Butte Wash,
Cedar Creek, Big Bug Creek, Bitter Creek, Cottonwood Creek,
Tank Creek, North Fork Rock Creek, Minnehaha Creek, Willow
Creek, Humbug Creek, Agua Fria River, Mineral Creek, Indian
Creek, Hackberry Creek, Slate Creek, Antelope Creek, Boulder
Creek, Towers Creek, Buckhorn Creek, Larry Creek, Badger
Spring Wash, Pine Creek, Bear Creek, Banty Creek, Tuscumbia
Creek, Ash Creek, Bishop Creek, Castle Creek, Wolf Creek,
Government Spring Wash, Tussock Spring Creek, Turkey Creek,
Poland Creek, Sand Creek, Crazy Basin Creek, Tiger Creek,
Little Ash Creek, Black Canyon Creek, Silver Creek, Black
Canyon, Squaw Creek and Rock Creek.
Additional rainfall amounts of 0.25 to 1 inch are expected
over the area. This additional rain will result in minor
flooding.
- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
Horse Thief Basin, Sunset Point Rest Area, Black Canyon City,
Castle Hot Springs, Coles Bay, Agua Fria National Monument,
Humbug Bay, Cordes Lakes, Goose Bay, Spring Valley, Castle
Creek Boat Ramp, Cottonwood Day Use Area, Lake Pleasant,
Castle Creek Wilderness, Humbug, Bumble Bee, Crown King, Rock
Springs, Cleator and Casa Rosa.
- This includes the following highways...
State Route 69 between mile markers 263 and 264.
Interstate 17 between mile markers 242 and 263.

This includes the following recreation areas and
campgrounds...
Turney Gulch Group Campground, Hazlett Hollow Campground and
Black Canyon Campground.
- Additional information is available at weather.gov/flagstaff.
</description>
        <instruction>Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Low water crossings will become dangerous in heavy rain. Do not
attempt to cross flooded roads. Find an alternate route.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSFGZ</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS85 KFGZ 182125</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 530 PM MST THIS AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KFGZ.FA.Y.0030.251118T2125Z-251119T0030Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-18T17:30:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Yavapai, AZ</areaDesc>
            <polygon>34.34,-112.35 34.35,-112.04 34.04,-112.08 34.05,-112.16 34.04,-112.15 34.04,-112.16 34.01,-112.16 34.01,-112.18 33.97,-112.2 33.96,-112.24 33.92,-112.24 33.89,-112.28 33.88,-112.28 33.93,-112.47 34.34,-112.35</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004025</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZC025</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>