<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 10 Jun 2022 10:15:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MN1263FA4A15BC.FloodWarning.1263FA963410MN.DLHFLWDLH.950a7fbc45c202d224eca5b3f23f59bf</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-06-10T17:15:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Koochiching (Minnesota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-06-12T20:49:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-06-15T16:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Duluth (Northeast Minnesota and Northern Wisconsin)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued June 10 at 5:15PM CDT until June 15 at 4:00PM CDT by NWS Duluth</headline>
<description>...FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by rain and snowmelt continues. Namakan and
Rainy Lake have both surpassed levels set during the 2014 peak
levels with Rainy Lake now above the 1950 record peak as well.
* WHERE...Portions of north central Minnesota and northeast
Minnesota, including the following counties, in north central
Minnesota, Koochiching. In northeast Minnesota, St. Louis.
* WHEN...Until further notice.
* IMPACTS...Flooding of lakes, rivers, and other low-lying and
flood-prone locations is occurring. Several structures are flooded
and sand bagging operations are continuing. Low-water crossings
are inundated with water and may not be passable. Expect many
areas of slow moving or standing water.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 506 PM CDT, Friday, emergency management continued to
reported flooding in the warned area.
- The dry weather over the past week has meant declining flows
in the smaller streams and reduced inflows to the lakes. The
4-day forecast includes chances of showers and thunderstorm
with one-tenth up to three-tenths of an inch of rain expected
across the basin. Even with this rainfall, the expectation is
that the recent decreases of inflow will continue. There is
some rain in the forecast beyond four days, but amounts
remain uncertain. Flows across most of the watershed are
expected to remain very high for the week ahead.
Namakan and Kabetogama Lakes were at 1122.2 feet as of June
10, which is 20 inches above the peak level set in 2014 and
7.5 inches below the 1916 peak. The level of Namakan Lake is
expected to fall by 9 to 12 inches between June 10 and June
17.
Rainy Lake was at 1113.2 feet as of June 10 which is 22
inches above the 2014 flooding peak and 3 inches above the
previous record peak of 1950. The level of Rainy Lake is
expected to remain stable with slight fluctuations up or down
depending on rainfall by six-tenths of an inch between June
10 and June 17. Rainy Lake should reach its peak by around
June 17 unless more rainfall occurs than currently expected.
- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
International Falls, Kabetogama, Crane Lake, Kabetogama Lake,
Voyageurs National Park, Rainy Lake - East, Rainy Lake -
West, northwestern Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness,
Ranier, Ray, Island View, Ericksburg, Johnson Lake, and Sand
Point Lake.
- For more information about flood safety visit,
https://weather.gov/safety/flood .
For more information about the Rainy Lake Basin flooding
visit, https://weather.gov/dlh/RainyRiverBasin .</description>
<instruction>Turn around, don`t drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.
Once levels have peaked, it will take a matter of weeks to a month
for levels to decline to near normal summer levels. Additional
rainfall will prolong the time it takes for levels to recede.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNC071-137</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.KDLH.FA.W.0012.000000T0000Z-220616T2200Z/
/00000.0.RS.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Koochiching</areaDesc>
<polygon>48.36,-93.44 48.59,-93.47 48.63,-93.32 48.63,-92.95 48.61,-92.95 48.54,-92.73 48.54,-92.63 48.49,-92.7 48.47,-92.71 48.46,-92.71 48.44,-92.66 48.42,-92.47 48.35,-92.47 48.22,-92.37 48.36,-93.44</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNC071</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>