<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.adbc927a5cf0e1e587bfa8d6bf80f712f051f4b7.009.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-25T02:41:00-06:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Winter Storm Warning</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>WSW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-25T02:41:00-06:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-25T12:00:00-06:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-25T14:45:00-06:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Twin Cities/Chanhassen MN</senderName>
        <headline>Winter Storm Warning issued November 25 at 2:41AM CST until November 26 at 6:00AM CST by NWS Twin Cities/Chanhassen MN</headline>
        <description>...RAIN WILL TURN TO HEAVY SNOW FROM WEST TO EAST THIS AFTERNOON AND
TONIGHT...
...SNOW AMOUNTS HAVE INCREASED AND EXPANDED FARTHER SOUTH...
...SNOWFALL RATES EXCEEDING AN INCH PER HOUR AND STRONG NORTHWEST
WINDS GUSTING TO 45 MPH MAY LEAD TO BLIZZARD CONDITIONS AT TIMES...

.A potent storm system will move across the area today and tonight.
Rain will transition snow from west to east as cold air arrives.
Periods of heavy snow are expected with rates of around an inch per
hour at times. The heaviest totals will be found across central
Minnesota and northwest Wisconsin where around 6 inches are expected.
Farther south across southern Minnesota and parts of west central
Wisconsin, 1 to 3 inches are expected.

Winds will increase later today and tonight with gusts as high as 45
mph. Combined with the falling snow, widespread blowing snow and
blizzard conditions are possible at times with visibilities 1/4 mile
or less.

The Winter Storm Warning has been expanded south into most of
southern Minnesota despite lower snow totals to account for the
strongest winds and near blizzard conditions. A Winter Weather
Advisory is in effect for far southern Minnesota and parts of west
central Wisconsin.

* WHAT...Heavy snow and blowing snow expected. Total snow
accumulations between 4 and 6 inches. Winds gusting as high as 45
mph.

* WHERE...Pope and Stevens Counties.

* WHEN...From noon today to 6 AM CST Wednesday.

* IMPACTS...Visibilities may drop below 1/4 mile due to falling and
blowing snow. Travel could be very difficult. Widespread blowing
snow could significantly reduce visibility. The hazardous
conditions will impact the Tuesday evening commute. Gusty winds
could bring down tree branches.
</description>
        <instruction>Persons should delay all travel if possible. If travel is absolutely
necessary, drive with extreme caution and be prepared for sudden
changes in visibility. Leave plenty of room between you and the
motorist ahead of you, and allow extra time to reach your
destination. Avoid sudden braking or acceleration, and be especially
cautious on hills or when making turns. Make sure your car is
winterized and in good working order.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWMPX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS43 KMPX 250841</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>WINTER STORM WARNING IN EFFECT FROM NOON TODAY TO 6 AM CST WEDNESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXA.KMPX.WS.W.0006.251125T1800Z-251126T1200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-26T06:00:00-06:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Stevens; Pope</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027149</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027121</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ047</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ048</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>