<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a339a320a24cd3ee97f8801815b3f27c61448c5a.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-01T15:53:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-01T15:47:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-06-01T15:47:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-02T20:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Columbia SC</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued June 1 at 3:47PM EDT by NWS Columbia SC</headline>
        <description>The South Carolina Department of Environmental Services (SCDES)
has issued a Code Orange Ozone Action Day for the Catawba and
Upstate regions of South Carolina in effect from 10 AM to 8 PM
EDT Monday.

A combination of primed ozone formation conditions, owing to a
lack of both morning cloud cover and excess moisture being
introduced into the environment with the addition of a lack of
pollutant dispersion characteristics from low wind speeds and
a very stable atmosphere are anticipated to bring action level
ozone concentrations to the defined forecast regions. This has
been further compounded by higher than projected ozone readings
from over the weekend and an influence from interactions with
the Canadian wildfire smoke that has poured across the Plains
and Southeast.



All other forecast regions are projected to peak in code Yellow
for Monday's ozone concentrations.

An ozone action day means that atmospheric conditions will
likely produce unhealthy concentrations of ground level ozone
air pollution. A Code Orange forecast indicates that ground
level ozone concentrations are expected to be unhealthy for
sensitive groups, which includes people with lung disease,
older adults and children. Sensitive groups should reduce
prolonged or heavy outdoor exertion, take more breaks, and
do less intense activities, especially during afternoon and
early evening hours. You can help prevent ozone pollution by
walking or riding your bicycle, taking your lunch to work,
reducing idling, conserving energy, and keeping your vehicle
properly tuned. For additional information, please visit the
South Carolina Department of Environmental Services website
at http://www.des.sc.gov/ozone or the Environmental Protection
Agency AirNow website at https://www.airnow.gov.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQACAE</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS72 KCAE 011953</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>Air Quality Alert in effect from 10 AM to 8 PM EDT Monday</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Lancaster; Southern Lancaster</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045057</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ115</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ116</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>