<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.487dbe59a488dc0f8868c3967856774c9893f649.002.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-29T04:06:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-29T04:06:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-30T11:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-29T16:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued September 29 at 4:06AM EDT until October 3 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents.
For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 6 to 8 feet,
building to 10 to 12 feet expected in the surf zone. For the
Coastal Flood Advisory, minor inundation 1 to 2 feet of
inundation above ground level expected in low-lying areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways.

* WHERE...Northern Outer Banks.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 8 AM EDT this
morning through this evening. For the High Surf Advisory, from
5 PM this afternoon to 8 AM EDT Saturday. For the Coastal
Flood Advisory, from 11 AM Tuesday to 8 PM EDT Friday.

* IMPACTS...Minor inundation, 1 to 2 feet above ground level, is
possible in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways
resulting in a low threat of property damage. Some roads and low
lying property including parking lots, parks, lawns, and homes
adjacent to the waterfront will experience shallow flooding.
Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and beach erosion.
Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore
into deeper water.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 7:00 PM Monday.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 290806</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 8 AM EDT THIS MORNING THROUGH THIS EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 5 PM THIS AFTERNOON TO 8 AM EDT SATURDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 11 AM TUESDAY TO 8 PM EDT FRIDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.CF.Y.0011.250930T1500Z-251004T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Outer Banks</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>