<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 12 Mar 2023 08:20:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA12663C928F10.FloodWatch.12663CCC8300CA.REVFFAREV.133456eab82f0e9b84c4bd4491ca4793</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-03-12T13:20:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Greater Lake Tahoe Area (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-03-13T05:26:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2023-03-15T17:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Reno (Western Nevada)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Watch issued March 12 at 1:20PM PDT until March 15 at 5:00PM PDT by NWS Reno</headline>
<description>.Heavy rain with elevated snow levels are expected to renew the risk
of flooding Tuesday morning through Wednesday, mostly in areas below
approximately 7000 feet. Areas of primary concern are small creeks
and streams, and areas with poor or obstructed drainage, including
areas impacted by flooding recently. Mainstem river flooding is not
currently forecast, but minor to moderate river flooding can not be
ruled out especially in lower elevation basins, and in areas that
experienced recent flooding. Flooding is unlikely in Pershing County.
...FLOOD WATCH IN EFFECT FROM LATE MONDAY NIGHT THROUGH WEDNESDAY
EVENING...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by rain and snowmelt is possible.
* WHERE...Portions of California and Nevada, including the following
areas, in California, Greater Lake Tahoe Area, Lassen-Eastern
Plumas-Eastern Sierra Counties and Mono County. In Nevada, Greater
Lake Tahoe Area, Greater Reno-Carson City-Minden Area, Mineral and
Southern Lyon Counties and Western Nevada Basin and Range
including Pyramid Lake.
* WHEN...From late Monday night through Wednesday evening.
* IMPACTS...Excessive runoff may result in flooding of rivers,
creeks, streams and other low-lying and poor drainage areas.
Flooding may occur in mountain urban areas due to deep snow
confining flow and restricting drainage. Runoff exceeding drainage
capacity is expected to impact roads, agricultural areas, and poor
drainage areas. Very high flows will continue on the Carson River
both above and below Lahontan Reservoir. Terminal Lakes will see
additional rises.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- A warm atmospheric river will lead to rapid runoff in
elevations below approximately 7000 feet. Although this
atmospheric river appears to be slightly cooler and maybe not
quite as wet as last Friday`s storm, runoff will respond more
rapidly due to primed low elevation snowpack, current high
river and stream flows, and saturated ground conditions.
Expect renewed flooding in areas that have just experienced
flood impacts. Significant river rises are expected. Mainstem
river flooding is not currently forecast, but minor to
moderate river flooding can not be ruled out.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood</description>
<instruction>Monitor weather and river forecasts and be alert for possible flood
warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action, and take advantage of relatively quiet weather today
and Monday to prepare.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ071>073-NVZ001>004</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KREV.FA.A.0002.230314T1200Z-230316T0600Z/
/00000.0.RS.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Greater Lake Tahoe Area</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ072</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>