<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.542d71df1faf6bd9c188ea9739b78494f157fb88.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-04T22:51:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-04T22:51:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-04T22:51:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-05T08:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wilmington NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 4 at 10:51PM EDT by NWS Wilmington NC</headline>
        <description>HLSILM

This product covers southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina

**TROPICAL DEPRESSION THREE REMAINS OFFSHORE WITH LITTLE MOVEMENT**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Georgetown and
Coastal Horry counties

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 260 miles south-southwest of Wilmington NC or about 210
miles south of Myrtle Beach SC
- 30.6N 78.9W
- Storm Intensity 35 mph
- Movement Stationary

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Depression Three is expected to approach the South
Carolina coast this weekend, strengthening into a tropical storm
before landfall. The largest impact on the Carolinas should be locally
heavy rainfall with an isolated flooding potential Saturday night
through Sunday.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- Localized flooding from rainfall may occur, especially in
low-lying and poor drainage areas. Small streams, creeks, and
ditches may overflow in some locations.
- Storm drains and retention ponds may become full and
begin to overflow. Some brief road closures are possible.

* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
coastal northeastern South Carolina. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Unsecured lightweight objects may be blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted or
weak trees may snap or be knocked down.
- Hazardous driving conditions are possible, especially for high
profile vehicles on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.

Elsewhere across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina, little to no impact is anticipated.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:

When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track as there are inherent forecast uncertainties
which must be taken into account.

If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low lying or poor
drainage area, plan to move to safe shelter on higher ground.

Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any orders
that are issued.

Closely monitor NOAA Weather Radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for possible changes to the
forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Wilmington NC around 6 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSILM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KILM 050251</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL DEPRESSION THREE REMAINS OFFSHORE WITH LITTLE MOVEMENT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Coastal Horry; Inland Georgetown; Coastal Georgetown; Central Horry; Northern Horry</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ054</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ059</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>