<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 21 Apr 2022 08:56:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-WI1263EF05EE60.HydrologicOutlook.1263EF22AF50WI.DLHESFDLH.33cf920a9881b8336f533fcdbe801b1b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-04-21T15:56:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Ashland; Bayfield; Burnett; Douglas; Iron; Price; Sawyer; Washburn (Wisconsin) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-04-21T11:02:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-04-23T04:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Duluth (Northeast Minnesota and Northern Wisconsin)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued April 21 at 3:56PM CDT  by NWS Duluth</headline>
<description>...HYDROLOGIC OUTLOOK FOR SNOWMELT AND END OF WEEK RAINFALL...
A multi-day rainfall event this weekend may lead to flooding.
Our Spring 2022 weather conditions have been cooler than normal
with above normal precipitation across northeastern Minnesota and
northwestern Wisconsin. Snowmelt has occurred from south to north
in our region, leaving saturated ground where the snowpack has
completely melted. A heavy snowpack remains in the Minnesota
Arrowhead and along the International Border to International
Falls. Any rainfall over areas of saturated ground or heavy
snowpack will likely result in efficient runoff, leading to
localized flooding.
A strong weather system, expected this Friday and Saturday, will bring
a short period of above normal temperatures from the upper 40s to
lower 50s in the Arrowhead to the low 70s for areas south of U.S.
Highway 2. This will increase the snowmelt rate. Furthermore,
heavy rainfall and thunderstorms are possible with this system,
which will increase the chances for localized flooding. Widespread
minor flooding is possible due to poor drainage. Streams and
creeks will likely become bankfull and cause minor flooding as
runoff routes to our rivers. River flooding is possible during the
beginning of next week.
The Minnesota Arrowhead has an unusually deep snowpack with high moisture
content. Two feet of snow depth are common in the higher
elevations. This snowpack ranks in the top 10 snowiest winters on
record. Areas of the North Shore in the highest elevations may
absorb and store any new rainfall. However, areas along the
southern slopes of this area will exhibit strong melt in addition
to rainfall. Total rainfall amounts this weekend in the Arrowhead
are forecast to be around 0.7 to 1.2 inches. Rapid runoff is
possible, causing potential flooding impacting low-lying areas,
ditches, and culverts, in addition to strong river rises.
The Rainy Lake Basin east of Lake of the Woods will likely see localized
flooding due to poor drainage. Strong rises are likely on the
Littlefork River, Big Fork and other drainages flowing north to
the Rainy River. Total rainfall accumulations through the weekend
are forecast to range from 1 to 1.9 inches.
The Upper Mississippi Headwaters saw new snow on Wednesday but
most snowpack had melted prior to this event. Again, localized
minor flooding due to poor drainage is likely in the headwaters.
Runoff will increase reservoirs levels throughout the system due
to flood control for areas downstream. Minor river flooding is
possible along the Mississippi from Aitkin to points downstream
starting early next week. Total rainfall accumulations through the
weekend are forecast to range from 0.7 to 1.1 inches.
The Lake Superior South Shore has snowpack remaining in the Bad River
Basin and the Bayfield Peninsula, which could lead to localized
flooding enhanced by runoff and steep terrain. The Tyler Forks
River is currently forecast to crest just below minor flood
stage. However, recent forecast trends show an increase in total
precipitation, and the Tyler Forks River may reach minor flood
stage. Total rainfall accumulations through the weekend are
forecast to range from 0.5 to 0.9 inches west of U.S. Highway 63.
Areas east of U.S. Highway 63 are forecast to see 0.3 to 0.5
inches of precipitation through the weekend.
The evolution of our Spring snowmelt runoff continues and looks to get
very active starting this weekend. If you live by a flood prone
area or immediately adjacent to a river or creek, please be aware
of water levels. If you have poor drainage around your home make
sure you have an operating sump pump. One thing of note will be
sub-freezing temperatures early next week following this storm.
Near record-breaking cold low temps on Monday and Tuesday
mornings will likely slow down the rate of flooding across the
region.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ010>012-018>021-025-026-033>038-WIZ001>004-006>009</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Ashland; Bayfield; Burnett; Douglas; Iron; Price; Sawyer; Washburn</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055129</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ004</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ006</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ008</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ009</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>