<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7ed23941bb4fdac047ddf7fde728435117b5cff7.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-09T13:18:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-09T12:08:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-09T12:08:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-12T09:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Aberdeen SD</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued August 9 at 12:08PM CDT by NWS Aberdeen SD</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency has issued an Air
Quality Alert for fine particles pollution. The Air Quality Index
(AQI) is expected to reach the Red or Unhealthy category.

* WHERE...Central, east central, west central, north central,
northwest, and northeast Minnesota.

* WHEN...From 9 AM CDT Sunday to 9 AM CDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Some members of the general public may experience health
effects. Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease
(including asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, may
experience health effects.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Heavy surface smoke from many wildfires across
central Saskatchewan and Manitoba will wrap around the backside of an
area of low pressure system this weekend, as the low moves east
across south central Canada. Poor air quality will most likely impact
western Minnesota beginning Sunday morning, and then expand further
east through the evening. Heavy smoke should then disperse from west
to east across the state from Monday into Tuesday morning.
</description>
        <instruction>Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease (including
asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, should avoid
prolonged or heavy exertion. The general public should limit
prolonged or heavy exertion.

Reduce or eliminate activities that contribute to air pollution, such
as outdoor burning, and use of residential wood burning devices.
Reduce vehicle trips and vehicle idling as much as possible.

Keep windows closed overnight to prevent smoke from getting indoors.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAABR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS73 KABR 091818</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FROM 9 AM CDT SUNDAY TO 9 AM CDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Traverse; Big Stone</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027155</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ046</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>