<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 20 May 2023 06:24:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AK126648F81680.FloodAdvisory.1266491420A0AK.AFGFLSAFG.1666dc9c730ea4d83698423a44c3cf3b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-05-20T10:24:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Central Interior (Alaska) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-05-18T08:59:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-05-21T18:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Fairbanks (Northern Alaska - Fairbanks)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Advisory issued May 20 at 10:24AM AKDT  by NWS Fairbanks</headline>
<description>...FLOOD ADVISORY FOR AN ICE JAM NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL 1215 PM AKDT
MONDAY...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by an ice jam continues.
* WHERE...Yukon River between Tanana and the Nowitna River.
* WHEN...Until 1215 PM AKDT Monday.
* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in low-lying areas along the Yukon River
between Tanana and Nowitna River, and minor flooding of the lower
Nowitna River. Flooding of low lying roads in Tanana is occuring
and will continue this weekend. Water levels are expected to fall
very slowly this weekend. Some areas of ponded water will see
water remain for a number of days.  Locations that have ice
onshore will likely see that ice remain for days until it melts.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1010 AM AKDT, On Friday at 7pm, the ice jam downstream of
Kallands began to move. This means that water levels along
the Yukon from Tanana downstream to the Nowitna River, and
along the lower Nowitna River are now slowly falling.
Extensive flooding formed a large lake along and upstream of
where the ice jam was with satellite imagery showing that
flooding was occuring 20 to 30 miles up the Nowitna River,
and along the Yukon River from the Nowitna River upstream to
Kallands. Water is backed up all the way to Tanana, with
minor flooding of low lying roads occuring in Tanana. Water
will slowly drain back into the river, but water could remain
in some low lying areas for many days. Ice that is onshore
could remain for many days as well until it melts.
- Minor flooding in Tanana of low lying roads in Tanana is
expected to continue into the weekend. Water levels will fall
slowly over the next several days at Tanana, but flooding is
expected to remain in low lying areas through MOnday.
Flooding is worse along the Yukon River near the Nowitna
River and for 20 to 30 miles up the Nowitna River. Water
levels in all those areas will fall very slowly over the next
several days. Some poorly drained areas will keep water for
many days. Ice that is up on shore will remain for many days
until it melts.
- For Tanana: At 9:00am the stage was 84.96 feet.
Flood Stage is 86.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
- If you live near or along the Yukon River between the Nowitna
River and Tanana, or along the lower Nowitna River, stay take
action to protect yourself from flooding.</description>
<instruction>People along the Yukon River between Tanana and the Nowitna River
should prepare for high water. Move valuables away from the river to
higher ground.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ221</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.PAFG.FA.Y.0003.000000T0000Z-230522T2015Z/
/00000.N.IJ.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Central Interior</areaDesc>
<polygon>65.08,-154.04 65.16,-153.5 65.22,-152.83 65.2,-152 65.13,-151.93 65,-153.12 64.91,-154.27 65.08,-154.04</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002290</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ221</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>