<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.e17525814b87de90ba9e1612ba248f8d2114b5f2.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-04-05T20:22:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FLW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-04-05T20:22:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-04-05T20:22:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-04-06T14:30:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Nashville TN</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued April 5 at 8:22PM CDT until April 8 at 7:19PM CDT by NWS Nashville TN</headline>
        <description>...The National Weather Service in Nashville TN has issued a Flood
Warning for the following rivers in Tennessee...

Buffalo River Near Lobelville affecting Perry County.

For the Buffalo River...including Lobelville...Minor flooding is
forecast.

* WHAT...Minor flooding is forecast.

* WHERE...Buffalo River near Lobelville.

* WHEN...From this evening to Tuesday evening.

* IMPACTS...At 10.0 feet, Water begins to inundate low lying areas
and agricultural land along the river, and begins to cover
portions of Dailey Loop and Caruthers Trace Lane.
At 12.0 feet, Water continues to inundate low lying areas and
agricultural land along the river, and covers portions of Dailey
Loop and Caruthers Trace Lane. Water also approaches Old State Hwy
13 south of School House Rd, and begins to impact properties on
Lost Creek Rd near Gilmer Bridge Rd and portions of the Buffalo
River Country Club.
At 14.0 feet, Flooding begins along the river, impacting
agricultural land and adjacent properties including Dailey Loop,
Caruthers Trace Lane, Lost Creek Rd near Gilmer Bridge Rd, and
portions of the Buffalo River Country Club. Water reaches Old
State Hwy 13 south of School House Rd and is impassable, and
approaches Gilmer Bridge Rd  Lost Creek Rd.
At 16.0 feet, Flooding continues to impact agricultural land and
properties along the river including Dailey Loop, Caruthers Trace
Lane, Lost Creek Rd near Gilmer Bridge Rd, and portions of the
Buffalo River Country Club. Water covers Old State Hwy 13 south of
School House Rd and Gilmer Bridge Rd  Lost Creek Rd which are
impassable. Water begins to impact waterfront properties off E 8th
Ave in Leeper Bottom and approaches Cuba Landing Rd and Squeeze
Bottom Rd.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 7:30 PM CDT Saturday the stage was 8.8 feet and rising.
- Forecast...The river will rise above flood stage tomorrow
morning to 15.5 feet tomorrow evening. It will then fall
Monday morning. It will rise to 16.0 feet early Tuesday
morning. It will then fall below flood stage early Tuesday
afternoon.
- Flood stage is 14.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>

Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Additional information is available at www.weather.gov.

The next statement will be issued Sunday afternoon at 230 PM CDT.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLWOHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS44 KOHX 060122</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM THIS EVENING TO TUESDAY EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KOHX.FL.W.0029.250406T0122Z-250409T0019Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-04-08T19:19:00-05:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Perry, TN</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.0,-87.89 36.0,-87.83 35.79,-87.74 35.66,-87.78 35.66,-87.85 35.79,-87.82 36.0,-87.89</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>047135</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>TNC135</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>