<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.be3ea9bc30d2f09252eb5499029ff1528cbe8340.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-04-05T22:41:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FLW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-04-05T22:41:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-04-05T22:41:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-04-06T16:45:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Nashville TN</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued April 5 at 10:41PM CDT until April 7 at 10:46AM CDT by NWS Nashville TN</headline>
        <description>...The National Weather Service in Nashville TN has issued a Flood
Warning for the following rivers in Tennessee...

Harpeth River Near Kingston Springs affecting Cheatham County.

For the Harpeth River...including Kingston Springs...Minor flooding
is forecast.

* WHAT...Minor flooding is forecast.

* WHERE...Harpeth River near Kingston Springs.

* WHEN...From this evening to late Monday morning.

* IMPACTS...At 16.0 feet, Agricultural land and low-lying areas
along the Harpeth River begin to be inundated. Water approaches
Narrows of the Harpeth Rd near Cedar Hill Rd and may be impassable
at higher levels.
At 18.0 feet, Agricultural land and low-lying areas along the
river continue to be inundated, including Narrows of the Harpeth
Rd near Cedar Hill Rd. Water begins to impact properties on Zapata
Dr, Walkup Rd, Sawyer Farms Ln, Bluff View Dr, Riverview Dr, as
well as portions of Kingston Springs City Park and LL Burns Park.
At 20.0 feet, Flooding of the Kingston Springs City Park begins
and water approaches Pinnacle Hill Road and East Kingstons Springs
Road. Several secondary roads near the river become impassable.
At 22.0 feet, Flooding continues to impact properties and
structures on Zapata Dr, Sawyer Farms Ln, Bluff View Dr, Riverview
Dr, as well as Kingston Springs City Park and portions of  LL
Burns Park. Roads near the river are also impacted, including
Walkup Rd near Sawyer Farms Ln, Riverview Dr near Elkmoore Dr, and
Cedar Hill Rd near Griffintown Rd. Water approaches portions of
U.S. 70 near Hwy 249 and may be impassable at higher levels.
At 24.0 feet, Residences on Zapata Dr, Sawyer Farms Ln, Bluff View
Dr, and Riverview Dr are being impacted by flooding, as well as
U.S. 70 near Hwy 249, Walkup Rd near Sawyer Farms Ln, Riverview Dr
near Elkmoore Dr, and Cedar Hill Rd near Griffintown Rd. Water
approaches W Kingston Springs Rd at Big Turnbull Creek, and Cedar
Hill Rd at Pickards Rd which may be impassable at higher levels.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 10:00 PM CDT Saturday the stage was 12.1 feet and rising.
- Forecast...The river is expected to rise above flood stage
late tonight to a crest of 23.5 feet tomorrow evening. It
will then fall below flood stage early Monday morning.
- Flood stage is 20.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>

Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Additional information is available at www.weather.gov.

The next statement will be issued Sunday afternoon at 445 PM CDT.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLWOHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS44 KOHX 060341</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM THIS EVENING TO LATE MONDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KOHX.FL.W.0031.250406T0341Z-250407T1546Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-04-07T10:46:00-05:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Cheatham, TN</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.3,-87.12 36.17,-87.1 36.13,-87.0 36.04,-87.04 36.14,-87.24 36.31,-87.2 36.3,-87.12</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>047021</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>TNC021</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>