<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.af1957f3096b29526514a991e7cd6de444f3f4be.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-26T04:24:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-26T04:24:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-26T04:24:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-26T23:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Caribou ME</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued July 26 at 4:24AM EDT by NWS Caribou ME</headline>
        <description>The Maine Department of Environmental Protection's Bureau of Air
Quality has issued an Air Quality Alert for particle pollution until
11 PM EDT this evening.

Particle pollution levels are in the Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups
for the Eastern Interior, Mid-Coast, and Downeast Coastal regions. A
plume of smoke moved into Maine overnight bringing much higher
particle pollution values than previously expected. As the day
progresses, the plume of smoke is expected to keep moving and values
should drop down but air quality will continue to be a health concern
for much of the day for these regions.

The Maine Department of Environmental Protection recommends that
individuals consider limiting strenuous outdoor physical activity to
reduce the risk of adverse health effects. People who may be
especially sensitive to the effects of elevated levels of pollutants
include the very young, the elderly, those with pre-existing
respiratory problems such as asthma, those with heart disease and
anyone who is working hard outdoors. But if you experience symptoms
such as shortness of breath, coughing, throat irritation or an
uncomfortable sensation in your chest please consider limiting the
intensity and duration of your outdoor activities.

A toll free air quality hotline has been established so Maine
residents can stay informed on the air quality situations. The toll
free number is: 1-800-223-1196.

Additionally the Maine Department of Environmental Protection has
the air quality forecast available on the web at
www.maine.gov/dep/air/aqforecast.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQACAR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS71 KCAR 260824</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT UNTIL 11 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southern Penobscot; Interior Hancock; Central Washington; Coastal Hancock; Coastal Washington</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>023019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>023009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>023029</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MEZ015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MEZ016</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MEZ017</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MEZ029</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MEZ030</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>