<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:23:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL126418063FCC.HurricaneLocalStatement.126418077B08FL.MFLHLSMFL.a57584ef0b105e904e67aabbc67588e1</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-11-09T04:23:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Broward County; Coastal Collier County; Coastal Miami Dade County; Coastal Palm Beach County; Far South Miami-Dade County; Glades; Hendry; Inland Broward County; Inland Collier County; Inland Miami-Dade County; Inland Palm Beach County; Mainland Monroe; Metro Broward County; Metro Palm Beach County; Metropolitan Miami Dade (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-11-09T04:14:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-11-09T12:30:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Miami (Southern Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued November 09 at 4:23AM EST  by NWS Miami</headline>
<description>This product covers South Florida
**NICOLE CONTINUES TO TRACK TOWARDS THE EAST COAST OF FLORIDA, AND IS
EXPECTED TO MAKE LANDFALL TONIGHT**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Hurricane Warning are in effect for
Coastal Palm Beach
- A Tropical Storm Warning, Storm Surge Watch, and Hurricane
Watch are in effect for Coastal Broward
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Hurricane Watch are in effect for
Inland Broward, Inland Palm Beach, Metro Broward, and Metro
Palm Beach
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Glades and Hendry
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Miami-Dade and
Metro Miami-Dade
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 280 miles east-northeast of Miami FL or about 380 miles
east of Naples FL
- 26.6N 75.7W
- Storm Intensity 70 mph
- Movement West-southwest or 250 degrees at 13 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Nicole is currently moving west to southwest near
the northwest Bahamas in the southwest Atlantic and is forecast to
gradually turn toward the west and then northwest towards the east
coast of Florida late today into early Thursday as a hurricane.
While the finer details of the track and intensity could fluctuate a
bit, the confidence in the potential impacts of this system are
increasing. Keeping in mind the magnitude of impacts may vary a bit
with any changes to Nicole`s forecast, however the main hazards of concern
are:
* Coastal Flooding/Surge - Higher than usual tides due to the recent
full moon and antecedent moderate northeasterly flow will become
further enhanced as Nicole moves towards the east coast of Florida.
Tidal gauges are forecast to climb into moderate to major flood stage
during periods of high tide through Thursday with the peak expected
today. Peak inundation values of concern along the immediate coast are
forecast to range from 3 to 5 feet across northern Palm Beach, 2 to
4 feet south to Hallandale Beach, and 1 to 3 feet across Miami-Dade.
Large breaking/life threatening waves are expected along the east
coast with the worst conditions expected along Palm Beach.
* Rainfall - The majority of the rainfall associated with the system
is forecast to fall today through Thursday morning. Waves of moderate
to heavy rain could cause localized flooding. The greatest risk for
flash flooding will be near the coast should bands of heavy rain fall
when tides are at their peak. Fairly widespread rain amounts of 2-4&quot;
with localized amounts in excess of 6 inches are expected over the
area. The highest amounts are anticipated over Palm Beach county and
the Lake region.
* Wind - Based on the current forecast for Nicole, the reasonable
worst case scenario is for tropical storm force winds particularly
across Palm Beach region and Broward counties. Tropical storm force
winds are expected to arrive into the area this afternoon although
brief periods of strong winds will also be possible in squalls this morning.
Along the immediate coast, hurricane force winds are a reasonable
worse case scenario mainly across portions of coastal Palm Beach
county.
* Tornadoes - A low-end tornado threat is currently forecast late today
into Thursday as banding from the system moves ashore along the
Florida east coast. The greatest potential for tornadoes will be along
Palm Beach county and northward.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Protect against life-threatening wind having possible extensive
impacts across the Palm Beach coast. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Also, protect against dangerous wind having possible limited to
significant impacts across the inland Palm Beach region and Broward
county.
* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across the Palm Beach and Broward coasts. Potential impacts
in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across Miami-Dade and Collier counties.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across the Palm Beach region, Broward county, and
coastal Miami-Dade. Potential impacts include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Ditches and canals may quickly become swollen with swift
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.
Protect against locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across the remainder of south Florida.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across Palm Beach and Glades counties. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, mobile
homes pushed off foundations or overturned, large tree tops and
branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees knocked over, moving
vehicles blown off roads, and small boats pulled from moorings.
Elsewhere across South Florida, little to no impact is anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible.
Allow extra time to reach your destination. Many roads and bridges
will be closed once strong winds arrive. Check the latest weather
forecast before departing and drive with caution.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Miami FL around 11 AM EST, or sooner if conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ063-066>075-168-172>174</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Broward County; Coastal Collier County; Coastal Miami Dade County; Coastal Palm Beach County; Far South Miami-Dade County; Glades; Hendry; Inland Broward County; Inland Collier County; Inland Miami-Dade County; Inland Palm Beach County; Mainland Monroe; Metro Broward County; Metro Palm Beach County; Metropolitan Miami Dade</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012086</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ063</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ066</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ072</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ074</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ168</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ172</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ173</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ174</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>