<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ad4ce2e88e4b2f948b9bf81e826de109cd2ca634.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2024-09-08T03:49:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>ESF</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2024-09-08T03:49:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2024-09-08T03:49:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2024-09-08T19:00:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued September 8 at 3:49AM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>ESFGUM

A developing tropical disturbance, known as JTWC's Invest 95W, is
currently located just northwest of Pohnpei near 8N158E. Forecast
guidance continues to show a gradual organization as it heads towards
the Marianas over the next few days. Model consensus indicates the
possibility of locally heavy rainfall of 4 to 8 inches across the
Marianas. Such rainfall could lead to localized flooding and the
potential for flash flooding.

Uncertainty still remains with the track and evolution of Invest 95W.
A stronger system that tracks further north could leave much of Guam
out of the focus for rainfall. A faster moving system would
dramatically reduce the residence time of heavy rainfall, which would
limit the threat for flash flooding. This product will be updated to
reflect the trend in rainfall and the potential flooding over the
next few days until it is canceled or replaced by a flash flood
watch.

Localized flooding will be possible in low-lying and poor drainage
areas, while flash flooding could also be possible in areas of heaviest
rainfall. This developing situation will continue to be monitored
closely and a flash flood watch may be issued if conditions warrant.


TIMING: Monday night through Thursday night.

RAINFALL: 4 to 8 inches of rainfall with locally higher amounts
likely.

Monitor local weather forecasts and conditions closely the next
few days. Outdoor plans and events should have an alternate plan
in place should heavy weather occur. When thunder roars, get indoors.
If you can hear thunder, you are at risk of a lightning strike. Plan
ahead and stay informed  with the latest news from your local
emergency management offices and the National Weather Service
(weather.gov/gum).
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>ESFGUM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FGMY70 PGUM 071749</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HEAVY RAINFALL POSSIBLE MONDAY NIGHT THROUGH THURSDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Guam; Rota; Tinian; Saipan</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>066010</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069100</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069120</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>GUZ001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ002</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ003</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>