<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 10 May 2022 06:34:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC1263F4539FE8.BeachHazardsStatement.1263F46015C0NC.MHXCFWMHX.5785e5f3e3dad0d258bbd4e178f60ebb</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-05-10T14:34:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-05-10T14:34:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-05-10T20:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City (Eastern North Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued May 10 at 2:34PM EDT until May 10 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City</headline>
<description>...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 6 AM EDT
THURSDAY...
...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 AM EDT THURSDAY...
...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS
EVENING...
* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Warning, 2 to 4 feet of
inundation above ground level expected near vulnerable dune
structures. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves
of 10 to 15 feet in the surf zone. For the Beach Hazards
Statement, dangerous rip currents, large breaking waves
expected, and strong longshore currents in the surf zone.
* WHERE...Oceanside Outer Banks, north of Cape Hatteras.
* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Warning, until 6 AM EDT Thursday.
For the High Surf Advisory, until 8 AM EDT Thursday. For the
Beach Hazards Statement, through this evening.
* IMPACTS...Up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation above ground level is
expected for beach-adjacent properties and roadways, resulting
in a significant threat to life and property. Numerous roads may
be closed, including several sections of NC 12 on Hatteras
Island. Low lying property including homes, businesses, and some
critical infrastructure will be inundated. Dangerous swimming
and surfing conditions and shoreline erosion will occur. Rip
currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into
deeper water. Dangerous shore break can throw a swimmer or
surfer head first into the bottom causing neck and back
injuries. Strong longshore currents will create dangerous
swimming conditions.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...This will be a long duration event with
conditions peaking through Wednesday, then gradually improving
late in the week. The greatest threat of ocean overwash and
inundation will occur around the times of high tide. Dune
erosion will be progressive and overwash will likely be worse
with each successive high tide. High tide is around 345 PM this
afternoon and 4 AM Wednesday morning. NC DOT is reporting that
NC-12 between Oregon Inlet and Rodanthe will remain closed
through at least Wednesday.
Time of high total tides are approximate to the nearest hour.
Duck NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 5.5 ft, Moderate 6.0 ft, Major 6.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor 1.8 ft, Moderate 2.3 ft, Major 2.8 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
10/04 PM     5.5        1.8        2.6      10-11    Minor
11/04 AM     5.3        1.6        2.3       10       None
11/05 PM     5.0        1.3        1.8        9       None
12/04 AM     3.9        0.2        1.0       7-8      None
12/05 PM     4.0        0.3        0.4        6       None
13/06 AM     3.1       -0.6        0.0       4-5      None
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.
Swimmers should remain out of the water due to dangerous surf
conditions.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203-205</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMHX.CF.W.0002.000000T0000Z-220512T1000Z/
/O.CON.KMHX.SU.Y.0010.000000T0000Z-220512T1200Z/
/O.CON.KMHX.BH.S.0007.000000T0000Z-220511T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ205</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>