<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.053388f7278c7097ac51503184a1ec1b4223197d.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-03-27T10:01:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a1aa0243a5f5fb2f7b8499950a2e69b1cfcb4a1d.001.1,2025-03-27T03:47:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-03-27T10:01:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-03-28T14:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-03-27T22:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Gaylord MI</senderName>
        <headline>Winter Storm Watch issued March 27 at 10:01AM EDT until March 29 at 11:00AM EDT by NWS Gaylord MI</headline>
        <description>...FIRST WAVE OF SIGNIFICANT WINTRY MIX EXPECTED FRIDAY INTO
SATURDAY...

.A series of disturbances will pass through the Great Lakes Friday
and through the rest of the weekend, bringing mixed precipitation
that will come in waves. There is potential for significant sleet
accumulation across portions of Chippewa County, along with
significant icing potential across eastern upper Michigan. There is
also icing potential across far northern lower Michigan. This watch
is set to encompass the first wave of mixed precipitation, which is
slated to occur from Friday afternoon through Saturday morning.
Another period of mixed precipitation is set to follow Saturday
night into Monday.

* WHAT...Heavy mixed precipitation possible. Total snow accumulation
of around an inch, and sleet accumulations of 1 to 2 inches,
especially across Chippewa County... and ice accumulations between
two tenths and one half of an inch possible. Winds could gust as
high as 35 mph.

* WHERE...A portion of Eastern Upper Michigan.

* WHEN...From Friday afternoon through Saturday morning.

* IMPACTS...Roads, and especially bridges and overpasses, will
likely become slick and hazardous. Significant ice accumulation on
power lines and tree limbs may cause widespread and long-lasting
power outages. Power outages and tree damage are likely due to the
ice. The hazardous conditions could impact the Friday evening and
Saturday morning commutes.
</description>
        <instruction>Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.

Persons should consider delaying all travel. If travel is absolutely
necessary, drive with extreme caution. Consider taking a winter
storm kit along with you, including such items as tire chains,
booster cables, flashlight, shovel, blankets and extra clothing.
Also take water, a first aid kit, and anything else that would help
you survive in case you become stranded.

Do not touch downed lines and report any power outages to your
electric company. Travel is highly discouraged due to slick roadways
and the possibility of downed trees and power lines.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWAPX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS43 KAPX 271401</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>WINTER STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM FRIDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH SATURDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KAPX.WS.A.0003.250328T1800Z-250329T1500Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-03-29T11:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Western Chippewa; Central Chippewa; Southeast Chippewa; Western Mackinac; Eastern Mackinac; Mackinac Island/Bois Blanc Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>026033</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>026097</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ086</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ087</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ088</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ096</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MIZ097</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>