<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 16 Sep 2022 12:20:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-VI12640C83ECD0.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640C852938VI.JSJHLSSJU.9168991cccb5b53ea133039c6c9fed6b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-15T20:20:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for St Croix; St.Thomas...St. John.. and Adjacent Islands (Virgin Islands) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-15T18:20:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-16T04:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS San Juan (San Juan, Puerto Rico)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 15 at 8:20PM AST  by NWS San Juan</headline>
<description>This product covers Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands
**TROPICAL STORM CONDITIONS EXPECTED TO BEGIN IN THE NORTHERN LEEWARD
ISLANDS FRIDAY EVENING**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Central Interior,
Culebra, Eastern Interior, Mayaguez and Vicinity, North
Central, Northeast, Northwest, Ponce and Vicinity, San Juan and
Vicinity, Southeast, Southwest, St Croix, St.Thomas...St.
John...and Adjacent Islands, Vieques, and Western Interior
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 670 miles east-southeast of San Juan PR or about 600
miles east-southeast of Saint Thomas VI
- 16.1N 56.1W
- Storm Intensity 60 mph
- Movement West or 260 degrees at 14 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
A Tropical Storm Watch remains in effect for the US Virgin Islands and
Puerto Rico. At 8 PM AST (00 UTC), the center of Fiona was located
about 385 miles east of the Lesser Antilles. Changes were not
introduced with this Intermediate Advisory. On the forecast track, the
center of Fiona is expected to move across the Leeward Islands Friday
night and early Saturday, and move near the Virgin Islands and Puerto
Rico late Saturday into Sunday. This system is expected to bring
rainfall amounts in excess of 8 inches across portions of the local
islands with life-threatening flash flooding and mudslides/rockfalls,
as well as river flooding beginning Saturday and continuing through at
least Sunday. Marine and coastal conditions are expected to deteriorate
as well starting on Saturday with seas up to 10 feet. Maximum
sustained winds near 50 mph (85 km/h) with higher gusts are expected
across much of the forecast area.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts particularly across the eastern sectors of Puerto
Rico. Potential impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, arroyos, and
ditches may become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas,
destructive runoff may run quickly down valleys while
increasing susceptibility to rockslides and mudslides. Flood
control systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible significant
impacts particularly across the eastern sectors of Puerto Rico.
* WIND:
Prepare for dangerous wind having possible significant impacts across
Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential impacts include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent
in areas with above ground lines.
* SURGE:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across Puerto Rico
and the US Virgin Islands.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a waterspouts having possible limited impacts across
the local waters of Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands.
Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated waterspouts.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
WATCH/WARNING PHASE - If you are exceptionally vulnerable to wind or
water hazards from tropical systems, consider voluntary evacuation,
especially if being officially recommended. Relocate to a predetermined
shelter or safe destination.
WATCH/WARNING PHASE - If evacuating away from the area or relocating
to a nearby shelter, leave early before weather conditions become
hazardous.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and take necessary
actions to secure your home or business. Deliberate efforts should be
underway to protect life and property. Ensure that your Emergency
Supplies Kit is stocked and ready.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track as there are inherent forecast uncertainties
which must be taken into account.
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any orders
that are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives
of others.
Visitors to the area should become familiar with nearby surroundings.
If you are a visitor, know the name of the county or parish in which
you are located and where it is relative to current watches and
warnings. If staying at a hotel, ask the management staff about their
onsite disaster plan. Listen for evacuation orders, especially
pertaining to area visitors.
Closely monitor NOAA Weather Radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for possible changes to the
forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in San Juan PR around 11 PM AST, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ001>013-VIZ001-002</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>St Croix; St.Thomas...St. John.. and Adjacent Islands</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078030</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VIZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VIZ002</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>