<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.525ae0fe10792e5e421204d5566ff448fdf5193c.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2024-11-10T04:48:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2024-11-10T04:48:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2024-11-10T04:48:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2024-11-11T09:00:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued November 10 at 4:48AM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>The Joint Typhoon Warning Center's (JTWC) Invest 94W continues to
move west-northwest, spreading numerous showers and isolated
thunderstorms across western Chuuk State and eastern Yap State.
Latest scatterometer and infrared satellite data suggest 94W is
centered west-southwest of Chuuk Proper near 5N147E. The latest
CIMSS tropical vorticity analysis however, shows mid-level vorticity
in the 850mb to 500mb layer is displaced slightly north of the
surface circulation, which is likely leading the variability in the
forecast track in the models. Satellite imagery shows moderate to
deep convection over a broad area covering much of western Chuuk
State and eastern Yap State. The overnight scatterometry data shows
an area of moderate to fresh winds north of the disorganized
circulation center, though gusts around 25 kt (30 mph) are possible
near heavier showers and thunderstorms.

This disturbance is favored to continue west-northwest over the next
few days, becoming gradually more organized as it shifts south of
the Marianas this afternoon into Monday. Latest model guidance shows
94W passing to the north of Yap Proper through Monday night as it
strengthens, potentially reaching tropical storm strength (sustained
maximum winds greater than 33 kts) sometime late Monday night or
Tuesday. The forecasted track keeps 94W north of Yap State as it
heads into the Philippine Sea over the next few days, but unsettled
weather may still be felt across the eastern outer islands of Yap
State and possibly Yap Proper, especially tonight through Monday
night. Locally heavy showers and associated strong wind gusts are
possible. Travel between islands could become hazardous with gusty
winds and choppy sea near thunderstorms.

Folks across Chuuk State and Yap State should monitor local weather
forecasts the next couple of days from the National Weather Service
in Guam, and for additional information from your local Weather
Service Office and emergency management. Visit
weather.gov/gum/PublicForecasts for the latest weather information
from the National Weather Service.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSPQ2</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWPQ82 PGUM 091848</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>MONITORING INVEST 94W IN WESTERN MICRONESIA FOR FURTHER DEVELOPMENT... ...LOCALLY HEAVY SHOWERS AND GUSTY WINDS POSSIBLE FOR EASTERN YAP STATE AND WESTERN CHUUK STATE</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Chuuk Lagoon; Yap</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>064002</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>064060</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FMZ023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FMZ037</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>