<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 29 Aug 2023 09:12:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12665B637E40.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B7050ACNC.ILMHLSILM.d838455169a39e8c4e10ccf948b09ac7</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-29T17:12:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Brunswick; Coastal New Hanover; Coastal Pender (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-29T18:00:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-30T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Wilmington (Northeastern South Carolina and Southeastern North Carolina - Wilmington)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 29 at 5:12PM EDT  by NWS Wilmington</headline>
<description>This product covers southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina
**IDALIA WILL IMPACT THE AREA LATE WEDNESDAY THROUGH THURSDAY**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Watch has been upgraded to a Tropical Storm
Warning for Central Horry, Coastal Brunswick, Coastal
Georgetown, Coastal Horry, Coastal New Hanover, Coastal Pender,
Inland Georgetown, Northern Horry, and Williamsburg
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Central Horry,
Coastal Brunswick, Coastal Georgetown, Coastal Horry, Coastal
New Hanover, Coastal Pender, Inland Georgetown, Northern Horry,
and Williamsburg
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 700 miles southwest of Wilmington NC or about 630 miles
southwest of Myrtle Beach SC
- 26.1N 84.8W
- Storm Intensity 100 mph
- Movement North or 360 degrees at 16 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Idalia will move up the Carolina coast late Wednesday night into
Thursday. The main impact will be heavy rain and localized flooding.
Isolated tornadoes will also be possible, closest to the coast.
Minimal tropical storm force winds may cause power outages, again
closest to the coast where minor storm surge is also possible.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- Major flooding from rainfall may prompt evacuations and
numerous rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rapidly overflow their banks in multiple
places. Creeks and ditches will flood and may contain strong
currents.
- Flood waters may enter many structures, and some may become
uninhabitable. Some road scours or complete road failures will
be possible, along with the potential for sinkholes. Many
streets and parking lots may flood, and may be impacted by
flowing water. Many road and low-lying bridge closures are
possible with some weakened or washed away. Driving conditions
will be dangerous.
- The delivery of drinking water and sewer services may be
interrupted. Flood waters may be polluted and contain hazardous
materials.
* WIND:
Protect against dangerous wind having possible significant impacts
across coastal southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina.
Potential impacts in this area include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding, along with damage to porches
and awnings. A few buildings experiencing window, door, and
garage door failures. Damage to vulnerable structures such as
carports, sheds and mobile homes is possible.
- Large limbs will be down with several trees snapped or
uprooted. Several fences and roadway signs may become blown
over. Some roads may become impassable due to large debris
blocking the roadway, especially within urban or heavily wooded
locations. Some bridges, causeways, and elevated roads may be
impacted by high winds making driving on them hazardous.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible, but
more prevalent in areas with above ground lines.
- Small craft that are not properly moored may break loose.
Also, protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts
across inland areas of southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina.
* SURGE:
Prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
across the coast. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation and minor over-wash is possible, mainly
along immediate shorelines and other vulnerable low-lying areas
along the coast. Low spots along waterways and tidal creeks may
also be impacted.
- Some portions of near-shore roads and parking lots may become
covered by surge water. Driving conditions may become hazardous
in places where the surge covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion is possible, mainly in the vulnerable
locations along the ocean front.
- Minor damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers is
possible. A few small craft may break away from moorings if not
properly secured.
- Navigation may be difficult near inlets and waterways, as
navigational aids may be off station or missing.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a dangerous tornado event having possible significant
impacts across coastal southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of scattered tornadoes can hinder preparedness
actions during tropical events.
- Tornadoes can rip roofs from homes, destroy mobile homes, cause
trees to become snapped or uprooted, flip cars and boats.
Dangerous projectiles can add to the damage.
- Several places may experience tornado damage with a few spots
of considerable damage, power loss, and communications failures.
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
far inland areas of southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and take necessary
actions to secure your home or business. Deliberate efforts should be
underway to protect life and property. Ensure that your Emergency
Supplies Kit is stocked and ready.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track as there are inherent forecast uncertainties
which must be taken into account.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low lying or poor
drainage area, plan to move to safe shelter on higher ground
Closely monitor NOAA Weather Radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for possible changes to the
forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Wilmington NC around 11 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ106-108-110-SCZ039-054>056-058-059</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Brunswick; Coastal New Hanover; Coastal Pender</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037129</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ106</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ108</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ110</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>