<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.38fdccdb0b077fa67b447c088cb63d370f3df68b.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-28T14:40:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Extreme Heat Warning</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>XHW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-28T14:40:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-29T11:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-29T05:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Upton NY</senderName>
        <headline>Extreme Heat Warning issued July 28 at 2:40PM EDT until July 30 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Upton NY</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Heat Advisory, heat index values up to 101. For the
Extreme Heat Warning, dangerously hot conditions with heat index
values up to 106 expected.

* WHERE...Eastern Bergen, Eastern Essex, Eastern Passaic, Eastern
Union, Hudson, Western Bergen, Western Essex, and Western Union
Counties.

* WHEN...For the Heat Advisory, until 11 AM EDT Tuesday. For the
Extreme Heat Warning, from 11 AM Tuesday to 8 PM EDT Wednesday.

* IMPACTS...Extreme heat and humidity will significantly increase
the potential for heat related illnesses, particularly for those
working or participating in outdoor activities. Hot temperatures
and high humidity may cause heat illnesses.
</description>
        <instruction>An Extreme Heat Warning means that the combination of heat and
humidity is expected to make it feel like it is 105 degrees or
greater. Take extra precautions if you work or spend time outside.
When possible, reschedule strenuous activities to early morning or
evening. Know the signs and symptoms of heat exhaustion and heat
stroke. Wear light weight and loose fitting clothing when possible,
and drink plenty of water.

Seniors and those with chronic health problems or mental health
conditions are at an increased risk. Homes without air conditioning
can be much hotter than outdoor temperatures.

Use air conditioning to stay cool at home or go to a place that has
air conditioning. If you don't have home air conditioning, continue
to seek out cool spaces each day as long as it remains hot, and for
a few days after if your home is still hot. Check on vulnerable
friends, family members and neighbors.

To reduce risk during outdoor work, the Occupational Safety and
Health Administration recommends scheduling frequent rest breaks in
shaded or air conditioned environments. Anyone overcome by heat
should be moved to a cool and shaded location. Heat stroke is an
emergency! In cases of heat stroke call 9 1 1.

A Heat Advisory is issued when the combination of heat and humidity
is expected to make it feel like it is 95 to 99 degrees for two or
more consecutive days, or 100 to 104 degrees for any length of time.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>NPWOKX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS71 KOKX 281840</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HEAT ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 11 AM EDT TUESDAY... ...EXTREME HEAT WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 11 AM TUESDAY TO 8 PM EDT WEDNESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KOKX.XH.W.0003.250729T1500Z-250731T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-30T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Eastern Passaic; Hudson; Western Bergen; Eastern Bergen; Western Essex; Eastern Essex; Western Union; Eastern Union</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>034031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>034017</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>034003</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>034013</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>034039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ004</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ006</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ104</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ105</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ106</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ107</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NJZ108</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>