<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.77ac52506e65ca6c3a57062441adc228e358fd60.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-02T20:25:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-02T20:25:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-02T20:25:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-04T05:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Melbourne FL</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued October 2 at 8:25PM EDT until October 5 at 11:00PM EDT by NWS Melbourne FL</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, minor coastal flooding.
For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 5 to 8
feet in the surf zone. For the High Rip Current Risk,
dangerous rip currents.

* WHERE...Coastal Volusia County.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 11 PM EDT Sunday.
For the High Surf Advisory, until 4 AM EDT Sunday. For the
High Rip Current Risk, through late Saturday night.

* IMPACTS...Some flooding of low-lying lots, parks and roadways
may occur near the shoreline. Only isolated road closures are
expected. Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and
localized beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best
swimmers away from shore into deeper water.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...High tide is expected between 6 to 9 AM and
PM through this weekend.
</description>
        <instruction>Onshore winds and above normal tides will combine to generate
flooding of low areas along the shore. Do not drive around
barricades or through water of unknown depth. Take the necessary
actions to protect flood-prone property.

High surf will affect the beaches in the advisory area, producing
localized beach erosion and dangerous swimming conditions.
Swimmers should remain out of the water due to large breaking
waves and dangerous surf conditions.

Rip currents are powerful channels of water flowing quickly away
from shore, which occur most often at low spots or breaks in the
sandbar and in the vicinity of structures such as jetties and
piers. Heed the advice of lifeguards, beach patrol flags and
signs.

Entering the surf is strongly discouraged. If caught in a rip
current, relax and float. Don't swim against the current. If
able, swim in a direction following the shoreline. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMLB</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMLB 030025</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 11 PM EDT SUNDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 4 AM EDT SUNDAY... ...HIGH RIP CURRENT RISK REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH LATE SATURDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMLB.CF.Y.0001.251003T0025Z-251006T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-05T23:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Coastal Volusia</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012127</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ141</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>