<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.cebe4f03c6c7b1557261eafea73f8f3eeed62501.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-04-08T13:32:00-06:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>ESF</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-04-08T13:32:00-06:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-04-08T13:32:00-06:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-04-09T01:45:00-06:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Riverton WY</senderName>
        <headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued April 8 at 1:32PM MDT by NWS Riverton WY</headline>
        <description>ESFRIW

Temperatures are forecast to climb Thursday through Saturday, which
will melt low elevation and foothill snow in far west Wyoming,
specifically the Star Valley region. There is also potential for
higher elevation snow to melt during this time. Current high
temperatures are forecast to be in the 60s Thursday and Friday and
around 60 on Saturday. additionally, low temperatures Friday and
Saturday mornings will struggle to drop below the mid-30s.

These warm temperatures are around 15 degrees above normal and could
result in significant melting of snow given a deep snowpack. As of
Tuesday April 8th, a snow depth of 20-25 inches exists near Bedford,
WY. Additionally, the snow pack temperatures in the mountains
around Star Valley are around 32F as of Tuesday April 8th. With
much above normal temperatures, above freezing overnight lows
Thursday April 10th - Saturday April 12th, and primed snowpack,
there is significant snow melt potential. This snowmelt could
quickly raise the water levels around Fairview and in tributary
creeks and streams of the Salt River, especially Spring, Tin Cup,
Crow, Jack Knife, and Stump creeks. Temperatures are forecast to
drop below freezing Saturday night.

Now would be the time to clear snow, ice, and debris from culverts
and other flow paths to allow runoff to flow away from buildings and
other vulnerable infrastructure. This could include moving deep snow
away from the foundations of buildings, relocating equipment to
higher ground, and moving livestock out of poorly drained or low-
lying areas.

Stay tuned for the latest river forecasts. Remember, if you
encounter a flooded roadway, turn around don't drown. You never know
what road conditions are hidden under the water.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>ESFRIW</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FGUS75 KRIW 081932</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>Warming Temperatures Later this Week Increase Snow Melt and the Potential for Flooding</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Lincoln, WY</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>056023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>WYC023</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>