<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:22:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-VA126660FD3968.StormSurgeWarning.126660FD6398VA.AKQTCVAKQ.56ac3281314436e8f81288c98258eed8</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-09-23T13:22:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Westmoreland (Virginia) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Storm Surge Warning</event>
<urgency></urgency>
<severity></severity>
<certainty></certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-09-23T13:22:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-09-23T14:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Wakefield (Eastern Virginia and Southern Maryland)</senderName>
<headline>Storm Surge Warning issued September 23 at 1:22PM EDT until further notice by NWS Wakefield</headline>
<description>...STORM SURGE WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...TROPICAL STORM WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Colonial Beach
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Below tropical storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 20-30 mph with gusts to 45 mph
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- The wind threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Remaining efforts to protect property should be
completed as soon as possible. Prepare for limited wind
damage.
- ACT: Move to safe shelter before the wind becomes hazardous.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, especially if soils are saturated. Some roadway
signs will sustain damage.
- A few roads will be impassable from debris. Hazardous
driving conditions on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Life-threatening storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 2-4 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: through early Sunday morning
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 3 feet above ground
- The storm surge threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Shelter against life-threatening storm surge of
greater than 3 feet above ground.
- PREPARE: Flood preparations and ordered evacuations should
be complete. Evacuees should be in shelters well away from
storm surge flooding.
- ACT: Remain sheltered in a safe location. Do not venture
outside.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main surge event are unfolding.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Flood Watch is in effect
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: Additional 1-3 inches, with locally
higher amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
moderate flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
moderate flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues
are possible.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action may result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Flooding from heavy rainfall may prompt evacuations and
rescues
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen, with
swift currents, and overspill their banks. Small streams,
creeks, and ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures and/or weaken
foundations. Some areas may experience areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor
drainage areas. Some streets and parking lots take on
moving water as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
Driving conditions become hazardous. Some road and bridge
closures are expected.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is somewhat favorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for a few
tornadoes
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for a
few tornadoes.
- PREPARE: If your shelter is particularly vulnerable to
tornadoes, prepare to relocate to safe shelter before
hazardous weather arrives.
- ACT: If a tornado warning is issued, be ready to shelter
quickly.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- A few tornadoes are expected. As a result, execution of
emergency plans could be hindered in affected areas.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with
power and communications disruptions.
- Roofs peeled off some buildings. A few chimneys toppled and
mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned. Large
tree tops and branches snapped off, with some trees knocked
over. A few vehicles blown off roads.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes
- www.readyvirginia.gov
- weather.gov/akq
LAT...LON 3828 7698 3826 7696 3824 7696 3823 7696
3821 7695 3819 7691 3817 7688 3816 7684
3817 7679 3817 7675 3816 7669 3815 7663
3815 7661 3811 7660 3807 7654 3806 7654
3804 7652 3803 7652 3803 7656 3803 7657
3802 7657 3800 7659 3800 7662 3805 7661
3805 7658 3807 7658 3808 7666 3806 7667
3805 7664 3803 7664 3804 7676 3809 7675
3809 7678 3811 7677 3812 7680 3814 7680
3815 7694 3817 7695 3818 7699 3818 7700
3818 7703 3818 7705 3826 7704 3826 7704
3827 7703 3827 7700 3827 7699 3827 7699
3828 7698</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VAZ075</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KAKQ.SS.W.1016.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Westmoreland</areaDesc>
<polygon>38.14,-77.03 38.13,-77.02 38.13,-76.98 38.13,-76.96 38.11,-76.94 38.09,-76.94 38.08,-76.94 38.08,-76.94 38.09,-76.98 38.09,-76.99 38.11,-76.99 38.11,-77 38.09,-77.01 38.09,-77.03 38.1,-77.04 38.11,-77.05 38.14,-77.05 38.16,-77.06 38.17,-77.06 38.16,-77.05 38.14,-77.03 38.14,-77.03</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>051193</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VAZ075</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>