<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.cfc24d3d3bcfd3610c8119c9d8e4645f564fcc38.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-02T15:46:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-02T15:46:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-02T15:46:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-03T18:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Anchorage AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 2 at 3:46PM AKDT until August 3 at 6:00PM AKDT by NWS Anchorage AK</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...Matanuska River.

* WHEN...Until 600 PM AKDT Sunday.

* IMPACTS...River levels have exceeded those observed in early July,
and increased bank erosion expected along the lower Matanuska
River. While water levels may rise in small streams and rivers
across the Matanuska-Susitna Valley, flooding is not expected west
of the lower Matanuska River. Minor flooding in low-lying and poor
drainage areas. Possible isolated landslides in areas of steep
terrain primarily between Sutton and Eureka.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 336 PM AKDT, river gauge reports indicate rises in water
levels from heavy rain in the advisory area. Minor flooding
is ongoing or expected to begin shortly, especially near
Matanuska River. Between 1.5 and 2 inches of rain have
fallen.
- - For Matanuska River at Palmer:
At 2:30pm the stage was 28600.0 cfs.
Forecast: A crest around 34016.8 cfs is expected around
10:00pm Saturday.

Impacts:
At 15000.0 cfs: Action Flow - This discharge (flow) level
represents the higher end of the typical summertime range,
and will likely be reached at least once nearly every year.
Localized minor out-of-bank flooding may start to occur along
parts of the Glenn highway, especially east of Sutton from
milepost 64 to 66.
At 30000.0 cfs: Minor Flood Flow - This discharge (flow)
level has a roughly 20 percent chance of being reached in any
given year. Additional vulnerable locations near the active
river channel may experience some flooding at this level west
of the Old Glenn Highway in the Butte and near Sutton from
Milepost 64 to 66. Residents are advised that for the past
several years at both of these locations, the main channel of
the river has been shifting closer to the bank.
At 35000.0 cfs: Moderate Flood Flow - This discharge (flow)
level has a roughly 10 percent chance of being reached in any
given year. Flooding near vulnerable locations along the
active river channel may become more significant and
widespread. This level was reached during the flooding in
2012.
- For Moose Creek near Palmer:
At 2:45pm the stage was 16.0 feet.
Flood Stage is 17.5 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood

- If you live near or along the Matanuska River near Palmer or
Butte stay alert and be prepared to take action.
</description>
        <instruction>Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSAFC</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK88 PAFC 022346</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FOR THE MATANUSKA RIVER UNTIL 6 PM AKDT SUNDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.PAFC.FA.Y.0019.250802T2346Z-250804T0200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-03T18:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Lower Matanuska Valley; Sutton / Upper Matanuska Valley</areaDesc>
            <polygon>61.6,-149.01 61.51,-148.98 61.49,-149.1 61.57,-149.15 61.65,-149.15 61.7,-149.07 61.76,-148.84 61.82,-148.48 61.84,-148.13 61.83,-147.83 61.82,-147.82 61.81,-147.71 61.81,-147.7 61.76,-147.64 61.77,-147.98 61.77,-148.32 61.75,-148.53 61.69,-148.87 61.66,-149.03 61.63,-149.03 61.6,-149.01</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002170</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ711</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ713</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>