<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.41cf3941bd06f006a50fb0123fd6c544dd09b591.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-02T07:09:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.9097c9b0c067a0cc54085cd11addd2d1ff9ae689.001.1,2025-08-01T15:10:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.4ada9da07b47cb5578d2d029f0d308af625d1acd.001.1,2025-08-02T05:56:00-08:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-02T07:09:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-02T07:09:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-03T07:15:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Anchorage AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Watch issued August 2 at 7:09AM AKDT until August 4 at 3:00PM AKDT by NWS Anchorage AK</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is possible.

* WHERE...The lower Matanuska River near Butte and Palmer as well as
small rivers and streams between Sutton and Eureka.

* WHEN...Through Monday afternoon.

* IMPACTS...Heavy rainfall will lead to rapid runoff and rises in
small streams draining the steep terrain along the Glenn Highway
between Sutton and Eureka. Landslides are possible in
landslide-prone areas along this corridor. Significant runoff is
also expected to raise water levels on the Matanuska River, with
some locations approaching bankfull by early Sunday morning. River
levels may approach or even exceed those observed in early July,
with increased bank erosion expected along the lower Matanuska
River. While water levels may rise in small streams and rivers
across the Matanuska-Susitna Valley, flooding is not expected west
of the lower Matanuska River.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- Rain will continue across the western Copper River Basin and
northern Matanuska Valley Saturday morning through Sunday
morning. As of 4 AM this morning, 1.00" to 1.25" inches of
rain has already fallen across the area. An additional 0.50"
to 1.00" of rain is possible through Sunday morning, with
projected rainfall totals with this storm likely around 1 to
2 inches from Mendeltna to Sutton. Precipitation will be
enhanced near terrain and along the northeast facing slopes
of the Talkeetna and Chugach mountains. The heaviest rainfall
is expected within the mountainous terrain along the Glenn
Highway corridor between Sutton and Eureka. Ponding of water
on roadways and erosion of unpaved surfaces is also possible.

As of 4 AM Saturday morning, the Matanuska River at Palmer
(MATA2) is at 16800 cfs and is expected to crest Sunday
morning at 25100 cfs, which is below minor flood stage (30000
cfs).

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood

- If you live near or along the Matanuska River, stay alert and be
prepared to take action.
- All residents on or near mountain slopes should be prepared for
possible landslides.
</description>
        <instruction>Persons living along streams should stay alert and be prepared to
take action if a warning or advisory is issued, or flooding is
observed.

You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.

Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.

Reports on river conditions can be sent to the River Forecast Center
by calling 1-800-847-1739</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFAAFC</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK68 PAFC 021509 CCA</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH MONDAY AFTERNOON FOR THE WESTERN COPPER RIVER BASIN, SUTTON, AND PORTIONS OF THE MATANUSKA VALLEY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.COR.PAFC.FA.A.0003.000000T0000Z-250804T2300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-04T15:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Lower Matanuska Valley; Sutton / Upper Matanuska Valley; Eureka / Tahneta Pass</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002170</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ711</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ713</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ714</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>