<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.70de5daebbb9d89cc35f077e1fe50c6f483b21ce.001.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-08T20:26:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-08T20:26:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-09T08:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-09T08:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued October 8 at 8:26PM EDT until October 9 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, 1 to 3 feet of inundation
above ground level expected in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the Coastal Flood Watch, 2 to 4 feet of
inundation above ground level possible in low-lying areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways. For the Beach Hazards Statement,
dangerous rip currents.

* WHERE...For the Coastal Flood Watch and Advisory, areas along
Hatteras beaches, Pamlico Sound, and adjacent tidal creeks. For
the Beach Hazards Statement, the beaches north of Cape
Hatteras..

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, from 7 AM Thursday to 5
PM EDT Saturday. For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 8 AM
EDT Thursday through Thursday evening. For the Coastal Flood
Watch, from Saturday afternoon through Monday morning.

* IMPACTS...For the Beach Hazards Statement, rip currents can
sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper water.
For the Coastal Flood Advisory, up to 1 to 3 feet of inundation
above ground level with minor ocean overwash possible in
vulnerable locations along shorelines and tidal waterways. For
the Coastal Flood Watch, up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation above
ground level is possible in some areas near shorelines and tidal
waterways resulting in an elevated threat of property damage
around the times of high tide. Flooding will extend inland from
the waterfront threatening some homes and businesses. Numerous
road closures and flooding of vehicles will be possible, most
notably along NC 12 where ocean overwash may make several
portions of the highway inaccessible across Hatteras Island.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...A strong coastal storm will develop this
weekend off the North Carolina coast, and has the potential to
bring stronger winds and higher water levels to the area.
Depending on the exact track and strength of the low, there is
potential for major coastal flooding impacts from ocean
overwash, and users are urged to check back in on the forecast
the rest of the week.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 090026</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 7 AM THURSDAY TO 5 PM EDT SATURDAY... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT FROM 8 AM EDT THURSDAY THROUGH THURSDAY EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM SATURDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH MONDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.BH.S.0084.251009T1200Z-251010T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-09T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>