<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.bd0e417cd14e673dcb8d16a34598ed1e6d61e1a8.005.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-08T04:32:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.cbef6addf0f16e06897600bb789c470eae48a55d.005.1,2025-10-07T20:37:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-08T04:32:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-08T04:32:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-08T16:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued October 8 at 4:32AM EDT until October 8 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Watch, 2 to 4 feet of inundation
above ground level expected in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the Beach Hazards Statement,
dangerous rip currents.

* WHERE...For the Coastal Flood Watch, areas along the beaches,
Pamlico Sound, and adjacent tidal creeks, and Ocracoke Island.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, Ocracoke Island beaches and
Hatteras Island beaches south of Cape Hatteras.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, through this evening.
For the Coastal Flood Watch, from Thursday morning through
Monday morning.

* IMPACTS...For the Coastal Flood Watch, up to 2 to 4 feet of
inundation above ground level is possible in some areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways resulting in an elevated threat
of property damage around the times of high tide. Flooding
will extend inland from the waterfront threatening some homes
and businesses. Numerous road closures and flooding of
vehicles will be possible, most notably along NC 12 where
ocean overwash may make several portions of the highway
inaccessible across Ocracoke and Hatteras Islands. For the
Beach Hazards Statement, rip currents can sweep even the best
swimmers away from shore into deeper water.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...A strong coastal storm will develop this
weekend off the North Carolina coast, and has the potential to
bring stronger winds and higher water levels to the area.
Depending on the exact track and strength of the low, there is
potential for major coastal flooding impacts from ocean
overwash, and users are urged to check back in on the forecast
the rest of the week. The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 3:05 PM Wednesday.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 080832</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT NOW IN EFFECT THROUGH THIS EVENING SOUTH OF CAPE HATTERAS... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM THURSDAY MORNING THROUGH MONDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXT.KMHX.BH.S.0083.251008T0832Z-251009T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-08T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Ocracoke Island; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>