<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2583d5523d59d0ede84b9a9a810c60aeb2770757.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-09T14:29:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-09T14:29:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-10T05:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-12T04:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Melbourne FL</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Warning issued October 9 at 2:29PM EDT until October 10 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Melbourne FL</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, minor coastal flooding.
For the High Rip Current Risk, dangerous rip currents. For the
High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 3 to 8 feet
expected in the surf zone. For the Coastal Flood Warning,
significant coastal flooding expected. For the Coastal Flood
Watch, significant coastal flooding possible.

* WHERE...Coastal Volusia County.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 5 AM EDT Friday.
For the High Rip Current Risk, through late Saturday night.
For the High Surf Advisory, from 8 PM this evening to 4 AM EDT
Sunday. For the Coastal Flood Warning, from 5 AM to 8 PM EDT
Friday. For the Coastal Flood Watch, from Friday evening
through late Saturday night.

* IMPACTS...Coastal roads may be closed. Low lying property
including homes, businesses and some critical infrastructure
will be inundated. Significant shoreline erosion will occur.
Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and localized beach
erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from
shore into deeper water.
</description>
        <instruction>Coastal flooding is occurring or imminent. Coastal residents in
the warned area should be alert for rising water, and take
appropriate action to protect life and property. If travel is
required, do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth.

High surf will affect the beaches in the advisory area, producing
localized beach erosion and dangerous swimming conditions.
Swimmers should remain out of the water due to large breaking
waves and dangerous surf conditions.

Rip currents are powerful channels of water flowing quickly away
from shore, which occur most often at low spots or breaks in the
sandbar and in the vicinity of structures such as jetties and
piers. Heed the advice of lifeguards, beach patrol flags and
signs.

Entering the surf is strongly discouraged. If caught in a rip
current, relax and float. Don't swim against the current. If
able, swim in a direction following the shoreline. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMLB</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMLB 091829</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 5 AM EDT FRIDAY... ...HIGH RIP CURRENT RISK REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH LATE SATURDAY NIGHT... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 8 PM THIS EVENING TO 4 AM EDT SUNDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 5 AM TO 8 PM EDT FRIDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH NOW IN EFFECT FROM FRIDAY EVENING THROUGH LATE SATURDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMLB.CF.W.0001.251010T0900Z-251011T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Coastal Volusia</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012127</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ141</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>