<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 22 Sep 2023 09:14:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC126660EE9048.HurricaneLocalStatement.126660FB61ECNC.MHXHLSMHX.29ef2c68c549b66a8db5b54dbfcd764b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-09-22T17:14:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Beaufort; Coastal Onslow; Duplin; East Carteret; Greene; Hatteras Island; Inland Onslow; Jones; Lenoir; Mainland Dare; Mainland Hyde; Martin; Northern Craven; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Pamlico; Pitt; Southern Craven; Tyrrell; Washington; West Carteret (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-09-22T17:05:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-09-23T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City (Eastern North Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 22 at 5:14PM EDT  by NWS Newport/Morehead City</headline>
<description>This product covers Eastern North Carolina
**HURRICANE WATCH ISSUED FOR PORTIONS OF EASTERN NORTH CAROLINA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Hurricane Watch has been issued and the Storm Surge Watch has
been upgraded to a Storm Surge Warning for West Carteret
- A Hurricane Watch has been issued for Coastal Onslow, East
Carteret, Pamlico, and Southern Craven
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning, Tropical Storm Warning, and Hurricane
Watch are in effect for East Carteret, Pamlico, Southern
Craven, and West Carteret
- A Tropical Storm Warning, Storm Surge Watch, and Hurricane
Watch are in effect for Coastal Onslow
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Beaufort, Hatteras Island, Mainland Hyde, Northern Outer
Banks, and Ocracoke Island
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Mainland Dare, Tyrrell, and Washington
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Duplin, Greene,
Inland Onslow, Jones, Lenoir, Martin, Northern Craven, and Pitt
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 170 miles south-southwest of Buxton NC or about 130 miles
south of Morehead City NC
- 32.9N 76.3W
- Storm Intensity 70 mph
- Movement North-northwest or 345 degrees at 13 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Ophelia, currently located around 150 miles
southeast of Cape Fear, North Carolina, will continue to strengthen as
it moves toward eastern North Carolina tonight, and makes landfall
across the Crystal Coast early tomorrow morning. Moderate to locally
significant impacts will occur across eastern North Carolina, with the
greatest impacts along the coast.
Life threatening storm surge with inundation 2 to 4 feet above ground
level is expected across all coastal areas tonight into tomorrow.
Additionally, up to 4 to 6 feet of storm surge is possible across the
lower Pamlico and Neuse Rivers. There remains potential for at least
minor overwash also along the Outer Banks through the weekend.
Finally, we continue to monitor the potential for rapid water level
rises across the soundside Outer Banks tomorrow and into tomorrow
night when the winds shift.
Tropical storm force winds will continue to impact eastern North
Carolina through tomorrow, with winds increasing tonight and through
tomorrow morning as Ophelia approaches. These strong winds will have
the potential to cause areas of tree damage and power outages.
Heavy rain will continue to bring additional rainfall amounts of 3 to
5 inches, with isolated amounts up to 8 to 10 inches across Onslow and
Duplin counties. This will bring the threat of localized flash
flooding especially in low-lying, urban, and poor drainage areas.
A few tornadoes could produce locally significant damage, mainly east
of Highway 17 late today into early tomorrow.
Dangerous marine conditions will continue for all coastal waters, the
sounds and rivers, with strong winds and dangerous seas building to
create treacherous conditions for mariners. Localized ocean overwash
is expected along the coast due to high surf. Stronger and more
frequent rip currents will also exist along area beaches through the
weekend.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are now unfolding across
coastal North Carolina north of Surf City. The highest potential for
significant impacts will be up and along the Neuse and Pamlico Rivers
as well as soundside locations across the Outer Banks. Remain well away
from life-threatening surge having possible significant impacts. If
realized, these impacts include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.
* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
Eastern North Carolina. Remain well sheltered from dangerous wind
having possible significant impacts. If realized,
these impacts include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent
in areas with above ground lines.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
eastern North Carolina. Remain well guarded against
life-threatening flood waters having possible extensive impacts.
If realized, these impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may
become dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and barriers may
become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
* TORNADOES:
Potential impacts from tornadoes are still unfolding across eastern
North Carolina. Remain well braced against a dangerous tornado
event having possible significant impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- The occurrence of scattered tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- Several places may experience tornado damage with a few spots
of considerable damage, power loss, and communications failures.
- Locations could realize roofs torn off frame houses, mobile
homes demolished, boxcars overturned, large trees snapped or
uprooted, vehicles tumbled, and small boats tossed about.
Dangerous projectiles can add to the toll.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to stay inside and away from windows. Listen for
updates and be ready in case you lose electrical power. Keep a
battery-powered radio, charged cell phone and flashlight handy.
Keep your cell phone charged and in power-saving mode. If you lose
power, use it sparingly and mainly for personal emergencies and
check-ins.
Do not be a thrill seeker or risk your life for senseless photos or
videos.
If you are prone to flooding or in an area under a storm surge watch
or warning, be prepared for the possibility of a quick and dramatic
rise in water levels.
If a tornado warning is issued for your area, quickly move to the
safest place within your shelter. Protect your head and body.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Newport/Morehead City NC around 11 PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ029-044>047-079>081-090>092-094-193>196-198-199-203>205</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Beaufort; Coastal Onslow; Duplin; East Carteret; Greene; Hatteras Island; Inland Onslow; Jones; Lenoir; Mainland Dare; Mainland Hyde; Martin; Northern Craven; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Pamlico; Pitt; Southern Craven; Tyrrell; Washington; West Carteret</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037137</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037177</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037187</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ090</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ092</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ094</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ193</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ194</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ195</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ196</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ198</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ199</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ204</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ205</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>