<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 04 Sep 2022 12:23:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AK12640BCCD2FC.FloodAdvisory.12640BCF6210AK.AFCFLSAFC.a6d1d966fc152901787647558fb31749</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-03T16:23:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Western Kenai Peninsula; Western Prince William Sound (Alaska) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-04T07:54:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-04T09:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Anchorage (Southern Alaska - Anchorage)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Advisory issued September 03 at 4:23PM AKDT  by NWS Anchorage</headline>
<description>...FLOOD ADVISORY FOR A GLACIER-DAMMED LAKE OUTBURST IN EFFECT UNTIL
230 PM AKDT THURSDAY FOR SNOW RIVER TO KENAI LAKE AND DOWN THE KENAI
RIVER TO SKILAK LAKE...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by a glacier-dammed lake outburst continues.
* WHERE...Including the following areas, the Snow River, Kenai Lake,
and the Kenai River from Kenai Lake to Skilak Lake.
* WHEN...Until 230 PM AKDT Thursday.
* IMPACTS...Water will flow over Primrose Road (leading to Primrose
Campground), likely becoming impassable to small vehicles and
affecting campground access. Garages along Primrose Road may begin
to flood. Water levels are expected to steadily rise tonight
through Sunday and peak sometime Sunday night or Monday morning.
Sterling Highway Residences from Milepost 48 to 50 could see water
in their yards. Cooper Landing boat launch &quot;fish walk&quot; could become
submerged. Potential flooding of Quartz Creek boat ramp and adjacent
campsites. Water levels in these areas are expected to crest Monday
night or Tuesday.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 421 PM AKDT, Based on rising Snow River water levels and
downstream water temperature we believe the Snow Glacier
Dammed Lake has begun to release. Water levels on Snow River
just upstream of Kenai Lake have risen 1.5 feet since 30
August. The hydrographic trend continues to rise steeply in
the absence of relative precipitation.
Typically Snow Glacier Dammed Lake releases every other year;
the last release was in October 2020.
Current water level on the Snow River is above 11 ft, gage
datum, and is expected to rise an additional 2-3 feet with a
crest near 13 ft early Monday. At this time we expect Snow
River water levels to exceed bankfull, but well below flood
stage (16 ft, gage datum).
Residents near the Snow River and the Kenai Lake confluence
and Kenai Lake outlet should monitor local conditions and
prepare for rising water levels.
Current water level on the Kenai River at Cooper Landing is
above 11 ft, gage datum, and may be just starting to rise. At
this time, we anticipate a peak 4-5 ft higher than present
water level. The forecast models suggest that by late Sunday,
Kenai Lake outlet will reach Minor flood stage (13 ft, gage
datum) and rise another 1 to 3 feet before the flood peak
crests early Tuesday. Water level recession from flood stage
should continue through the middle of the week before
dropping below bank.
The flood wave is expected to dissipate by lake effects with
only minor water level rises below Skilak Lake and no flood
impacts.
- Inherent uncertainty in initial glacier lake volume will
result in varying crest height and timing.  -
http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood</description>
<instruction>Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.
Turn around, don`t drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.
Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.
Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ121-125</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.COR.PAFC.FA.Y.0012.000000T0000Z-220908T2230Z/
/00000.N.GO.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Western Kenai Peninsula; Western Prince William Sound</areaDesc>
<polygon>60.46,-149.82 60.4,-150.11 60.38,-150.31 60.4,-150.48 60.45,-150.54 60.48,-150.51 60.47,-150.44 60.43,-150.28 60.49,-150.16 60.5,-149.75 60.43,-149.61 60.42,-149.39 60.37,-149.32 60.29,-149.3 60.32,-149.25 60.29,-149.11 60.26,-149.38 60.36,-149.39 60.37,-149.42 60.37,-149.64 60.46,-149.82</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002063</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002122</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ125</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>