<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:10:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MN12641E965FE8.WinterStormWatch.12641EE16EC0MN.MPXWSWMPX.9f6e35b1954caf14f0da948db2048d7c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-19T14:10:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Goodhue (Minnesota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-21T12:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-24T06:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Minneapolis (Southern Minnesota)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Watch issued December 19 at 2:10PM CST until December 24 at 6:00AM CST by NWS Minneapolis</headline>
<description>...BLIZZARD CONDITIONS AND DANGEROUSLY COLD AIR LIKELY LATER THIS
WEEK...
...TRAVEL THURSDAY THROUGH FRIDAY NIGHT COULD BE IMPOSSIBLE AND
LIFE-THREATENING...
.Snow will overspread the region Wednesday and bring several
inches of fluffy accumulation through early Thursday. Winds will
be relatively light Wednesday and Wednesday evening. Then, strong
northwest winds gusting as high as 55 mph and dangerously cold air
will surge in Thursday through Saturday morning. Whiteout
conditions are expected during that time with travel becoming very
difficult or impossible. This event could be life-threatening if
you are stranded with wind chills in the 30 below to 45 below zero
range. Travel plans for late this week should be adjusted now. In
addition, heavy snow remaining on trees from the last storm and
strong winds arriving could result in tree damage and power
outages as temperatures drop below zero.
A Winter Storm Watch is in effect from Wednesday through late
Friday night for all of central and southern Minnesota and west
central Wisconsin. A Wind Chill Watch is in effect Thursday
through Saturday morning for southern and western Minnesota.
...WINTER STORM WATCH IN EFFECT FROM WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH
LATE FRIDAY NIGHT...
* WHAT...Blizzard conditions possible. Total snow accumulations of
5 to 10 inches possible. Winds could gust as high as 50 mph.
* WHERE...Portions of southeast Minnesota and northwest and west
central Wisconsin.
* WHEN...From Wednesday afternoon through late Friday night.
* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult or impossible.
Widespread blowing snow could significantly reduce visibility.
Gusty winds could bring down tree branches. The cold wind
chills as low as 30 below zero could cause frostbite on exposed
skin in as little as 30 minutes.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...This could be a life-threatening situation
if you get stranded traveling late this week. Consider adjusting
any travel plans now.</description>
<instruction>Prepare for possible blizzard conditions. Continue to monitor the
latest forecasts for updates on this situation.
Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ078-WIZ014>016-023>028</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KMPX.WS.A.0006.221221T1800Z-221224T1200Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Goodhue</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ078</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>