<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 19 Dec 2022 02:06:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MS12641E9573F8.SpecialWeatherStatement.12641E95AA44MS.LIXSPSLIX.da1727d12480e388f516d90bd247eccb</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-19T08:06:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson (Mississippi) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-18T19:50:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-19T09:45:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS New Orleans (Southeastern Louisiana)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 19 at 8:06AM CST  by NWS New Orleans</headline>
<description>...Potent Arctic Airmass for the Gulf South Still on Track for
Thursday Night and Impacting the Region Through Christmas Day with
Multiple Hazards Expected and Major Impacts Likely...
An extremely cold airmass is expected to surge towards the Gulf
coast Thursday and Thursday Night and bring a multitude of
hazardous conditions to the area. Hard Freeze, very strong winds,
and dangerous Wind Chill conditions would begin as early as late
Thursday night and we will continue to deal with the Arctic air
through Christmas Day. Now is the time to start taking measures to
protect your family, pets, friends, property, and yourself from
the likelihood of extreme and prolonged freezing conditions for
southern Mississippi and southeast Louisiana.
What will be the impacts:
- Extreme cold
- Very strong and possibly damaging wind gusts
- Dangerous wind chills
- Hazardous Driving conditions due to winds
An Arctic airmass surging south out of Canada and across the
central United States will quickly move into the Lower Mississippi
Valley Thursday night. The cold front is expected to move into
southwestern Mississippi and Southeast Louisiana during the
evening hours with temperatures dropping 20 to 30 degrees or more
in only a few hours. Temperatures will continue to plummet through
the early morning hours with almost the entire area below
freezing around sunrise. Not only will the temperatures plunge
but this will be accompanied by very strong winds and wind chill
readings in the teens to single digits are now EXPECTED! There is
even an outside chance of a few locations experiencing a wind
chill below zero! The wind chill has no impact on pipes but for
people and pets the rapidly moving air speeds up the heat loss
over our bodies and can quickly lead to hypothermia. As for pipes,
plants, and property, temperatures will struggle to get above
freezing, if they even do Friday, and there is a chance that many
locations could be below freezing for 24 to possibly even more
than 36 hours. And even if temperatures climb above freezing
Friday or in southwestern Mississippi and the adjacent Louisiana
parishes` case Saturday, they will only be above 32 for a very
short time. Not until Christmas Day does it looks like we will
comfortably get above 32 degrees for much of the area and for
more than a few hours.
We know many of you are thinking at least in the back of your head
about winter precip. This is NOT a Winter Storm, it is strictly an
Arctic Airmass and ALL of the impacts will be dealt by the
temperatures and wind. That said there is a small chance of
flurries at best right now on the very back end rain associated
with the cold front Thursday night but this will lead to ZERO
impacts. Do not, again do not concern yourself with flurries.
Here is the latest forecast for Friday, Saturday, and Sunday
referencing highs, lows, and minimum apparent temperature (Wind
Chill).
Morning   Afternoon   Minimum
Low       High        Wind Chill
McComb
Friday     15        29          0
Saturday   13        34          3
Sunday     18        40          11
Baton Rouge
Friday     20        34          7
Saturday   17        38          9
Sunday     21        44          17
Slidell
Friday     22        37          10
Saturday   16        39          8
Sunday     20        44          16
Poplarville
Friday     18        32          6
Saturday   16        36          8
Sunday     20        41          14
New Orleans
Friday    26        35          13
Saturday  24        38          15
Sunday    28        41          22
Houma
Friday    24        37          11
Saturday  20        39          11
Sunday    24        43          18
Gulfport
Friday    25        39          14
Saturday  19        41          9
Sunday    23        45          16
Pascagoula
Friday    24        39          13
Saturday  16        39           6
Sunday    20        43          13
Yes that is a forecast wind chill of ZERO at McComb and actually
have a -2 wind chill currently forecast for Woodville, MS Friday
morning.
The other high impact from the weather will be the winds.
Immediately behind the cold front very strong winds out of the
north-northwest will develop and continue to strengthen through
the overnight hours and remain quite strong through the day.
Conditions will be quite favorable for winds to gust to and likely
higher than 40 mph and this will have a good bit of impact on
travel, especially for high profile vehicles along our major east
to west highways where the winds will almost be perpendicular to
the direction you are traveling. Any elevated roadways (which
there are a lot of) especially the Mississippi River and Pearl
River bridges along with the Causeway and Twin Span will be
dealing with very hazardous winds. If that wasn`t enough there
will likely be quite a bit of people traveling for the Christmas
holidays only leading to greater congestion on the roads with
these strong winds. Please plan accordingly and allow for extra
time especially if you travel across any roads that may close due
to high winds like the Causeway.
Also don`t get caught one the roads by traffic or an accident and
stuck in the very cold air. With most people not use to packing
for cold weather while making even a small trip down I-10 it would
be a great idea to pack an emergency kit with a way to keep warm
just in case. You can never be too careful especially when dealing
with conditions we are just not use to down here.
Some historical information to relate to prior to our cold event.
Every weather event is different and they should all be treated
as such but for at least some modern reference here are a few
Arctic events to relate to; February 2nd through 5th 1996, January
8th through 11th, 2010, and more recently is February 15th
through 17th 2021. However, this airmass appears to be more potent
than the 2010 and 2021 events. Also we did not compare this to
the Jan 17th and 18th Winter event; yes it was cold and it appears
that we even had one Co-Op site record 9 degrees for a low on the
17th, Poplarville Exp Station. This station has a continuous data
history back 1919 and partial data back to 1896. This was part of
a major winter storms for the deep south that brought snow and
ice across the region and closed I-10 from Lafayette to Slidell,
LA and out airmass late this week will not be a winter storm, just
a very cold airmass.
As for reference to the Holiday time frame, surprisingly there
are 2 of the more historic events and not just for our area that
occurred during this time; 1983 December 23rd through 26th and
1989 December 22nd through 25th events. These two are quite
historic events but at this time we are not anticipating testing
those 2 Arctic events. The 1989 Arctic airmass still holds
numerous records across a good portion of the US including here
where single digits were recorded in more than just a few places.
We would have to go back to 1899 to see temperatures recorded
lower than 1989 in much of the area over a multi day stretch. 1985
saw another historic cold front for our area which did set some
all time record lows but it was a short lived airmass with highs
back in the 50s the next day.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>LAZ034>037-039-046>048-056>060-064>071-076>090-MSZ068>071-077-080>082</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028059</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028157</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ082</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>