<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 19 Dec 2021 03:09:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AK1261CA89B834.SpecialWeatherStatement.1261CA96FB20AK.AFCSPSAER.56b789da1ef6b823eaca56130b2e68a8</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2021-12-19T06:09:00-09:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Anchorage; Matanuska Valley; Susitna Valley; Western Kenai Peninsula (Alaska) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2021-12-19T06:09:00-09:00</effective>
<expires>2021-12-19T17:00:00-09:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Anchorage (Southern Alaska - Anchorage)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 19 at 6:09AM AKST  by NWS Anchorage</headline>
<description>...WINTER STORM TO IMPACT WESTERN KENAI PENINSULA, ANCHORAGE, AND
THE MAT-SU VALLEYS MONDAY...
Snow is expected to develop Monday morning from the Western Kenai
Peninsula north to the Mat-Su Valleys. The snow is expected to
start off as west snow before transitioning to a drier, more
powdery snow by Monday afternoon or evening. Snowfall rates are
also expected to increase late Monday, especially for east
Anchorage and along the Glenn Highway from Palmer to Anchorage as
a colder northwesterly flow develops. Snowfall amounts of 1 to 3
inches is possible for the Western Kenai Peninsula; 2 to 4 inches
are possible for the Susitna Valley, mainly along the Parks
Highway from Talkeetna south; and 4 to 8 inches are possible for
the Anchorage Bowl and Matanuska Valley. The highest snowfall
totals are expected from Palmer south along the Glenn Highway to
east Anchorage and the Anchorage Hillside.
This weather system will also usher in warmer air aloft over Cook
Inlet Monday morning with the potential for the onset of
precipitation to be in the form of a wintry mix of
snow/sleet/freezing rain for portions of the Western Kenai
Peninsula. Any wintry mix is expected to quickly change to all
snow by mid morning Monday. Farther south, warmer air near the
surface will move over the Southern Cook Inlet and into Kachemak
Bay, allowing a transition to rain for Homer.
Snow may linger along upslope locations of the Chugach and Kenai
Mountains through early Tuesday morning before tapering off as
this system moves east.
There is still some uncertainty with the exact details of this
system, so we will be closely monitoring this system as it
develops.
This system may impact travel across the area to start the week.
For the latest informations go to www.weather.gov/anchorage.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ101-111-121-145</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Anchorage; Matanuska Valley; Susitna Valley; Western Kenai Peninsula</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002122</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002170</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ145</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>