<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 18 Sep 2022 03:07:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-PR12640CA2E16C.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640CA41D0CPR.JSJHLSSJU.8d67727360d22566fc42a2f36d69cdf9</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-18T00:07:00-03:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Central Interior; Culebra; Eastern Interior; Mayaguez and Vicinity; North Central; Northeast; Northwest; Ponce and Vicinity; San Juan and Vicinity; Southeast; Southwest; Vieques; Western Interior (Puerto Rico) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-17T23:35:00-03:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-18T08:15:00-03:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS San Juan (San Juan, Puerto Rico)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 18 at 12:07AM ADT  by NWS San Juan</headline>
<description>This product covers Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands
**LIFE-THREATENING FLOODING AND MUDSLIDES POSSIBLE ACROSS PUERTO RICO
FROM FIONA DURING THE NEXT SEVERAL DAYS**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Hurricane Warning is in effect for Central Interior, Culebra,
Eastern Interior, Mayaguez and Vicinity, North Central,
Northeast, Northwest, Ponce and Vicinity, San Juan and
Vicinity, Southeast, Southwest, Vieques, and Western Interior
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Hurricane Watch are in effect for
St Croix and St.Thomas...St. John...and Adjacent Islands
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 150 miles southeast of Ponce PR or about 80 miles south
of Saint Croix VI
- 16.6N 64.9W
- Storm Intensity 60 mph
- Movement West-northwest or 285 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Fiona is currently located 80 miles southeast of St.
Croix and 150 miles southeast of Ponce, at 16.6 North, 64.9 West. The
forecast is now showing a hurricane crossing from southwestern to
northwestern Puerto Rico tomorrow. Therefore, a Hurricane Warning is in
effect for Puerto Rico, as well as for the local waters. For the U.S.
Virgin Islands, a Tropical Storm Warning and a Hurricane Watch are in
effect. Hurricane conditions are likely for portions of Puerto Rico as
well as for the local waters. Maximum sustained winds are expected to
be as high as near 75 mph with higher gusts up to 90 mph over Puerto
Rico.
The main hazard remains the flooding rainfall that it will bring.
Rainfall totals in southern Puerto Rico are forecast to be 12 to
16 inches, and locally up to 20 inches. Elsewhere, rainfall amounts of
5 to 10 inches are expected, with locally higher amounts. This amount
of rainfall will result in life-threatening flash and urban flooding,
as well as mudslides or rockfalls and river flooding. The greatest
threat for these dangerous flooding conditions is expected between
tonight and Monday.
Deteriorating marine and coastal conditions are also anticipated. Seas
will build to around 18 feet, lasting through the weekend. Winds over
the seas will be around 65 knots with gusts to 85 knots.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts, especially across eastern and southern Puerto
Rico. Potential impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, arroyos, and
ditches may become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas,
destructive runoff may run quickly down valleys while
increasing susceptibility to rockslides and mudslides. Flood
control systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across the rest of the region.
* WIND:
Protect against life-threatening wind having possible extensive
impacts across Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential
impacts include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
* SURGE:
Protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts, mostly along the southern coast of Puerto Rico. Potential
impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of near-shore roads and parking lots become overspread
with surge water. Driving conditions dangerous in places where
surge water covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential impacts
include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
- If you are exceptionally vulnerable to wind or water hazards from
tropical systems, consider voluntary evacuation, especially if being
officially recommended. Relocate to a predetermined shelter or safe
destination.
- If evacuating away from the area or relocating to a nearby shelter,
leave early before weather conditions become hazardous.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to bring to completion all preparations to protect
life and property in accordance with your emergency plan.
Outside preparations should be wrapped up as soon as possible before
weather conditions completely deteriorate. Any remaining evacuations
and relocations should be expedited before the onset of tropical
storm force wind.
If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible. If
heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or own a
pet. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.
Check the latest weather forecast before departing.
Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.
Check-in with your emergency points of contact among family, friends,
and workmates. Inform them of your status and well-being. Let them
know how you intend to ride out the storm and when you plan to
check-in again.
Keep cell phones well charged and handy. Also, cell phone chargers
for automobiles can be helpful after the storm. Locate your chargers
and keep them with your cell phone.
If relocating to a nearby shelter or to the home of a family member
or friend, drive with extra caution, especially on secondary roads.
Remember, many bridges and causeways will be closed once higher winds
arrive. Also, if you encounter water covering the road, seek an
alternate route. Always obey official road signs for closures and
detours.
If you are a visitor and still in the area, listen for the name of
the city or town in which you are staying within local news updates.
Be sure you know the name of the county or parish in which it
resides. Pay attention for instructions from local authorities.
Closely monitor NOAA Weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes to
the forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in San Juan PR around 2 AM AST, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ001>013-VIZ001-002</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Central Interior; Culebra; Eastern Interior; Mayaguez and Vicinity; North Central; Northeast; Northwest; Ponce and Vicinity; San Juan and Vicinity; Southeast; Southwest; Vieques; Western Interior</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072054</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072059</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072063</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072083</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072105</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072115</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072119</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072123</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072125</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072129</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072131</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072135</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072137</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072139</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072143</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072145</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072151</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>072153</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ004</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ006</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ008</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ012</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ013</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>