<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:10:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D1FB3B8.StormSurgeWarning.12640D2C86ECFL.TBWTCVTBW.85efeab29d091d8f10660652ff828c23</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-26T17:10:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Charlotte (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Storm Surge Warning</event>
<urgency></urgency>
<severity></severity>
<certainty></certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-26T17:10:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-27T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Tampa Bay (West Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Storm Surge Warning issued September 26 at 5:10PM EDT until further notice by NWS Tampa Bay</headline>
<description>...STORM SURGE WARNING IN EFFECT...
...TROPICAL STORM WARNING IN EFFECT...
...HURRICANE WATCH IN EFFECT...
A Hurricane Watch means hurricane-force winds are possible somewhere
within this area within the next 48 hours
A Storm Surge Warning means there is a danger of life-threatening
inundation, from rising water moving inland from the coastline,
somewhere within this area within the next 36 hours
A Tropical Storm Warning means tropical storm-force winds are
expected somewhere within this area within the next 36 hours
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Port Charlotte
- Punta Gorda
- Charlotte harbor
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Tropical Storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 40-50 mph with gusts to 85 mph
- Window for Tropical Storm force winds: Tuesday evening
until early Friday morning
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind
greater than 110 mph
- The wind threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for extreme wind of equivalent CAT 3 hurricane
force or higher.
- PREPARE: Remaining efforts to protect life and property
should be urgently completed. Prepare for catastrophic wind
damage.
- ACT: Move to safe shelter before the wind becomes hazardous.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Devastating to Catastrophic
- Structural damage to sturdy buildings, some with complete
roof and wall failures. Complete destruction of mobile
homes. Damage greatly accentuated by large airborne
projectiles. Locations may be uninhabitable for weeks or
months.
- Numerous large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences
and roadway signs blown over.
- Many roads impassable from large debris, and more within
urban or heavily wooded places. Many bridges, causeways,
and access routes impassable.
- Widespread power and communications outages.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Life-threatening storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 5-8 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: Begins early Wednesday morning
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 6 feet above ground
- The storm surge threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for life-threatening storm surge flooding of
greater than 6 feet above ground.
- PREPARE: Evacuation efforts should soon be brought to
completion before driving conditions become unsafe.
- ACT: Leave immediately if evacuation orders are given for
your area to avoid being cut off from emergency services or
needlessly risk lives.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Extensive
- Large areas of deep inundation with storm surge flooding
accentuated by battering waves. Structural damage to
buildings, with several washing away. Damage compounded by
floating debris. Locations may be uninhabitable for an
extended period.
- Large sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary
roads washed out or severely flooded. Flood control systems
and barriers may become stressed.
- Severe beach erosion with significant dune loss.
- Major damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers. Many
small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages with some lifted onshore and
stranded.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Flood Watch is in effect
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: Additional 3-6 inches, with locally
higher amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
moderate flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
moderate flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues
are possible.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action may result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations
and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with
swifter currents and overspill their banks in a few places,
especially in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams,
creeks, canals, and ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken
foundations. Several places may experience expanded areas
of rapid inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and
poor drainage areas. Some streets and parking lots take on
moving water as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
Driving conditions become hazardous. Some road and bridge
closures.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is somewhat favorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for a few
tornadoes
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for a
few tornadoes.
- PREPARE: If your shelter is particularly vulnerable to
tornadoes, prepare to relocate to safe shelter before
hazardous weather arrives.
- ACT: If a tornado warning is issued, be ready to shelter
quickly.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the
execution of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with
power and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings,
chimneys toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or
overturned, large tree tops and branches snapped off,
shallow-rooted trees knocked over, moving vehicles blown
off roads, and boats pulled from moorings.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- https://www.weather.gov/tbw</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ162</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KTBW.SS.W.1009.220926T2110Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Charlotte</areaDesc>
<polygon>26.98,-81.95 26.77,-81.93 26.77,-82.06 26.77,-82.18 26.77,-82.21 26.78,-82.22 26.79,-82.27 26.8,-82.28 26.83,-82.29 26.83,-82.3 26.9,-82.35 26.95,-82.38 26.95,-82.26 27,-82.25 27,-82.26 27.03,-82.26 27.03,-82.06 27.03,-81.99 27.03,-81.99 27.04,-81.97 26.98,-81.95 26.98,-81.95</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ162</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>