<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:28:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D1FBAC0.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D2D2908FL.MLBHLSMLB.2a72fe5429ded96993bea3bfb693c3ca</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-26T17:28:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-26T17:07:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-27T05:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 26 at 5:28PM EDT  by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>This product covers East Central Florida
**TROPICAL STORM WATCHES IN EFFECT FOR ALL OF EAST CENTRAL FLORIDA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch has been issued for Coastal Indian
River, Coastal Martin, Coastal Saint Lucie, Coastal Volusia,
Inland Indian River, Inland Martin, Inland Northern Brevard,
Inland Saint Lucie, Inland Southern Brevard, Inland Volusia,
Mainland Northern Brevard, Mainland Southern Brevard, Northern
Brevard Barrier Islands, and Southern Brevard Barrier Islands
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Indian River,
Coastal Martin, Coastal Saint Lucie, Coastal Volusia, Inland
Indian River, Inland Martin, Inland Northern Brevard, Inland
Saint Lucie, Inland Southern Brevard, Inland Volusia, Mainland
Northern Brevard, Mainland Southern Brevard, Northern Brevard
Barrier Islands, Northern Lake, Okeechobee, Orange, Osceola,
Seminole, Southern Brevard Barrier Islands, and Southern Lake
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 590 miles south of Leesburg FL or about 580 miles
south-southwest of Orlando FL
- 20.3N 83.2W
- Storm Intensity 100 mph
- Movement North-northwest or 330 degrees at 13 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Hurricane Ian was located about 590 miles south of Leesburg at 5 pm
with 100 mph winds and continues to strengthen while moving Northwest at
13 mph. Ian is forecast to cross the westernmost portion of Cuba as a
major hurricane early Tuesday and enter the southeast Gulf of Mexico
and continue strengthening through Tuesday afternoon. Ian is then
forecast to track north northeast offshore the southwest Florida coast
on Wednesday and approach the west central Florida coast Wednesday
night and Thursday while slowing in forward speed.
With Ians approach, tropical storm conditions will develop across east
central Florida from north to south on Wednesday into Wednesday night.
A Tropical Storm Watch is now in effect for all east central Florida
counties. Flooding impacts may begin as early as Tuesday with wind
impacts as early as Wednesday across east central Florida.
Significant to extensive wind impacts are expected with the onset of
tropical storm wind gusts associated with the outer bands of Ian
Wednesday and deteoriating wind conditions expected Wednesday night
into Thursday. Wind impacts may linger into Thursday night and early
Friday across mainly northern portions of east central Florida from
Orlando and Cape Canaveral northward as Ian moves northward late this
week.
Locally heavy rainfall amounts are expected Tuesday through Thursday
night across east central Florida. Storm total rainfall amounts may
reach 5 to 10 inches with some localized spots reaching 12 inches. A
Flood Watch is in effect across all of east central Florida through
late Thursday night. Additional areal and river flooding is likely
across portions of east central Florida that receive the heaviest
rainfall.
The environment will also be increasingly favorable for the development
of isolated tornadoes across east central Florida Tuesday through mid
week.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Prepare for life-threatening wind having possible extensive impacts
across Lake County. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Also, prepare for dangerous wind having possible significant impacts
across the remainder of east central Florida.
* SURGE:
Prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
along the east central Florida Atlantic coast and intracoastal waters
shorelines. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of near-shore roads and parking lots become overspread
with surge water. Driving conditions dangerous in places where
surge water covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across east central Florida. Potential
impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may
become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas, destructive runoff
may run quickly down valleys while increasing susceptibility to
rockslides and mudslides. Flood control systems and barriers
may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
East Central Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions, including
possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so immediately.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, plan to move to safe shelter.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low-lying or poor
drainage area, in a valley, or near an already swollen river, plan to
move to safe shelter on higher ground.
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.
When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.
There is a threat from tornadoes with this storm. Have multiple ways
to receive Tornado Warnings. Be ready to shelter quickly.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 1130 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041-044>046-053-058-141-144-154-159-164-247-254-259-264-347-447-547-647-747</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ058</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ144</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ159</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ164</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ247</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ254</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ259</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ347</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ447</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ547</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ647</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ747</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>