<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 27 Sep 2022 03:09:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D2C3674.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D2D714CFL.TAEHLSTAE.c5dec4a8ed44c19953a4c203f4905373</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-26T23:09:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Dixie; Coastal Franklin; Coastal Gulf; Coastal Jefferson; Coastal Taylor; Coastal Wakulla; Inland Franklin (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-26T10:10:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-27T07:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Tallahassee (the Florida Peninsula)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 26 at 11:09PM EDT  by NWS Tallahassee</headline>
<description>This product covers eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend, southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia
**IAN EXPECTED TO BECOME A MAJOR HURRICANE OVERNIGHT OR EARLY
TUESDAY**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Watch and Tropical Storm Watch are in effect for
Coastal Dixie and Coastal Taylor
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Franklin,
Coastal Jefferson, and Coastal Wakulla
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 620 miles south-southeast of Panama City or about 590
miles south of Apalachicola
- 21.3N 83.4W
- Storm Intensity 105 mph
- Movement North-northwest or 340 degrees at 13 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
At 11pm EDT Hurricane Ian remains just south of the western tip of
Cuba. Ian is still forecast to strengthen into a Category 4 hurricane
over the eastern Gulf of Mexico before beginning to weaken as it
approaches the northeast Gulf. Ian is currently forecast to pass near
the Tampa Bay area before continuing to the north- northeast. There
remains a lot of uncertainty with the forecast of Ian beyond the next
couple of days. We will have a better idea of specific impacts once
the track and intensity forecasts become more clear.
The Tropical Storm Watch and Storm Surge Watch remain unchanged from
the last advisory. Tropical Storm watches are in effect for all
coastal zones from Indian Pass east towards the Suwanee River. A Storm
Surge watch is also in effect from the Aucilla River east to the
Suwanee River.
Forecast uncertainty still remains high with Ian, but we will be able
to provide additional details on Ian over the next 24 hours.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Prepare for life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across Apalachee Bay Coast from Aucilla River east towards
the Suwanee River. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across the rest of the Apalachee Bay from the Aucilla River
west to Indian Pass.
* WIND:
Prepare for life-threatening wind having possible extensive impacts
across the Florida Big Bend. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Also, prepare for dangerous wind having possible limited to
significant impacts elsewhere across southwest Georgia.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across the southeast Florida Big Bend. Potential
impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, and ditches may become
dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and barriers may become
stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible limited to
significant impacts across the rest of the Florida Big Bend.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
the southeast Florida Big Bend. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
Elsewhere across eastern Florida panhandle, Florida Big Bend,
southeastern Alabama and southwestern Georgia, little to no impact is
anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and emergency supplies
kit and take necessary actions to protect your family and secure your
home or business.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, plan to move to safe shelter.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the Gulf of Mexico or a large inland lake, in a low-lying or
poor drainage area, or near an already swollen river, plan to move to
safe shelter on higher ground.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tallahassee FL around 5 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ015-114-115-118-127-128-134</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Dixie; Coastal Franklin; Coastal Gulf; Coastal Jefferson; Coastal Taylor; Coastal Wakulla; Inland Franklin</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012123</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012129</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ114</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ115</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ118</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ128</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ134</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>