<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:18:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D1DE218.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D1F1F48FL.KEYHLSKEY.d9ed7063537b4589b0a05a2f58d3c0fd</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-26T05:18:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Monroe Lower Keys; Monroe Middle Keys; Monroe Upper Keys (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-26T04:58:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-26T13:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Key West (Key West - The Florida Keys)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 26 at 5:18AM EDT  by NWS Key West</headline>
<description>This product covers the Florida Keys
**Ian becomes a hurricane over the northwestern Caribbean Sea**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Monroe Lower Keys
- A Storm Surge Watch is in effect for Monroe Middle Keys and
Monroe Upper Keys
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 440 miles south of Key West FL
- 18.2N 82.0W
- Storm Intensity 75 mph
- Movement Northwest or 325 degrees at 14 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
At 500 AM EDT, the center of Hurricane Ian was located over the warm
and deep waters of the Western Caribbean, to the southwest of the
Cayman Islands. Ian is moving toward the northwest, and a turn to the
north-northwest is expected later today, followed by a northward motion
on Tuesday with a slightly slower forward speed. On the forecast
track, the center of Ian is expected to pass near or to the west of the
Cayman Islands today, and near or over western Cuba tonight and early
Tuesday. Ian will then emerge over the southeastern Gulf of Mexico on
Tuesday, likely as a major hurricane, and pass west of the Florida Keys
Tuesday afternoon and Tuesday night.
Although the forecast calls for a smooth curving turn to the north,
tiny wobbles, interactions with land, and fluctuations in intensity
will result in subtle shifts in the forecast track over the next
48 hours. Nevertheless, Ian will pass west of the Florida Keys Tuesday
afternoon and Tuesday night as a major hurricane with a large wind
field extending well to the east of the center of circulation. Threats
will include damaging wind gusts from fast moving squalls, storm surge
flooding of 2 to 4 feet above normal high tides, 4 to 6 inches of
rainfall causing localized freshwater flooding, and isolated
tornadoes.
Saltwater flooding of low elevation streets and lots is expected to
continue today and tonight prior to the passage of Ian. Boaters can
expect less clearance under fixed bridges. Motorists should remember
that persistent puddles around the times of high tide are almost
certain to contain a mix of saltwater.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Prepare for dangerous winds having possible significant impacts
across the Lower Keys. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with minor
damage to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few
buildings may experience window, door, and garage door
failures. Mobile homes damaged, especially if unanchored.
Unsecured lightweight objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Isolated power and communications outages possible.
* SURGE:
Protect against hazardous storm surge having possible significant
impacts across the Florida Keys. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of secondary roads become weakened or washed out,
especially in usually vulnerable low spots.
- Major beach erosion.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for rainfall flooding having possible significant impacts
across the Florida Keys. Potential impacts include:
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rainfall
flooding at low-lying spots, and poor drainage areas. Some
streets and parking lots take on moving water as storm drains
and retention ponds overflow. Some secondary road closures due
to freshwater flooding.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
the Florida Keys. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, mobile
homes damaged, large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow
- rooted trees knocked over, and small boats pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging wind
gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the center of
the storm.
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.
When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.
If staying at a hotel, ask the management staff about their onsite
disaster plan. Listen for evacuation orders, especially pertaining to
area visitors.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.
There is a threat from tornadoes with this storm. Have multiple ways
to receive Tornado Warnings. Be ready to shelter quickly.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For Monroe County Emergency Management Information, Hurricane
Preparedness Information, Evacuation Information, and shelter
information see monroecountyem.com/JIC
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
- For Florida Division of Emergency Management information, see
floridadisaster.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Key West FL around 12 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ076>078</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Monroe Lower Keys; Monroe Middle Keys; Monroe Upper Keys</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ076</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ078</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>