<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:07:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D1FB28C.TropicalStormWatch.12640D2C86ECFL.JAXTCVJAX.c175ec9118bc208708a3f026d938b522</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-26T17:07:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for South Central Duval (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>TRA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-26T17:07:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-27T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Jacksonville (Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued September 26 at 5:07PM EDT until further notice by NWS Jacksonville</headline>
<description>...STORM SURGE WATCH IN EFFECT...
...TROPICAL STORM WATCH IN EFFECT...
A Storm Surge Watch means life-threatening inundation, from rising
water moving inland from the coastline, is possible somewhere within
this area within the next 48 hours
A Tropical Storm Watch means tropical storm-force winds are possible
somewhere within this area within the next 48 hours
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Ortega
- Riverside
- San Marco
- Mandarin
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Tropical Storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 40-50 mph with gusts to 85 mph
- Window for Tropical Storm force winds: Wednesday evening
until Friday evening
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Efforts to protect property should now be
underway. Prepare for limited wind damage.
- ACT: Act now to complete preparations before the wind
becomes hazardous.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees
are shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown
over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within
urban or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving
conditions on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Life-threatening storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 2-4 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: Wednesday morning until Friday morning
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 3 feet above ground
- PLAN: Plan for life-threatening storm surge flooding of
greater than 3 feet above ground.
- PREPARE: Storm surge flooding preparations should be
underway. Assemble disaster supplies and know your
evacuation route.
- ACT: Leave if evacuation orders are given for your area.
Failure to heed evacuation orders may result in the loss of
your life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- This statement pertains to storm surge forecasts up to 6
feet Above Ground Level (AGL) for portions of South-Central
Duval County along and near the St Johns River.
- Major flooding will occur along the banks of the St Johns,
Cedar and Ortega Rivers. In some cases, several blocks
landward from these rivers may flood. Many ground level
homes will flood along the rivers and creeks. These rivers
will take several days to drain both trapped tides and
rainfall flooding, which consequently will prolong river
flooding for many days.
- People in some areas may require rescue if they do not heed
advice to evacuate prior to the storm. If you have flooded
before, you WILL flood again. Other areas which have not
flooded could flood during this event.
- San Marco and Southbank: Life-threatening flooding is
expected in Southampton, Southbank and San Marco. The
deepest flood water of 6 feet in depth is expected near the
Anderson Cancer Center along Nira Street and Palm Way.
Baptist and Wolfson`s Children`s Hospitals will be cut off
by up to 3 feet of flooding. Flood water near Baptist
Hospital could be up to 6 feet in depth. Flooding on
Riverplace Blvd will be up to 5 feet in depth.. Flood water
up to 4 feet in depth is expected near the Duval County
Public Schools Administrative Building, and large breaking
river waves will impact the structure.
- Riverside: Riverside can expect flooding up to 6 feet above
ground level near the river with river flood water
extending inland to Park Street and Osceola Street.
Flooding on Riverside Drive will be up to 6 feet above
ground level. St Vincent`s Hospital will be surrounded by
water up to 6 feet in depth with up to 2 feet of water
inside the ground floor. Life-threatening flooding will
occur along the Willow Branch inland to Sydney Street.
- Lakeshore: Major flooding will occur in Lakeshore along the
banks of the Fishweir Creek and Ortega River. Major
flooding will occur in a low area that extends from the
Roosevelt Mall to Big Fishweir Creek which includes areas
along Mayview Road, Woodmere Drive, Oleander Place,
Marquette Street, McIntosh Place, Shirley Ave, Lexington
Ave, San Juan Ave, Euclid Street, Palmer Ave, Appleton Ave
and Colonial Ave.
- Ortega and Ortega Forest: Areas near the Ortega River will
experience major flooding. The most vulnerable locations
include Cates Ave, Godwin Ave, Sussex Ave, Blount Ave,
Water Oak Lane, all of Long Bow Road, Beefeaters Road,
Charlemagne Road and Ortega Forest Drive.
- Pirate`s Cove and Venetia: Major, life-threatening flooding
will occur in most areas with up to 6 feet of water above
ground in the deepest locations. Pirates Cove Road, Yacht
Club Road, Venetia Blvd, DeMedici Ave, Da Vinci Ave and
Lega Blvd will all experience flood water inundation of up
to 6 feet. Fire Station 23 will experience 3 to 4 feet of
flooding inside the building.
- Cedar River: Major river flooding will occur along the
banks of the Cedar River past San Juan Ave and Hyde Park to
Normandy Blvd. Flooding of the Riverside Apartments along
the Willis Branch, Greyfriar Lane, and Watergate Lane is
expected with low-lying units flooded to several feet in
depth. Many low-lying structures along the river will be
flooded.
- San Jose to Mandarin: Some flooding of neighborhoods along
the creeks draining into the St Johns river, including
Goodbys Creek, can be expected in Lakewood, San Jose
Forest, San Jose, Beauclerc, and Mandarin. Low-lying
locations along Julington Creek and its many tributaries
can be expected.
- This is a summary of surge impacts. Every neighborhood that
will experience flooding is not mentioned. Please heed the
advice of local Emergency Management.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: 8-12 inches, with locally higher
amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for major
flooding rain
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
major flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues are
likely.
- PREPARE: Strongly consider protective actions, especially
if you are in an area vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action will likely result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Extensive
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches
may become dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and
barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or
washed away. Many places where flood waters may cover
escape routes. Streets and parking lots become rivers of
moving water with underpasses submerged. Driving conditions
become dangerous. Many road and bridge closures with some
weakened or washed out.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is somewhat favorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for a few
tornadoes
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for a
few tornadoes.
- PREPARE: If your shelter is particularly vulnerable to
tornadoes, prepare to relocate to safe shelter before
hazardous weather arrives.
- ACT: If a tornado warning is issued, be ready to shelter
quickly.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the
execution of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with
power and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings,
chimneys toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or
overturned, large tree tops and branches snapped off,
shallow-rooted trees knocked over, moving vehicles blown
off roads, and small boats pulled from moorings.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- Family Emergency Plans (FEMA): http://ready.gov/hurricanes
- Local weather conditions and forecasts: http://www.weather.gov/jax/</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ325</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KJAX.SS.A.1009.220926T2107Z-000000T0000Z/
/O.NEW.KJAX.TR.A.1009.220926T2107Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>South Central Duval</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ325</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>