<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 27 May 2022 03:51:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CO1263F556979C.SpecialWeatherStatement.1263F5637C00CO.PUBSPSPUB.89f07f3f40ef625ad2b0d8f743993383</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-05-27T09:51:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Colorado Springs Vicinity, Southern El Paso County, Rampart Range Below 7400 Ft; Crowley County; Eastern Kiowa County; Eastern Las Animas County; La Junta Vicinity, Otero County; Lamar Vicinity, Prowers County; Las Animas Vicinity, Bent County; Northern El Paso County, Monument Ridge, Rampart Range Below 7500 Ft; Pueblo Vicinity, Pueblo County Below 6300 Feet; Springfield Vicinity, Baca County; Trinidad Vicinity, Western Las Animas County Below 7500 Ft; Walsenburg Vicinity, Upper Huerfano River Basin Below 7500 Ft; Western Kiowa County (Colorado) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-05-26T12:30:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-05-27T18:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Pueblo (Southeastern Colorado)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued May 27 at 9:51AM MDT  by NWS Pueblo</headline>
<description>...INCREASING FIRE-WEATHER RISK THROUGH THIS WEEKEND...
Across southeast Colorado, the fire-weather risk will increase in
many areas through this weekend.
Widely scattered thunderstorms are expected to form over the
eastern mountains this afternoon, and spread eastward across the
Interstate-25 corridor through this evening. This activity will
be capable of producing gusty and erratic winds, lightning, and
little to no precipitation. Lightning-induced ignitions, and
subsequent spread of fires from strong outflow winds, may be a
concern in areas where land-surface conditions are dry.
Then for this weekend, a passing weather system will bring strong
and gusty winds, along with very dry conditions, across the
Interstate-25 corridor and the plains. Critical meteorological
conditions are expected to develop in these areas, especially as
temperatures become hot and relative humidity values fall into the
single digits. These conditions are expected both Saturday and
Sunday.
However, many areas experienced appreciable amounts of precipitation
late last week, and this past weekend into Monday. For some
locations, this has resulted in unfavorable land-surface
conditions for fire spread. Regardless, the ongoing drought
conditions across the region will support favorable land-surface
conditions for fire spread in other areas, as well. Where these
drier land-surface conditions exist, the combination of strong
winds, low relative humidity, and hot temperatures this weekend
will have the potential to contribute to extreme fire behavior.
It is important to remain extremely cautious given these
conditions. Avoid burning or any outdoor activity that may
produce a spark and start a wildfire.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ084>089-093>099</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Colorado Springs Vicinity, Southern El Paso County, Rampart Range Below 7400 Ft; Crowley County; Eastern Kiowa County; Eastern Las Animas County; La Junta Vicinity, Otero County; Lamar Vicinity, Prowers County; Las Animas Vicinity, Bent County; Northern El Paso County, Monument Ridge, Rampart Range Below 7500 Ft; Pueblo Vicinity, Pueblo County Below 6300 Feet; Springfield Vicinity, Baca County; Trinidad Vicinity, Western Las Animas County Below 7500 Ft; Walsenburg Vicinity, Upper Huerfano River Basin Below 7500 Ft; Western Kiowa County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ084</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ086</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ088</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ094</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ096</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ098</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ099</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>