<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 27 May 2022 08:08:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC1263F5557560.FloodWarning.1263F5637C00NC.GSPFLSGSP.3b9d1f85d0068ba1543ce19359ec641c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-05-27T04:08:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Transylvania (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-05-27T09:34:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-05-27T20:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued May 27 at 4:08AM EDT until May 27 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT FRIDAY...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.
* WHERE...Transylvania County, North Carolina
* WHEN...Until 800 PM EDT Friday.
* IMPACTS...Minor flooding along the French Broad River from Rosman
to Brevard and along the Davidson River near Pisgah Forest, will
continue for at least the next several hours, impacting common,
flood-prone roadways, boat access areas, farmland, and other areas
adjacent to streams.  Floodwaters are currently impacting
residential areas adjacent to the French Broad River in Rosman.
Additional, nuisance flooding will continue to expand along the
Little River near Penrose as well through later this morning
before conditions stabilize and slowly start to improve Friday
afternoon.
* The French Broad River at Rosman exceeded the Minor Flood Stage of
9.0 feet at 1am this morning.  The current stage is 11.26 feet and
rising slowly.  The river is expected to continue to rise to near
11.5 feet over the next 1-2 hours before cresting.  Since no
additional rainfall is expected, confidence in this crest is
high.  Expect the river to fall back below Minor Flood Stage by
early this afternoon.  At these levels, floodwaters will be
approaching the crawl spaces of the homes along Depot St and may
begin inundating US 176 just downstream of the gauge site.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 358 AM EDT, Heavy rain has ended across Transylvania
County and high water and flooding conditions will gradually
improve later this morning into early this afternoon.  It
will take most of Friday for the larger streams to crest and
recede back below bankfull levels so this Flood Warning will
continue through Friday evening or until streams no longer
pose a flooding threat.  No additional rainfall is expected
for the next several days.
- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
Brevard, Rosman, Gorges State Park, Dupont State Forest,
Balsam Grove, Connestee, Wolf Mountain, Sapphire, Penrose,
Cedar Mountain, Little River In Transylvania County and North
Transylvania.</description>
<instruction>In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.
Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC175</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.W.0003.000000T0000Z-220530T0000Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Transylvania</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.29,-82.92 35.32,-82.83 35.42,-82.74 35.29,-82.61 35.26,-82.62 35.14,-82.58 35.12,-82.66 35.13,-82.68 35.1,-82.7 35.07,-82.76 35.07,-82.78 35.09,-82.78 35.03,-83.01 35.05,-83.06 35.08,-83.04 35.13,-82.98 35.16,-83 35.17,-82.98 35.19,-82.99 35.23,-82.93 35.29,-82.92</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037175</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC175</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>