<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.553f482d28c2b14f7d6f1d0d16fe325c7dd12d2b.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-10T10:45:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>ESF</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-10T10:45:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-10T10:45:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-10T18:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Anchorage AK</senderName>
        <headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued September 10 at 10:45AM AKDT by NWS Anchorage AK</headline>
        <description>ESFAFC

Multiple rounds of moderate to heavy rainfall are expected along the
Prince William Sound Coast through Saturday. This first round of
heavier rain will continue through today. A second round is then
expected tonight through early Saturday for eastern Prince William
Sound before slowly tapering off. Rain may persist through Saturday
for Western Prince William Sound.

Rainfall

* Western Prince William Sound, including Portage and Whittier: 2 to
4 inches of rain is expected through this evening. Steady rain may
taper off for a time tonight into early Thursday. However, an
additional 2 to 4 inches of rain is possible Thursday through
Saturday.

* Southern Kenai Peninsula, including Seward: 1 to 2 inches of rain
is expected through this evening. Steady rain may taper off for a
time tonight into early Thursday. However, an additional 0.75 to
1.5 inches of rain is possible Thursday through Saturday. Higher
amounts are likely over higher terrain.

* Eastern Turnagain Arm, including Girdwood: 1 to 2 inches of rain
is expected through this evening. Steady rain may taper off for a
time tonight into early Thursday. However, an additional 1 to 2
inches of rain is possible Thursday through Saturday. Higher
amounts are likely over higher terrain.

* Eastern Prince William Sound, including Cordova: 1.5 to 3 inches of
rain is expected through this evening. Steady rain may taper off
for tonight into early Thursday. However, an additional 1.5 to 3
inches of rain is possible Thursday through Saturday.

* Valdez: 0.75 to 1.5 inches of rain is expected through this
evening. Steady rain may taper off for a time tonight into early
Thursday. However, an additional 0.75 to 1.5 inches of rain is
possible Thursday through Saturday. Higher amounts are likely over
higher terrain.

Hydrologic Concerns

* Elevated water levels persist on many area streams and rivers.
Additional rainfall may bring sharp rises to water levels. Higher
than normal water levels may continue through the weekend.

* Many lower locations along rivers such as gravel bars and other
spots popular for camping and recreating may become
inundated with water.

* Heavy rain may result in localized ponding in low-lying areas and
locations with poor drainage.

Next Steps

* Residents along area streams as well as river users and
recreationists should anticipate higher than normal water levels
and are advised to monitor weather and river forecasts.

* Reports on river conditions may be sent to the river forecast
center by calling 1-800-847-1739.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>ESFAFC</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FGAK78 PAFC 101845</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>SIGNIFICANT RAINFALL THROUGH SATURDAY WILL BRING RIVER RISES AND LOCALIZED FLOOD POTENTIAL ACROSS PRINCE WILLIAM SOUND AND THE EASTERN KENAI PENINSULA</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Turnagain Arm; Portage; Southern Kenai Mtns; Interior Kenai Peninsula; Turnagain Pass; West Prince William Sound &amp; Whittier; Valdez; Cordova</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002020</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002122</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002063</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ703</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ704</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ725</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ726</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ727</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ728</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ731</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ735</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>