<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 20 Feb 2023 08:16:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MN12663714E9C0.WinterStormWatch.12663750B400MN.ARXWSWARX.ca8e3713b9617335901c6c4cb9eeb985</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-02-20T02:16:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Dodge; Fillmore; Houston; Mower; Olmsted; Wabasha; Winona (Minnesota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-02-21T18:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2023-02-23T18:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS LaCrosse (Southwestern Wisconsin, Southeastern Minnesota, and Northeast Iowa)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Watch issued February 20 at 2:16AM CST until February 23 at 6:00PM CST by NWS LaCrosse</headline>
<description>...Multi-Faceted Winter Storm from Tuesday Evening through
Thursday...
.A complex and highly impactful winter storm is shaping up for
Tuesday evening through Thursday. The heaviest snow arrives in
two waves, the first on Tuesday night into Wednesday morning along
an axis between interstates 90 and 94, where amounts of 3 to 7
inches are expected. While the snow tapers off during the morning
on Wednesday, the combination of ongoing light snow showers and
increasing northeasterly winds during the day may result in
travel impacts due to blowing and drifting of snow.
The second wave of snow arrives Wednesday evening and looks to
produce at least another 6 inches of snow over the watch area with
strong winds continuing to lead to reduced visibilities. By the
time the storm departs on Thursday evening, some locations in the
watch may see over a foot of snow over the course of the two days.
This looks to be a HIGHLY impactful winter storm with many
facets. Travel could be severely impacted at times. With some
adjustments in the storm track possible, along with uncertainties
in where the heavier snow bands and favored wintry mix areas lie
along the southern border of the storm track, expect refinements
to the forecast over the next few days.
...WINTER STORM WATCH NOW IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY EVENING THROUGH
THURSDAY AFTERNOON...
* WHAT...Heavy snow possible. Total snow accumulations of 6 to 12
inches over the course of two days with some locations seeing
amounts in excess of a foot. Winds could gust as high as 45 mph.
* WHERE...Portions of southeast Minnesota and central, north
central, southwest and west central Wisconsin.
* WHEN...There will be two main rounds of snow. The first from
Tuesday evening through Wednesday morning and the second from
Wednesday evening through Thursday afternoon. While the snow
will lessen between these two rounds, increasing winds and
blowing snow may result in continued travel difficulties.
* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult to impossible. Areas
of blowing snow could significantly reduce visibility. The
hazardous conditions could impact the morning or evening
commutes.</description>
<instruction>Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ079-086>088-094>096-WIZ017-029-032>034-041>044-053</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.KARX.WS.A.0004.230222T0000Z-230224T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Dodge; Fillmore; Houston; Mower; Olmsted; Wabasha; Winona</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027157</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027169</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ086</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ088</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ094</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ096</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>