<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.20a4872148a2c50f4d6fd2ecd856448bd0f75e14.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-24T20:19:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.63fdd9d0dac4733a2786682e83c6b5cf74b55723.001.1,2025-07-24T14:48:00+10:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-24T20:19:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-24T20:19:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-25T04:00:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued July 24 at 8:19PM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>...A SLOWLY INTENSIFYING TD KROSA WEST OF SAIPAN MOVING NORTH...
...TD KROSA COULD BECOME A TROPICAL STORM FRIDAY WEST OF ANATAHAN...

.NEW INFORMATION...
None.

.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and
recommended actions for people in the Commonwealth of the Northern
Mariana Islands.

.WATCHES/WARNINGS...
A Tropical Storm Watch continues for Rota, Tinian, and Saipan.

Tropical storm conditions are possible Friday for Rota, Tinian
and Saipan, depending on how quickly 12W intensifies once it has
passed to the northwest of the islands.

All persons in the watch areas should continue preparations for
low-end tropical storm conditions as indicated by your local
forecast and additional details, found below, for your island.

A Flood Watch remains in effect for all of Guam and the Northern
Marianas. Please listen closely for any Flood Warnings that might
be in effect for your area.

Please check the latest public and marine forecasts for detailed
information about additional hazards.

.STORM INFORMATION...
At 7 PM ChST...the center of Tropical Depression Krosa (12W) was
located near latitude 15.5N...longitude 143.5E. This was about 165
miles north-northwest of Guam and 150 miles west of Saipan. Storm
motion was north, 350 degrees, at 15 mph. Storm intensity remains at
35 mph.

.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
Tropical Depression Krosa has made a slight turn toward the north
and is moving at 15 mph. Currently west of Saipan, it will
continue to move along a northerly course to keep west of the
Marianas island chain. The bulk of rainfall and strong winds
remains in the eastern and southern periphery and will persist
over the islands for several days, despite TD Krosa having made
its closest point of approach (CPA) to Rota, Tinian and Saipan.
Again, worsening conditions including strong winds, gusts, and
heavy rains will be felt after CPA. Showers, occasionally heavy,
and increasing south to southwest winds and strong gusts will
spread over the southern CNMI islands today and onward to the far
northern islands Friday and Saturday. A Tropical Storm Watch is in
effect based on the potential for Krosa to intensify to a
tropical storm Friday as it heads northward, staying west of the
CNMI.

</description>
        <instruction>Preparations should be made as soon as possible before conditions
deteriorate and should be focused on the potential for tropical storm
force winds of 39 mph or greater. Keep informed while listening for
possible warnings. Secure loose outdoor objects which can be blown
around. Strongly consider evacuating if you live in a metal roof or
container home, and do so if ordered by local officials.

Residents should keep aware of the latest trends regarding TD 12W.
The latest track depicts a passage to the west of the islands with
tropical storm conditions possible by midday Friday. Preparations
should focus on securing loose items with anticipation for southerly
tropical storm winds of up to 50 mph.

.WIND INFORMATION...
The latest forecast track shows Krosa moving generally northward
through Friday, then turn slightly to the north-northeast over
the weekend, but staying the west of the islands. This will cause
southeast winds to shift to south and increase tonight and Friday,
becoming increasingly gusty as more widespread showers arrive
Friday. Latest forecast projections show south tropical storm
winds of 35 to 40 mph arriving by Friday afternoon and gradually
shifting to southwest Saturday, before diminishing sometime
Sunday. Even then, a strong southwest monsoon pattern will prolong
windy conditions through Sunday night.

.COASTAL INUNDATION AND SURF INFORMATION...
Surf will initially rise along south facing reefs Friday, then spread
to west facing reefs Saturday, exceeding hazardous levels of 9 ft.
Surf along these windward shores could approach dangerous levels of
15 ft Saturday and Sunday and remain at hazardous levels of 10 to 14
ft into early next week due to the persistent monsoon flow. Rip
currents during this time will be strong and life threatening. Stay
out of the water. Minor wind and wave-driven coastal inundation of 1
to 2 feet will be possible along windward shores, especially around
times of high tide as surf reaches peak heights Saturday and Sunday.

.OTHER STORM EFFECTS...
Scattered showers will persist tonight but will increase beginning
around midday Friday, becoming locally heavy Saturday and Sunday as
12W passes to the west. Rainfall amounts of 8 to 12 inches are
possible between Friday and Monday. Even after Krosa begins to move
away Sunday and Monday, a wet monsoon pattern will prolong showers
across the islands.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSPQ1</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTPQ81 PGUM 241019</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PGUM.TR.A.4012.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ceef9d3b43e180c9ea402bb9ba29871510b62e12.001.1,2025-07-24T09:33:00+10:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.af69ca3a58fe22a71f25037372f4fda1a9444250.001.1,2025-07-24T08:20:00+10:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Rota; Tinian; Saipan</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069100</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069120</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ002</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ003</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>