<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.63fdd9d0dac4733a2786682e83c6b5cf74b55723.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-24T14:48:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.af69ca3a58fe22a71f25037372f4fda1a9444250.001.1,2025-07-24T08:20:00+10:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ceef9d3b43e180c9ea402bb9ba29871510b62e12.001.1,2025-07-24T09:33:00+10:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-24T14:48:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-24T14:48:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-24T23:00:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued July 24 at 2:48PM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>...A SLOWLY-INTENSIFYING TD 12W NOW WEST OF ROTA MOVING NORTHWEST...
...TD 12W COULD BECOME A TROPICAL STORM FRIDAY WEST OF ANATAHAN...

.NEW INFORMATION...
None.

.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and recommended
actions for people in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana
Islands.

.WATCHES/WARNINGS...
A Tropical storm watch continues for Rota, Tinian, Saipan, Agrihan,
Pagan, and Alamagan.

Tropical storm conditions are possible Friday morning for Rota,
Tinian and Saipan, depending on how quickly 12W intensifies once it
has passed to the northwest of the islands.

All persons in the watch areas should continue preparations for low-
end tropical storm conditions as indicated by your local forecast
and additional details, found below, for your island.

A Flood Watch remains in effect for Rota, Tinian and Saipan. Please
listen closely for any Flood Warnings that might be issued for your
area.

Please check the latest public and marine forecasts for detailed
information about additional hazards.

.STORM INFORMATION...
At 1 PM ChST...the center of Tropical Depression 12W was located
near latitude 14.1N...longitude 143.6E. This was about 90 miles
west-northwest of Guam and 110 miles west of Rota. Storm motion was
northwest, 320 degrees, at 9 mph. Storm intensity has increased to
35 mph.

.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
Tropical Depression 12W has made a slight turn toward the northwest
and is moving at 9 mph. Currently west of Rota, it will continue to
move along a northerly course to keep west of the Marianas island
chain. The bulk of rainfall and strong winds remains in the eastern
and southern periphery and will persist over the islands for several
days, despite TD 12W having made its closest point of approach (CPA)
to Rota and soon for Tinian and Saipan. Again, worsening conditions
including strong winds, gusts, and heavy rains will be felt after
CPA. Showers, occasionally heavy, and increasing south to southwest
winds and strong gusts will spread over the southern CNMI islands
today and onward to the far northern islands Friday and Saturday. A
Tropical Storm Watch is in effect based on the potential for 12W to
intensify to a tropical storm Friday as it heads northward, staying
west of the CNMI.

</description>
        <instruction>Preparations should be made as soon as possible before conditions
deteriorate and should be focused on the potential for tropical storm
force winds of 39 mph or greater. Keep informed while listening for
possible warnings. Secure loose outdoor objects which can be blown
around. Strongly consider evacuating if you live in a metal roof or
container home, and do so if ordered by local officials.

Residents should keep aware of the latest trends regarding TD 12W.
The latest track depicts a passage to the west of the islands with
tropical storm conditions possible by midday Friday. Preparations
should focus on securing loose items with anticipation for southerly
tropical storm winds of at least 39 mph.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSPQ1</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTPQ81 PGUM 240448</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PGUM.TR.A.4012.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Rota; Tinian; Saipan</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069100</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069120</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>069110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ002</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MPZ003</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>