<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 30 Mar 2022 02:54:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-ND1263E9987678.FloodWarning.1263E9A8B510ND.FGFFLSFGF.fe86f25c5466eb9c84e95755352e1a6c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-03-30T09:54:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Pembina (North Dakota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-03-30T13:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-03-31T16:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Eastern ND and Grand Forks (Northeastern North Dakota and Northwestern Minnesota)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued March 30 at 9:54AM CDT until further notice by NWS Eastern ND and Grand Forks</headline>
<description>...The Flood Warning continues for the following rivers in
Minnesota...North Dakota...
Red River of the North at Drayton affecting Marshall, Kittson,
Walsh and Pembina Counties.
Red River of the North at East Grand Forks affecting Polk and
Grand Forks Counties.
Red River of the North at Oslo affecting Walsh, Marshall, Polk
and Grand Forks Counties.
Red River of the North at Fargo affecting Cass and Clay Counties.
Red River of the North at Pembina affecting Kittson and Pembina
Counties.
Two Rivers River near Hallock affecting Kittson County.
.The crest on the mainstem Red has passed through Oslo and is now en
route to Drayton. Drayton should crest within the next few days with
Pembina following later this weekend or early next week. Minor
flooding continues for most points downstream of Fargo/Moorhead with
the exception being moderate flooding at Oslo.
Minor flooding continues on the Two Rivers River at Hallock. All
other tributaries are below action stage with the exception of the
Maple River at Mapleton which may continue to see some minor
fluctuations above action stage.
Portions of the far southern basin and into west central Minnesota
received a fair amount of precipitation with the latest system to
impact the area. However, with most of this precipitation falling as
snow, immediate impacts to river levels is not expected. Lastly,
today`s river forecasts do incorporate the precipitation that has
occurred and any lingering precipitation with this system.
Additional information is available at www.weather.gov.
...FLOOD WARNING FOR SNOWMELT REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM THIS AFTERNOON
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE...
* WHAT...Minor flooding is forecast.
* WHERE...Red River of the North at Pembina.
* WHEN...From this afternoon until further notice.
* IMPACTS...At 39.0 feet, MINOR FLOOD.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 9:30 AM CDT Wednesday the stage was 38.8 feet.
- Forecast...The river is expected to rise above flood stage
this afternoon and continue rising to a crest of 40.5 feet
Monday morning.
- Flood stage is 39.0 feet.
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Safety message - Turn around, don`t drown. Don`t travel through
flooded areas. Most flood deaths occur in vehicles.
Please report observed flooding to local emergency services or law
enforcement and request they pass this information to the National
Weather Service when you can do so safely.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNC069-NDC067</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KFGF.FL.W.0020.220330T1800Z-000000T0000Z/
/PBNN8.1.SM.220330T1800Z.220404T1200Z.000000T0000Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Pembina</areaDesc>
<polygon>48.74,-97.01 48.77,-97.32 49,-97.4 49,-97 48.74,-97.01</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>038067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NDC067</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>