<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a7ea97b1db06e0dee61227d9022740e3639d9a54.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-09T22:33:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.fca240a5dea762a5b1e4e3810341198cc62ab18d.001.1,2025-07-09T20:17:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-09T22:33:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-09T22:33:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-10T01:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued July 9 at 10:33PM EDT until July 10 at 1:00AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...A portion of piedmont North Carolina, including the
following counties, Cleveland, Gaston and Lincoln.

* WHEN...Until 100 AM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance to Minor flooding of low-lying areas adjacent
to streams and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland,
parks, greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses,
and parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is
possible.  A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become
impassible.  A small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1030 PM EDT, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges
indicated heavy rain is ongoing due to multiple slow-moving
thunderstorm cells extending west to east to northeast from
Lawndale to Fallston, Cherryville, Lincolnton, and Boger
City. Between 1 and 3 inches of rain has fallen. These cells
are training from west to east over the same areas, prompting
concerns for excessive runoff capable of producing areas of
nuisance to Minor flooding.

Areas of greatest concern include in the Lincolnton, Boger
City, and Goodsonville areas, where rainfall accumulations of
2 inches in 30-45 minutes will be enough to overwhelm low-
lying areas, small drainages,  and storm drains, causing
ponding of farmland, woodland, residential yards, golf
courses, and a few roadways. Concern includes small streams
near Huss St, Walker Branch near N Aspen St and N Flint St,
Lithia Inn Branch near Jerry Crump Rd and Jonas Dr.  Clarks
Creek near Clarks Creek Rd and Jeb Seagle Dr may also rise
out of its banks. In Cleveland County, small streams near
Fallston and Lawndale, including Grassy Branch near Hicks
Hill Rd, Knob Creek near Brackett Rd, and Flag Branch near
Union Church Rd may cause flooding.

- An additional 0.50 to 1.0 inch of rain is possible over the
next hour or two due to these very slow-moving cells. This
rainfall may exacerbate developing flooding or cause new
areas of flooding to develop. Caution is advised near any
stream or other vulnerable area.Seek higher ground
immediately if streams start to rise. Please have a plan in
place should flash flooding develop and do not hesitate to
act.

- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
Shelby, Lincolnton, Cherryville, Belwood, High Shoals,
Lawndale, Fallston, Polkville, Waco, Kingstown, Boger City,
Iron Station and Crouse.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 100233</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL 1 AM EDT THURSDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXT.KGSP.FA.Y.0052.000000T0000Z-250710T0500Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-10T01:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Cleveland, NC; Gaston, NC; Lincoln, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.48,-81.37 35.54,-81.21 35.41,-81.14 35.32,-81.43 35.32,-81.62 35.39,-81.68 35.46,-81.63 35.5,-81.48 35.48,-81.37</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037109</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC109</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>