<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 02 Oct 2022 11:55:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC126411A7BE6C.BeachHazardsStatement.126411C2AB00NC.MHXCFWMHX.6b9fbba9c891b8c71292216d116fb9c6</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-10-02T19:55:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-10-03T08:00:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-10-03T20:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City (Eastern North Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued October 02 at 7:55PM EDT until October 03 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City</headline>
<description>...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT FROM MONDAY MORNING THROUGH
MONDAY EVENING NORTH OF CAPE HATTERAS...
...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 8 AM MONDAY TO 7 PM
EDT WEDNESDAY NORTH OF CAPE HATTERAS...
...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM NOON MONDAY TO 7
PM EDT WEDNESDAY...
* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Warning, 2 to 4 feet of inundation
above ground level expected in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking
waves of 7 to 10 feet expected in the surf zone. For the Beach
Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents and large breaking
waves expected in the surf zone.
* WHERE...Northern Outer Banks and Hatteras Island (soundside and
oceanside).
* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Warning, from noon Monday to 7 PM
EDT Wednesday. For the High Surf Advisory, from 8 AM Monday to
7 PM EDT Wednesday. For the Beach Hazards Statement, from
Monday morning through Monday evening.
* IMPACTS...Up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation above ground level is
possible in some ocean and soundside areas near shorelines and
tidal waterways resulting in a threat to life and property.
Significant flooding will extend inland from the waterfront
causing flooding of some homes and businesses. Some roads will
be impassable at times, including portions of Highway 12,
especially around the times of high tide for several high tide
cycles. Large 7 to 10 foot breaking surf will create dangerous
swimming and surfing conditions, localized beach erosion, and
ocean overwash. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers
away from shore into deeper water. Dangerous shore break can
throw a swimmer or surfer head first into the bottom causing
neck and back injuries.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 7:30 AM Monday.
Time of high total tides are approximate to the nearest hour.
Duck NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 5.5 ft, Moderate 6.0 ft, Major 6.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor 1.8 ft, Moderate 2.3 ft, Major 2.8 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
03/02 AM     5.3        1.6        2.3       3-4      None
03/02 PM     7.5        3.8        3.5      8-10     Major
04/02 AM     6.6        2.9        3.7       10      Major
04/03 PM     6.6        2.9        2.6        8      Major
05/04 AM     5.4        1.7        2.2        6       None
Oregon Inlet NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 3.0 ft, Moderate 4.5 ft, Major 5.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor 2.4 ft, Moderate 3.9 ft, Major 4.9 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
03/01 AM     2.5        1.9        1.9       1-2      None
03/03 PM     3.1        2.5        2.2        3      Minor
04/03 AM     3.0        2.4        2.3        3      Minor
04/03 PM     3.4        2.8        2.6        3      Minor
05/03 AM     3.2        2.6        2.6        2      Minor
Coast Guard Hatteras NC
MLLW Categories - Minor 2.5 ft, Moderate 3.5 ft, Major 4.5 ft
MHHW Categories - Minor 1.3 ft, Moderate 2.3 ft, Major 3.3 ft
Total      Total    Departure
Day/Time    Tide       Tide     from Norm   Waves    Flood
ft MLLW    ft MHHW       ft       ft      Impact
--------  ---------  ---------  ---------  -------  --------
02/03 PM     2.0        0.8        1.0        1       None
03/02 AM     2.4        1.2        1.6        2       None
03/02 PM     2.9        1.7        1.9       3-4     Minor
04/03 AM     3.3        2.1        2.5        3      Minor
04/04 PM     3.6        2.4        2.6        3     Moderate
05/04 AM     3.4        2.2        2.6        2      Minor
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.
Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.
Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.
Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203-205</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KMHX.BH.S.0052.221003T1200Z-221004T0000Z/
/O.CON.KMHX.CF.W.0005.221003T1600Z-221005T2300Z/
/O.CON.KMHX.SU.Y.0013.221003T1200Z-221005T2300Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Hatteras Island; Northern Outer Banks</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ205</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>