<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.67aef4cde9ebed9486ed981dd214aefd94e9b3a0.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-20T10:03:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-20T10:03:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-06-20T10:03:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-20T22:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Duluth MN</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued June 20 at 10:03AM CDT by NWS Duluth MN</headline>
        <description>Severe thunderstorms are expected to affect the Boundary Waters
Canoe Area Wilderness late this evening through tonight. Severe
storms will be capable of producing damaging winds, large to very
large hail, frequent cloud-to-ground lightning, and locally heavy
rainfall. Thunderstorms could happen as early as 11 PM CDT this
evening continuing overnight until around 6 AM CDT Saturday
morning.

Now is the time to prepare in case thunderstorms threaten.
Campers should take extra precautions now in order to secure
campsites and make a plan in case of severe weather. For strong
winds, try to keep your tent away from large or decayed trees. For
large hail, use your well-tied down canoe or tent for shelter.
For lightning, sit on your personal floatation devices or sleeping
pads and avoid putting your tent on top of exposed tree roots to
minimize your risk. For potential flash flooding, avoid camping
directly near streams and be prepared to find higher ground. Monitor
NOAA Weather Radio for updates and possible warnings.


Repeating... Severe thunderstorms are expected to affect the
Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness late this evening through
tonight. The storms will be capable of producing damaging winds,
large to very large hail, frequent cloud-to-ground lightning, and
locally heavy rainfall. Thunderstorms could happen as early as 11
PM CDT this evening continuing overnight until around 6 AM CDT
Saturday morning.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSDLH</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS83 KDLH 201503</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>SEVERE THUNDERSTORMS ARE EXPECTED TO AFFECT THE BOUNDARY WATERS CANOE AREA WILDERNESS LATE THIS EVENING AND TONIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>North St. Louis; Northern Cook/Northern Lake</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027137</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ012</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>