<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 22 Jan 2023 10:32:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA1266313DE1A0.CoastalFloodAdvisory.1266314F1330CA.MTRCFWMTR.f15c12a08816e65f172a50e5a8ab70fa</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-01-22T02:32:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes National Seashore; Northern Monterey Bay; San Francisco; San Fransisco Peninsula Coast; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-01-22T02:32:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-01-23T15:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued January 22 at 2:32AM PST until January 23 at 3:00PM PST by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>...LONG PERIOD SWELL, SNEAKER WAVES, AND KING TIDES WILL RESULT
IN HAZARDOUS BEACH CONDITIONS. ADDITIONAL RUNUP ON BEACHES
POSSIBLE THIS WEEKEND IN ADDITION TO MINOR COASTAL FLOODING FOR
LOW LYING AREAS THROUGH MONDAY AFTERNOON...
.The highest astronomical tides of the year, commonly referred to
as the King Tides, will impact the coast and San Francisco Bay
shoreline through Monday the 23rd, and have historically resulted
in the localized flooding of specific low lying areas each year.
The lowest low tides of the event will be observed during the
late afternoon to early evening hours which may lead to trouble
for mariners navigating shallow waterways. In addition, long
period northwest swell will enhance sneaker wave and rip current
risk.
...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 3 PM PST
MONDAY...
...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH THIS
AFTERNOON...
* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, minor coastal flooding
expected at prone low lying coastal locations across the coast
during peak high tide each day through Monday afternoon. For
the Beach Hazards Statement, increased risk of sneaker waves and
strong rip currents along the coast, especially for northwest
facing beaches.
* WHERE...San Francisco, Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes
National Seashore, San Francisco Peninsula Coast, Northern
Monterey Bay and Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast.
* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 3 PM PST Monday.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, through this afternoon.
* IMPACTS...Flooding of areas previously impacted by King Tide
events is expected, including low lying lots, parks, and roads
along the coast with the highest high tides. King Tides in
combination with a long period northwest swell will create
greater risk for sneaker waves as well as farther runup of water
near the coast and on beaches.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Tidal levels will rise along the Pacific
coast but impacts will be more localized to areas such as
Elkhorn Slough near Moss Landing and the mouth of the Salinas
river at the Salinas Lagoon. Beachgoers should be familiar
with times and heights of local tidal levels and also use
caution as sneaker wave risk is enhanced due to incoming long
period swell. Sneaker waves in addition to King Tides could
create additional runup of water and can easily move logs,
making for hazardous conditions.</description>
<instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.
Remain out of the water to avoid hazardous swimming conditions.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ006-505-509-529-530</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMTR.CF.Y.0004.000000T0000Z-230123T2300Z/
/O.CON.KMTR.BH.S.0002.000000T0000Z-230123T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes National Seashore; Northern Monterey Bay; San Francisco; San Fransisco Peninsula Coast; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ006</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ505</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ509</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ529</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ530</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>