<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 23 Jan 2023 03:57:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA1266314C1C34.BeachHazardsStatement.1266316AFFA0CA.MTRCFWMTR.37cfe8e9d94b8ab78ac93cb81ffbbd70</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-01-22T19:57:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes National Seashore; San Francisco; San Fransisco Peninsula Coast; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-01-23T16:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-01-24T22:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued January 22 at 7:57PM PST until January 24 at 10:00PM PST by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>...KING TIDES CONTINUE THROUGH MONDAY AFTERNOON, BRINGING MINOR
COASTAL FLOODING FOR LOW LYING AREAS. A NEW, LONG PERIOD
NORTHWESTERLY SWELL ARRIVES MONDAY EVENING, BRINGING RETURN OF
SNEAKER WAVE AND RIP CURRENT RISK...
.The highest astronomical tides of the year, commonly referred to
as the King Tides, will impact the coast and San Francisco Bay
shoreline through Monday, and have historically resulted in the
localized flooding of specific low lying areas each year. The
lowest low tides of the event will be observed during the late
afternoon to early evening hours which may lead to trouble for
mariners navigating shallow waterways. After King Tides subside, a
new, long period northwesterly swell arrives Monday evening.
...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 3 PM PST
MONDAY...
...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT FROM MONDAY AFTERNOON
THROUGH TUESDAY EVENING...
* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, minor coastal flooding.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, increased risk of sneaker waves
and strong rip currents along the coast, especially for
northwest facing beaches.
* WHERE...San Francisco, Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes
National Seashore, San Francisco Peninsula Coast and Southern
Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast.
* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 3 PM PST Monday.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, from Monday afternoon through
Tuesday evening.
* IMPACTS...Flooding of areas previously impacted by King Tide
events is expected, including low lying lots, parks, and roads
along the coast with the highest high tides. Increased risk of
sneaker waves and rip currents with incoming long period
northwesterly swell.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Tidal levels will rise along the Pacific
coast but impacts will be more localized to areas such as
Elkhorn Slough near Moss Landing and the mouth of the Salinas
river at the Salinas Lagoon. Beachgoers should be familiar with
times and heights of local tidal levels. Once King Tides
subside, continue to use caution on the beach as sneaker wave
risk will return.</description>
<instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.
Remain out of the water to avoid hazardous swimming conditions.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ006-505-509-530</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KMTR.BH.S.0003.230124T0000Z-230125T0600Z/
/O.CON.KMTR.CF.Y.0004.000000T0000Z-230123T2300Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes National Seashore; San Francisco; San Fransisco Peninsula Coast; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ006</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ505</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ509</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ530</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>