<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ba202785b6c908a5723413d88da39b5f13027825.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-08T03:55:00-09:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.58c65621da0dd6650daa6e39e85d4d8f88bc10d7.001.1,2025-11-07T13:51:00-09:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-08T03:55:00-09:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-09T00:00:00-09:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-08T15:00:00-09:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Winter Storm Watch issued November 8 at 3:55AM AKST until November 9 at 6:00PM AKST by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>...INCOMING STORM COULD BRING HEAVY SNOW TO THE NORTHERN
PANHANDLE...

.This weekend's snowfall event has high potential to be a heavy
snow maker to the higher elevations of the Klondike, but for the
Haines Highway there is still some uncertainty. Even higher
uncertainty at sea level in Skagway and Haines.

A low pressure system is forecast to track north through the
eastern gulf through Saturday night. The low will then move
northeast just south of Cross Sound and move inland towards
Canada just north of Juneau. That being said, there is some
evidence that the low could track west and stay in the gulf
through Sunday or turn towards Canada and track south of Juneau
on Sunday. These other tracks would greatly affect the final
snowfall amounts but for now, the following amounts are based on
the first track.

Another variable is the precipitation type forecast. As this low
moves north, the front side of the low will have northerly flow,
that would usher in cooler air and support snow. But as the low
tracks north, there will be a southerly push of wind that would
switch the snow to rain. The question is whether or not the
southerly push makes it that far north. There is more evidence in
the models that the switch to rain would happen because of the
southerly push but history and pattern recognition would say snow
would last into Sunday afternoon. So the precip type forecast
will be a challenge.

* WHAT...Heavy snow possible. Total snow accumulations of 10 to 13
inches possible past mile marker 8. For Skagway, amounts up to
1 to 3 inches possible.

* WHERE...Higher elevations along the Klondike Highway,
especially near White Pass.

* WHEN...From late Saturday night through Sunday afternoon.

* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult and is discouraged.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Depending on the temperature profile and
how much moisture can flow into the area, snowfall amounts
could be as high as 14 to 17 inches, but numbers like that are
on the high end with the lowest confidence. If the southerly
push makes it to Skagway faster than expected, total snowfall
amounts for Skagway would be lower than the 1 to 3 inches
mentioned above.
</description>
        <instruction>Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWAK47 PAJK 081255</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>WINTER STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM LATE TONIGHT THROUGH SUNDAY AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PAJK.WS.A.0007.251109T0900Z-251110T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-09T18:00:00-09:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Municipality of Skagway</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002230</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ318</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>