<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a9fb3468ecfd0d416f749f711936d07443ea8036.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-08T20:41:00-09:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.11265b468b1ed012b9000d2b79f9a6cb44877558.001.2,2025-11-08T13:05:00-09:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Winter Storm Warning</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>WSW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-08T20:41:00-09:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-09T00:00:00-09:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-09T04:45:00-09:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Winter Storm Warning issued November 8 at 8:41PM AKST until November 9 at 6:00PM AKST by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>...INCOMING STORM WILL BRING HEAVY SNOW TO THE NORTHERN PANHANDLE
HIGHWAYS...

.A low pressure system moving northward will bring heavy snow to
the northern panhandle Saturday night through Sunday. Forecast
confidence remains high of significant snow accumulations along
the Klondike Highway and Haines Highway, including White Pass and
Haines Customs. However, forecast confidence is much lower for
snow accumulations at sea-level, particularly for the towns of
Haines and Skagway. As the low moves north, northerly flow, will
usher in cooler air and support snow, however as the low tracks
north, there will be a southerly push of wind that will
ultimately switch the snow to rain. The forecast challenge is the
track of the low pressure and timing of wind change, which will
cause significant variability in snowfall accumulations for
Haines and Skagway at sea- level. By Sunday afternoon, snowfall
rates will diminish as the system begins to depart, and its
southerly push of warmer air arrives in the northern panhandle.

* WHAT...Heavy snow expected. Total snow accumulations of 14 to
18 inches possible at elevation; totals of 2-5 inches possible
near sea level.

* WHERE...Klondike Highway.

* WHEN...From midnight tonight to 6 PM AKST Sunday.

* IMPACTS...Travel will be very difficult and is discouraged
unless it is an emergency.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS... Forecast confidence is high in
significant accumulating snowfall along the Klondike Highway,
with totals of up to 18 inches expected, higher amounts near
White Pass. Forecast challenge for this system remains the
amount of snowfall that will reach the surface at sea-level
near Skagway. Forecast confidence is low for snowfall totals
closer to sea level and for the city of Skagway itself. Warmer
temperatures will likely cap snowfall totals near sea- level
up to 5 inches. However, there is the potential that
temperatures will be too warm for anything more than minor
accumulating snowfall for the Skagway itself. Alternatively,
heavy snowfall could cause cooling in the lower levels,
creating and enhancing snowfall, leading to significantly
higher totals for the town of Skagway, approaching similar
totals to those along the Klondike Highway.
</description>
        <instruction>If you must travel, keep an extra flashlight, food, and water
with you in case of an emergency.

People are urged to prepare their property before the onset of
winter weather.

For the latest road conditions, where available, call 5 1 1 or
visit 511.alaska.gov.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWAK47 PAJK 090541</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>WINTER STORM WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM MIDNIGHT TONIGHT TO 6 PM AKST SUNDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PAJK.WS.W.0016.251109T0900Z-251110T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-09T18:00:00-09:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Municipality of Skagway</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002230</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ318</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>