<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6813bb44c11dbbefa48edb871f7ebcd920c9651d.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-18T13:05:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-18T13:05:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-18T15:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-19T03:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued October 18 at 1:05PM EDT until October 18 at 9:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents
and large breaking waves in the surf zone. For the Coastal Flood
Advisory, up to 2 feet of inundation above ground level possible
in low- lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways on the
ocean side. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of
6 to 9 feet expected in the surf zone.

* WHERE...Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, until 8 PM EDT this
evening. For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 9 PM EDT this
evening. For the High Surf Advisory, until 8 AM EDT Sunday.

* IMPACTS...Flooding of lots, parks, and roads with only
isolated road closures expected. Dangerous swimming and
surfing conditions and localized beach erosion. Rip currents
can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper
water. Dangerous shore break can throw a swimmer or surfer
head first into the bottom causing neck and back injuries.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Large long period swells may produce minor
ocean overwash on vulnerable sections of Highway 12 on Hatteras
Island several hours either side of high tide, which will occur
around 6 pm.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 181705</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 9 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 AM EDT SUNDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.CF.Y.0013.251018T1900Z-251019T0100Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-18T21:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>