<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 15 Mar 2023 06:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA12663CC00814.FloodWarning.12663CCCDCD8CA.MTRFLSMTR.903aff68ac6d466f8bb36e365c577a2d</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-03-15T11:21:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Monterey (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-03-15T11:21:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2023-03-15T19:30:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued March 15 at 11:21AM PDT until further notice by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>...The Flood Warning continues for the following rivers in
California...
Salinas River near Spreckels affecting Monterey County.
For the SALINAS RIVER...including Spreckels...Minor flooding is
forecast.
...FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE...
* WHAT...Minor flooding is forecast to continue through tonight. The
river may drop briefly below the 23 ft flood stage before
beginning to rise again. The river is forecast to reach Minor
flood stage once again Thursday night.
* WHERE...Salinas River near Spreckels.
* WHEN...Until further notice.
* IMPACTS...At 23.0 feet, A few farm residences will begin to flood
near the Salinas River along the reach of the gage. River Road
will begin to flood near Spreckels.
...At 24.0 feet, Significant flooding of the lowest portions of
agricultural land begins within the reach of the gage. River Road
and Spreckels Boulevard begin to flood.
...At 26.0 feet, Moderate flooding of agricultural land and lower
portions of Soledad, Gonzales, Chualar, Spence and Spreckels.
Primary and secondary roads begin to flood within the reach.
Highway 68 begins to flood. Levees in danger of breaching along
the reach. At least 20,000 acres of farm land inundated in the
Salinas Valley.
...At 27.0 feet, Moderate flooding continues along the reach.
Approaches to river bridges within the reach begin to erode. Lower
portions of Castroville begin to flood. Highway 156 near
Castroville begins to flood. Flooding to Foster Road, 1 mile of
Salinas.
...At 28.0 feet, Major flooding of agricultural land within the
reach of the gages. Major flooding begins along lower portions of
Soledad, Gonzales, Chualar, Spence, Spreckels and Castroville.
Water/sewage treatment plants in danger of being flooded. Many
secondary and some primary roads inundated making travel difficult
in the Salinas Valley. Highway 156 and 68 inundated and closed.
Major damage to wide expanses of agricultural land in the Salinas
Valley with 40,000 acres inundated.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 11:00 AM PDT Wednesday the stage was 23.9 feet.
- Recent Activity...The maximum river stage in the 24 hours
ending at 11:00 AM PDT Wednesday was 24.0 feet.
- Forecast...The river is expected to briefly fall below flood
stage just after midnight tonight before rising back into
flood stage late Thursday evening.
- Flood stage is 23.0 feet.
- Flood History...This crest compares to a previous crest of
26.5 feet on 02/26/1969.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Motorists should not attempt to drive around barricades or drive
cars through flooded areas.
Turn around, don`t drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.
Additional information is available at www.weather.gov.
The next statement will be issued this evening by 1700 PM PDT.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC053</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMTR.FL.W.0014.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/
/SPRC1.1.ER.230312T1915Z.230313T1045Z.230316T0300Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Monterey</areaDesc>
<polygon>36.62,-121.85 36.79,-121.79 36.75,-121.61 36.45,-121.23 36.36,-121.36 36.62,-121.85</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC053</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>