<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8d64e29388a9220ec582e95b011c5151fbcd741a.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-24T15:04:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Heat Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HTY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-24T15:04:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-06-24T20:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-24T23:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Upton NY</senderName>
        <headline>Heat Advisory issued June 24 at 3:04PM EDT until June 25 at 7:00PM EDT by NWS Upton NY</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Extreme Heat Warning, dangerously hot conditions
with heat index values up to 108. For the Heat Advisory, heat
index values up to 102 expected.

* WHERE...In Connecticut, Southern Middlesex County. In New York,
Northern Nassau, Northwest Suffolk, Southern Nassau, and Southwest
Suffolk Counties.

* WHEN...For the Extreme Heat Warning, until 8 PM EDT this evening.
For the Heat Advisory, from 8 PM this evening to 7 PM EDT
Wednesday.

* IMPACTS...Extreme heat and humidity will significantly increase
the potential for heat related illnesses, particularly for those
working or participating in outdoor activities. Hot temperatures
and high humidity may cause heat illnesses.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The highest heat index values will take place
during the afternoon.
</description>
        <instruction>An Extreme Heat Warning means that the combination of heat and
humidity is expected to make it feel like it is 105 degrees or
greater. Take extra precautions if you work or spend time outside.
When possible, reschedule strenuous activities to early morning or
evening. Know the signs and symptoms of heat exhaustion and heat
stroke. Wear light weight and loose fitting clothing when possible,
and drink plenty of water.

Seniors and those with chronic health problems or mental health
conditions are at an increased risk. Homes without air conditioning
can be much hotter than outdoor temperatures.

Use air conditioning to stay cool at home or go to a place that has
air conditioning. If you don't have home air conditioning, continue
to seek out cool spaces each day as long as it remains hot, and for
a few days after if your home is still hot. Check on vulnerable
friends, family members and neighbors.

To reduce risk during outdoor work, the Occupational Safety and
Health Administration recommends scheduling frequent rest breaks in
shaded or air conditioned environments. Anyone overcome by heat
should be moved to a cool and shaded location. Heat stroke is an
emergency! In cases of heat stroke call 9 1 1.

A Heat Advisory is issued when the combination of heat and humidity
is expected to make it feel like it is 95 to 99 degrees for two or
more consecutive days, or 100 to 104 degrees for any length of time.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>NPWOKX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS71 KOKX 241904</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>EXTREME HEAT WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...HEAT ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 8 PM THIS EVENING TO 7 PM EDT WEDNESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXB.KOKX.HT.Y.0002.250625T0000Z-250625T2300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-06-25T19:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southern Middlesex; Northwest Suffolk; Southwest Suffolk; Northern Nassau; Southern Nassau</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>009007</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036059</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CTZ011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ078</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ080</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ177</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>