<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 01 Jan 2022 11:50:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA1263DBF1BC78.WinterStormWatch.1263DC1EFA80CA.MFRWSWMFR.c94e38d72fe51d8714e70d1efd3a6f11</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-01-01T03:50:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for North Central and Southeast Siskiyou County; South Central Siskiyou County (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Medford (Southwest Oregon and Northern California)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Watch issued January 01 at 3:50AM PST until January 04 at 12:00AM PST by NWS Medford</headline>
<description>...WINTER STORM WATCH IN EFFECT FROM LATE SUNDAY NIGHT THROUGH
MONDAY EVENING...
* WHAT...Heavy wet snow, with accumulations of 8 to 15 inches and
locally higher amounts up to 20 inches possible. Winds could
gust as high as 80 mph.
* WHERE...South Central Siskiyou County including portions of
highway 89 and Snowmans Summit, and in Eastern Siskiyou County
between highway 89 and Tennant.
* WHEN...From late Sunday night through Monday evening.
* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult to impossible. Patchy
blowing snow could significantly reduce visibility. The
hazardous conditions could impact the morning or evening
commute. Very strong winds could cause extensive tree damage.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- Monday morning, snowfall rates look reach 1&quot;/hr at Snowmans
Summit and could possibly do the same at Black Butte Summit
(though for now forecast rates are closer 0.75&quot;/hr at Black
Butte).
- The best forecast would suggest the snow level stays at or
below the passes until Monday evening, but should the
orographics of Mt. Shasta not be able to maintain the pool of
colder air at the surface, the rate and amount of snowfall
could come up short.
- It seems likely that areas around the edge of the current watch
area will meet winter weather advisory criteria. This would
include portions of I-5 at Black Butte Summit and South of
Dunsmuir, as well as the town of McCloud.
* View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr</description>
<instruction>* A Winter Storm Watch means there is potential for significant
snow accumulations that may create dangerous travel.
* Plan now to avoid traveling during the storm.
* Have an emergency kit with tire chains, flashlight, batteries,
blankets, food, water, and medications in your vehicle.
* The safest place during a winter storm is indoors.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ082-083</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KMFR.WS.A.0001.220103T0800Z-220104T0800Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>North Central and Southeast Siskiyou County; South Central Siskiyou County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ082</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ083</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>