<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 09 Jan 2024 02:27:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC126884822DEC.FloodWarning.126884AF9C00NC.GSPFLWGSP.d3632836f8efb52afe388da69063aa41</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-08T21:27:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Gaston (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-09T16:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-11T19:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued January 08 at 9:27PM EST until January 11 at 7:00PM EST by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...Forecast flooding changed from Minor to Moderate severity and
increased in duration for the following rivers in North Carolina...
South Fork Catawba River At Lowell affecting Gaston County
.A potent storm system is expected to produce 3-4 inches of rainfall
across the South Fork Catawba watershed from Tuesday morning through
Tuesday evening.  This rainfall will quickly overwhelm saturated
soils and result in excessive runoff and significant stream rises
across southeastern Burke County, Catawba County, Lincoln County,
and Gaston County, with several small tributaries of the SF Catawba
River possibly exceeding bankfull and causing Minor to Moderate
flooding of adjacent areas as early as late Tuesday morning.  This
excessive flow will cause the South Fork Catawba River near Lowell,
McAdenville, and Cramerton to exceed Minor Flood Stage Tuesday
afternoon and Moderate Flood Stage Tuesday night into Wednesday
morning.  This will result in significant lowland inundation with
floodwaters approaching vulnerable buildings and property near
Cramerton.  Residents and business owners are advised to move
vulnerable property to higher ground and stay up-to-date by
monitoring the latest river levels and forecasts, as conditions may
change quickly.
...FLOOD WARNING NOW IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY AFTERNOON TO THURSDAY
EVENING...
* WHAT...Moderate flooding is forecast.
* WHERE...South Fork Catawba River at Lowell.
* WHEN...From Tuesday afternoon to Thursday evening.
* IMPACTS...At 13.0 feet, Moderate Flood Stage.  Unusual, damaging
flooding is developing adjacent to the South Fork Catawba River
with considerable impacts to property.  Significant flooding of
Goat Island Park and Riverside Park is ongoing.  Floodwaters are
threatening the Cramerton Fire Department and adjacent
businesses.  The river is approaching the crawl spaces of homes
along Riverside Dr between 4th St and 5th St in Cramerton.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 2:15 PM EST Monday the stage was 3.4 feet and nearly
steady.
- Action/Advisory Stage is 9.0 feet.
- Forecast...The river is expected to rise above Minor Flood
Stage early tomorrow afternoon and rise above Moderate Flood
Stage Tuesday night, reaching a crest of 13.5 feet by early
Wednesday morning.  It will then fall below Minor Flood Stage
Thursday morning.  The river may rise above the forecasted
crest.  Please closely monitor the latest levels and
forecasts.
- Minor Flood Stage is 10.0 feet.
Moderate Flood Stage is 13.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Even 6 inches of fast-moving flood water can knock you off your feet
and a depth of 2 feet will float your car. Never try to walk, swim,
or drive through such swift water. If you come upon flood waters,
stop, turn around and go another way.
Caution is urged when walking near riverbanks.
Motorists should not attempt to drive around barricades or drive
cars through flooded areas.
For detailed information including observed and forecast stages,
flood impacts, flood history, FEMA Flood Hazard Layers, and more,
please visit: https://water.weather.gov/ahps2/index.php?wfo=gsp
The next statement will be issued Thursday evening at 700 PM EST.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC071</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.KGSP.FL.W.0003.240109T2100Z-240112T0000Z/
/LOWN7.2.ER.240109T1918Z.240110T0600Z.240111T0925Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Gaston</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.37,-81.26 35.37,-81.08 35.18,-81.02 35.18,-81.1 35.37,-81.26</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC071</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>