<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 08 Jan 2024 10:09:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12688475F1E4.FloodAdvisory.126884A14420SC.GSPFLSGSP.3d0f9eca98a87c3df76163c56d0b8d24</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-08T17:09:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Cherokee; York (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-09T13:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-11T01:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Advisory issued January 08 at 5:09PM EST until January 11 at 1:00AM EST by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...The National Weather Service in Greenville-Spartanburg has issued
a Flood Advisory for the following rivers in North and South
Carolina...
Broad River near Blacksburg affecting Cleveland County in North
Carolina and Cherokee County in South Carolina.
.A potent storm system is expected to produce 3.5-4.5 inches of
rainfall across the upper Broad River watershed from Tuesday morning
through Tuesday evening.  This rainfall will quickly overwhelm
saturated soils and result in excessive runoff and significant
stream rises across Cleveland and Cherokee counties, with some
small tributaries of the Broad River possibly exceeding bankfull and
causing nuisance to Minor flooding of adjacent areas as early as
late Tuesday morning.  This excessive flow will cause the Broad
River from near Gaston Shoals to Cherokee Falls to exceed
Action/Advisory Stage Tuesday afternoon and approach Minor Flood
Stage late Tuesday night into early Wednesday morning.  This will
result in common, nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to
the Broad River.  Residents are advised to move vulnerable property
to higher ground and stay up-to-date by monitoring the latest river
levels and forecasts.
...FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY AFTERNOON TO EARLY THURSDAY
MORNING...
* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
expected.  Minor flooding is possible.
* WHERE...Broad River near Blacksburg.
* WHEN...From Tuesday afternoon to early Thursday morning.
* IMPACTS...At 16.0 feet, Minor Flood Stage.  The Broad River may be
flooding River Rd and Little Hope Rd near US 29.  Farmland
flooding is continuing adjacent to the river.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 4:30 PM EST Monday the stage was 4.2 feet and falling
slowly.
- Forecast...The river is expected to rise to a crest of 15.8
feet early Wednesday morning.  The river may continue to rise
to near or just above Minor Flood Stage Wednesday morning.
If the river significantly exceeds Minor Flood Stage, a River
Flood Warning may be issued.  Please closely monitor the
latest levels and forecasts.
- Action/Advisory Stage is 13.0 feet.
- Minor Flood Stage is 16.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>If you encounter a flooded roadway, turn around and find an
alternative route.
Caution is urged when walking near riverbanks.
If you are in the advisory area, remain alert to possible flooding
or the possibility of the advisory being upgraded to a warning.
For detailed information including observed and forecast stages,
flood impacts, flood history, FEMA Flood Hazard Layers, and more,
please visit: https://water.weather.gov/ahps2/index.php?wfo=gsp
The next statement will be issued before late Wednesday night at 100
AM EST.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCC021-091</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FL.Y.0004.240109T1800Z-240111T0600Z/
/BBGS1.N.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Cherokee; York</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.24,-81.59 35.18,-81.56 35.09,-81.52 35.07,-81.61 35.16,-81.67 35.24,-81.59</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCC021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCC091</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>