<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:39:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-WA12666D546E0C.HydrologicOutlook.1266718ED430WA.PQRESFPQR.ef3686a5080f7c3421bd375381ae62cf</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-11-30T13:39:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Greater Vancouver Area; Lower Columbia and I - 5 Corridor in Cowlitz County; South Washington Cascade Foothills; South Washington Coast; Willapa Hills (Washington) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-11-30T14:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-12-01T07:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Portland (Northwest Oregon and Southwest Washington)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued November 30 at 1:39PM PST  by NWS Portland</headline>
<description>...A SERIES OF ATMOSPHERIC RIVERS WILL BRING WIDESPREAD HEAVY RAIN
THIS WEEKEND INTO EARLY NEXT WEEK...
...RIVER FLOODING IS POSSIBLE ALONG MOST RIVERS IN SOUTHWEST WA AND
NORTHWEST OR, AS WELL AS URBAN FLOODING...
A series of at least two, if not three, atmospheric rivers will
bring periods of widespread heavy rain to northwest Oregon and
southwest Washington this weekend into early next week. The first
system will also bring heavy Cascade snow for elevations above 3000
feet through Saturday evening before snow levels rapidly rise above
6000-7000 feet Saturday night. This means mountain snowmelt will
also be a contributing factor in regards to river flooding concerns
Sunday into early next week as rain will be falling over a fresh
snowpack. The period of heaviest rainfall is currently expected to
occur Saturday night through Sunday. Total rain amounts for the
entire weekend are expected to range between 3.0-5.0 inches along
the coast, 4.5-6.5 inches over the Willapa Hills and Oregon Coast
Range, and 3-4 inches across the Willamette Valley,
Portland/Vancouver metro, and interior lowlands of southwest WA.
4.0-7.0 inches of rain is expected over the Cascades, Cascade
foothills, and western Columbia River Gorge. 2.5-3.5 inches of rain
is expected for central Columbia River Gorge and Upper Hood River
Valley. Additional rainfall will occur early next week, however
uncertainty is high regarding exact rain amounts from Monday onward.
Given the aforementioned rainfall amounts expected this weekend,
river levels will be rising quickly. Most rivers across northwest OR
and southwest WA have anywhere from a 20-40% chance of reaching at
least minor flood stage, except for the mainstem Columbia and
Willamette Rivers where the chance of reaching minor flood stage is
around 5%. In fact, coastal rivers have a 10-25% chance of reaching
major flood stage; this includes the Willapa River near Willapa, the
Naselle River near Naselle, the Nehalem River near Foss, the Wilson
River and Trask River near Tillamook, the Nestucca River near
Beaver, and the Siletz River at Siletz. To view current and forecast
river stages for any river gage location across southwest WA and
northwest OR, visit https://water.weather.gov/ahps2/index.php?wfo=pqr
Lastly, urban flooding is also possible this weekend, especially in
low-lying areas with poor drainage. If you have gutters and/or storm
drains that still need to be cleared out, now is the time. Any
motorists with travel plans this weekend should also allow extra
time for their commute as hydroplaning will be a risk due to ponding
of water on roads.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ001>008-010-012-WAZ020>022-039-040</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Greater Vancouver Area; Lower Columbia and I - 5 Corridor in Cowlitz County; South Washington Cascade Foothills; South Washington Coast; Willapa Hills</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>053011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>053015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>053049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>053069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WAZ020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WAZ021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WAZ022</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WAZ039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WAZ040</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>