<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.37884b38ad2c5dd6f6941f92551dbb1b1904cc80.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-01T20:29:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-01T20:29:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-01T20:29:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-01T23:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wakefield VA</senderName>
        <headline>Flash Flood Warning issued July 1 at 8:29PM EDT until July 1 at 11:30PM EDT by NWS Wakefield VA</headline>
        <description>FFWAKQ

The National Weather Service in Wakefield has issued a

* Flash Flood Warning for...
Northwestern Chesterfield County in central Virginia...
Southeastern Goochland County in central Virginia...
Hanover County in central Virginia...
Northern Henrico County in central Virginia...
Powhatan County in central Virginia...
The City of Richmond in central Virginia...
Northwestern King William County in east central Virginia...
Southern Caroline County in north central Virginia...

* Until 1130 PM EDT.

* At 829 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicated thunderstorms producing
heavy rain across the warned area. Between 1 and 1.5 inches of
rain have fallen. The expected rainfall rate is 0.75 to 1.75
inches in 30 minutes. Additional rainfall amounts of 1 to 2 inches
are possible in the warned area. Flash flooding is ongoing or
expected to begin shortly.

HAZARD...Flash flooding caused by thunderstorms.

SOURCE...Radar.

IMPACT...Flash flooding of small creeks and streams, urban
areas, highways, streets and underpasses as well as
other poor drainage and low-lying areas.

* Some locations that will experience flash flooding include...
Richmond, Powhatan, Goochland, Ashland, Tuckahoe, Randolph Macon
College, University Of Richmond, Virginia Union University,
Virginia Commonwealth University, Downtown Richmond, Bon Air,
Mechanicsville, Highland Springs, Moseley, Milford, Hanover,
Laurel, Glen Allen, Lakeside and Wyndham.

This includes the following streams and drainages...
Pamunkey River, Chapel Creek, Mays Run, Crump Creek, Rocky Run,
Allens Branch, Newfound River, Appomattox River, Beaver Creek,
Dawson Swamp, Gammons Creek, Dorrell Creek, Skinquarter Creek,
Mill Run, Broad Rock Creek, Gillie Creek, Maple Swamp Creek, Jones
Run, Webb Creek, White Oak Swamp, Gravel Run, Lickinghole Creek,
Parsleys Creek, Broad Branch, Strawhorn Creek, Jordans Branch,
Malden Creek, Cedar Creek, Carvers Branch, Sappony Creek, Licking
Creek, Goode Creek, Doctors Creek, Kingsland Creek, Maracossic
Creek, Mohawk Creek, Horse Creek, Holladay Branch, Stony Run,
Mantilo Branch, Gaddes Creek, Boot Swamp, Millpond Creek, North
Anna River, Powhite Creek, Black Haw Branch, Polecat Creek, Cabin
Branch, Stagg Creek, Otterdale Branch, Aylett Creek, Hungary
Creek, Third Branch, Second Branch, Rafe Swamp, Tomahawk Creek,
Beverly Run, Bull Run, Hawes Millrace, Moore Creek, Opossum Creek,
South Anna River, Deep Run, Needstan Creek, Branch Creek, James
River, Pollard Creek, Whiting Swamp, Fork Bridge Creek, Deep
Creek, Jacks Creek, Cattail Creek, Mattaponi River, Butterwood
Creek, Rocky Ford Creek, Mehixen Creek, Elder Swamp, Falling
Creek, Little Tuckahoe Creek, Nuttree Branch, Fighting Creek, Dry
Creek, Chickahominy River, Norwood Creek, Neds Creek, Stegers
Creek, Little Dorrell Creek, Little Tomahawk Creek, Fine Creek,
Blackman Creek, Reedy Creek, Mechumps Creek, Jones Creek, Dover
Creek, Tuckahoe Creek, Black Creek, Long Creek, Marine Spring
Branch, Kersey Creek, Rocky Branch, Genito Creek, Little River,
Taylors Creek, Salmon Creek, North Run, Horsepen Branch, Wolf
Swamp, Bernards Creek, Fourmile Creek, Turkey Creek, Mill Creek,
Hornquarter Creek, Turner Run, Acquinton Creek, Totopotomoy Creek,
Beaverdam Creek, Matadequin Creek, Swift Creek, Winterpock Creek
and Herring Creek.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding. Do not stay in areas subject to flooding when
water begins rising.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Please report flooding by calling 757-899-2415, posting to the NWS
Wakefield Facebook page, or using X @NWSWAKEFIELDVA.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFWAKQ</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS51 KAKQ 020029</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDetection</valueName>
            <value>RADAR INDICATED</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KAKQ.FF.W.0055.250702T0029Z-250702T0330Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-01T23:30:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Caroline, VA; Chesterfield, VA; Goochland, VA; Hanover, VA; Henrico, VA; King William, VA; Powhatan, VA; City of Richmond, VA</areaDesc>
            <polygon>37.74,-77.82 37.73,-77.8 37.77,-77.78 38.04,-77.36 37.94,-77.18 37.9,-77.19 37.86,-77.13 37.81,-77.12 37.81,-77.09 37.75,-77.09 37.71,-77.01 37.44,-77.42 37.31,-77.81 37.33,-77.8 37.37,-77.88 37.42,-77.86 37.46,-77.87 37.5,-78.0 37.47,-78.05 37.55,-78.1 37.74,-77.82</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051033</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051041</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051085</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051087</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051101</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051145</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051760</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC033</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC041</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC085</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC087</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC101</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC145</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAC760</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>