<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0a02b657fa6ac0647cd6c1a051167d8c34c7ba26.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-01T17:35:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-01T17:35:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-01T17:35:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-01T20:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued July 1 at 5:35PM EDT until July 1 at 8:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of western North Carolina, including the
following county, McDowell.

* WHEN...Until 815 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in low-lying and poor drainage areas.
River or stream flows are elevated.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 535 PM EDT, emergency management and weather spotters
reported Buck Creek and Sams Creek were basically at the top
of their banks following multiple rounds of heavy rainfall in
the past 24 hours. Between 3 and 5 inches of rain have fallen
in the creek basin since Monday afternoon. The stream bed was
widened in some spots by the flooding which occurred during
Helene, and piles of debris in the creek still are inhibiting
flow in some spots. Additional rainfall remains possible
through this evening, and due to the height of Buck Creek and
Sams Creek, even short downpours may lead to flash flooding
along it.
- Areas along Buck Creek and downstream of Sams Creek are the
areas of most concern for possible flooding this evening.
- Some locations that may experience flooding include...
Pleasant Gardens, Busick, and the Blue Ridge Parkway between
Craggy and Little Switzerland.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>When it is safe to do so, please report flooding or landslides
threatening roads or property to the National Weather Service
Greenville-Spartanburg by calling toll free, 1, 800, 2 6 7, 8 1 0 1.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.

Many unstable slopes remain in areas of steep terrain because of the
very heavy rainfall that recently occurred. Additional moderate rain
could be enough to cause a few more slopes to fail, resulting in new
landslides. If you live in an area of steep terrain, avoid
landslide-prone areas and slopes that are unstable. Be especially
alert if you are near a stream, especially at the base of a mountain
or in a cove. Watch for loose-moving soil and rocks or a sudden
increase in streamflow. Leave the area quickly if this is observed.
When driving along roads where the terrain is steep or rocky, watch
and listen for falling rocks, mud, trees, and other debris.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 012135</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 815 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0043.250701T2135Z-250702T0015Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-01T20:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>McDowell, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.72,-82.1 35.72,-82.12 35.72,-82.15 35.72,-82.17 35.74,-82.19 35.76,-82.18 35.76,-82.17 35.77,-82.17 35.77,-82.11 35.75,-82.08 35.7,-82.04 35.69,-82.06 35.72,-82.1</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037111</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC111</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>