<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.92708482c0b44e19d4c1866b7227680bc36d4913.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-15T19:21:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f7b3ecf8dbf8de64b6b8954060f1e8a13c13ac89.001.1,2025-07-15T17:09:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.9a5506493fe3b8649f37ce9b85fe770b56c788a5.001.1,2025-07-15T17:16:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-15T19:21:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-15T19:21:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-15T23:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued July 15 at 7:21PM EDT until July 15 at 11:00PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...East central Rowan County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 1100 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 702 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicates that heavy rainfall
ended across the greater Salisbury area around 5:45pm, with
areas from downtown Salisbury, east and south towards South
Salisbury, Dogwood Acres, and Brentwood Acres, receiving 2-3
inches of rainfall in less than 60 minutes.  This rainfall
produced excessive runoff into area storm drains and small
streams, including along Town Creek, where Rowan County
Emergency Management observed that the stream briefly
exceeded bankfull, resulting in isolated nuisance flooding
near Old Concord Rd and E Innes St.  Town Creek crested
shortly after the heavy rainfall ended.

The streamgauge along Town Creek at E Innes St crested near
10.4 feet and is now below bankfull levels and gradually
receding.  Therefore, flood concerns in the immediate
Salisbury area are ending.  Isolated nuisance flooding was
also likely along Crane Creek from US 52 to Stokes Ferry Rd
to the Corbin Hills Golf Course, but the flood threat here
has also likely ended.  However, high flows are still working
downstream of these areas toward High Rock Lake and isolated
areas of nuisance flooding, especially of adjacent farmland
and wooded areas, will be possible for a bit longer.
Therefore, the Flood Advisory will remain in effect until 8pm
to allow high flow conditions to route downstream into High
Rock Lake.

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Grady Heights, Woodbine, Sandy Ridge Terrace, and Union
Terrace.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 152321</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 11 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0067.000000T0000Z-250716T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-15T23:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Rowan, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.68,-80.33 35.67,-80.32 35.63,-80.3 35.59,-80.48 35.62,-80.52 35.64,-80.53 35.68,-80.51 35.72,-80.39 35.72,-80.37 35.69,-80.33 35.68,-80.33</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037159</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC159</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>