<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6844e2c06b012114549ff220170f8ad612352acd.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-15T18:18:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-15T18:18:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-15T18:18:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-15T20:15:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tucson AZ</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued July 15 at 6:18PM MST until July 15 at 8:15PM MST by NWS Tucson AZ</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of South Central Arizona, including the
following county, central Pima.

* WHEN...Until 815 PM MST.

* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in low-lying and poor drainage areas.
Water over roadways.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 618 PM MST, Doppler radar indicated heavy rain due to
thunderstorms. Minor flooding is ongoing or expected to begin
shortly in the advisory area. Between 0.5 and 1.5 inches of
rain have fallen.
- This includes the following streams and drainages...
Blanco Wash, Moras Wash, Las, San Juan Wash, Bailey Wash,
Fresno Wash, Sil Nakya Wash, Bolas Blancas Wash, Seco,
Arroyo, Ko Vaya Wash, Placeritos Wash, Cerro Prieto Wash,
Mendoza Wash, Murk Kui Wash, Chukut Kuk Wash, Legunita Wash,
Soto Wash, Sabino Wash, Sasabe, Arroyo del, Topawa Wash,
Vamori Wash, Viopuli Wash, San Luis Wash, Pan Wash, South
Mendoza Wash, Sikul Himatk Wash, Contreras Wash, Arivaca
Creek, Baboquivari Wash, Santa Margarita Wash, Comobabi Wash,
Peitas Wash, Compartidero, Arroyo del, Fresnal Wash, Banner
Wash, Anegan Wash, Puertocito Wash, Sells Wash, Altar Wash,
Brawley Wash, Aguirre Wash, San Vicente Wash, Alambre Wash,
Pan Tak Wash, Little Thomas Wash, Thomas Canyon Wash, Osa
Wash, La, Mulberry Wash, Lopez Wash, Ali Molina Wash, Saucito
Wash, Brown Wash, Guijas Wash, Las, Chutum Vaya Wash and
Solano Wash.
- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
Sells, Three Points, Topawa, San Miguel, San Isidro, Kitt
Peak, Ali Chukson, Vamori, South Komelik, Fresnal, San Pedro,
Choulic, Newfield, Queens Well, Coldfields, South Comobabi,
Comobabi, Cababi, Santa Rosa Ranch and Fresnal Canyon.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSTWC</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS85 KTWC 160118</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 815 PM MST THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KTWC.FA.Y.0030.250716T0118Z-250716T0315Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-15T20:15:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Pima, AZ</areaDesc>
            <polygon>31.63,-112.0 32.07,-111.91 32.32,-111.71 32.27,-111.27 31.77,-111.36 31.49,-111.56 31.63,-112.0</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>004019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AZC019</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>