<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8ee7e6f5654f2cdbd4d462bf2d03a8fdbc9f9447.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-29T17:44:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-29T17:44:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-29T17:44:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-29T23:45:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS San Francisco CA</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued July 29 at 5:44PM PDT by NWS San Francisco CA</headline>
        <description>...TSUNAMI WATCH IS IN EFFECTOR COASTAL AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY
SOUTHWARD TO MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE BAY AREA COASTLINE...

THE NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE HAS ISSUED A TSUNAMI WATCH FOR COASTAL
AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY SOUTHWARD TO MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE
BAY AREA COASTLINE. IF YOU ARE LOCATED IN THIS COASTAL AREA, STAY
ALERT FOR FURTHER UPDATES.

AT 425 PM PACIFIC DAYLIGHT TIME ON JULY 29 AN EARTHQUAKE WITH PRELIMINARY
MAGNITUDE OF 8.7 OCCURRED 80 MILES SOUTHEAST OF PETROPAVLOVSK
KAMCHATKA.

ESTIMATED ARRIVAL TIMES FOR THE FIRST IN THE SERIES OF TSUNAMI
WAVES ARE AS FOLLOWS IN PACIFIC DAYLIGHT TIME. SAN FRANCISCO
CALIFORNIA ON JULY 30 AT 1240 AM.

ONCE AGAIN, THE NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE HAS ISSUED A TSUNAMI WATCH
FOR THE FOLLOWING LOCATIONS, COASTAL AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY
SOUTHWARD TO MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE BAY AREA COASTLINE. IF
YOU ARE LOCATED IN THIS COASTAL AREA, STAYALERT FOR FURTHER
UPDATES. STAY TUNED TO YOUR LOCAL NEWS SOURCE AND NOAA WEATHER RADIO
FOR FURTHER INFORMATION AND UPDATES....

* LOCAL IMPACTS...COASTAL AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY SOUTHWARD TO
MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE BAY AREA COASTLINE

* RECOMMENDED ACTIONS...
For people in the watch area...If you are located in this
coastal area, stay alert for further updates, as well as
instructions from your local emergency officials.

* FORECAST TSUNAMI START TIMES...San Francisco Bay, Monterey Bay,
and Central Coast of California 1215 AM PDT on Jul 30

Tsunamis often arrive as a series of waves or surges which
could be dangerous for many hours after the first wave arrival.
The first tsunami wave or surge may not be the highest in the series.

* FORECAST TSUNAMI DURATION...
TSUNAMI WATCH iS UNIL FURTHER NOTICe



* PRELIMINARY EARTHQUAKE INFORMATION...
An earthquake occurred with a preliminary magnitude of 8.7.

This product will be updated as new information becomes available.
Stay tuned to your local news source and NOAA weather radio for
further information and updates.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSMTR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS86 KMTR 300044</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TSUNAMI WATCH. REPEAT, TSUNAMI WATCH.  THE NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE HAS ISSUED A TSUNAMI WATCH FOR COASTAL AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY SOUTHWARD TO MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE BAY AREA COASTLINE. IF YOU ARE LOCATED IN THIS COASTAL AREA, STAY ALERT FOR FURTHER UPDATES.  AT 425 PM PACIFIC DAYLIGHT TIME ON JULY 29 AN EARTHQUAKE WITH PRELIMINARY MAGNITUDE OF 8.7 OCCURRED 80 MILES SOUTHEAST OF PETROPAVLOVSK KAMCHATKA.  ESTIMATED ARRIVAL TIMES FOR THE FIRST IN THE SERIES OF TSUNAMI WAVES ARE AS FOLLOWS IN PACIFIC DAYLIGHT TIME. SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA ON JULY 30 AT 1240 AM.  ONCE AGAIN, THE NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE HAS ISSUED A TSUNAMI WATCH FOR THE FOLLOWING LOCATIONS, COASTAL AREAS FROM SONOMA COUNTY SOUTHWARD TO MONTEREY COUNTY INCLUDING THE BAY AREA COASTLINE. IF YOU ARE LOCATED IN THIS COASTAL AREA, STAYALERT FOR FURTHER UPDATES. STAY TUNED TO YOUR LOCAL NEWS SOURCE AND NOAA WEATHER RADIO FOR FURTHER INFORMATION AND UPDATES.</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>San Francisco; Coastal North Bay Including Point Reyes National Seashore; North Bay Interior Valleys; San Francisco Bay Shoreline; San Francisco Peninsula Coast; Northern Monterey Bay; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006041</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006097</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006001</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006013</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006081</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006085</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006087</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006053</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ006</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ505</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ506</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ508</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ509</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ529</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ530</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>