<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.e0fc748b8cb930b48beccf35b9800dbd0af23faf.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-29T01:27:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.abd7316308abcf7402f43149753760e933913fbf.003.2,2025-07-28T12:59:00-07:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Red Flag Warning</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FWW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-29T01:27:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-29T14:00:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-29T17:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Medford OR</senderName>
        <headline>Red Flag Warning issued July 29 at 1:27AM PDT until July 29 at 11:00PM PDT by NWS Medford OR</headline>
        <description>The National Weather Service in Medford has issued a Red Flag
Warning, which is in effect from 2 PM to 11 PM PDT today. A Fire
Weather Watch has also been issued and is in effect from Wednesday
afternoon through Thursday morning.

* IMPACTS...Abundant lightning on dry fuels resulting in the
potential for numerous new fire starts.

* AFFECTED AREA...For the warning on Tuesday, the eastern
portion of Fire Weather zone the eastern portion of Fire
weather zone 623 in Klamath County and all of Fire weather
zones 624 and 625. For the Fire Weather Watch on Wednesday,
this includes all of Fire weather zones 623, 624 and 625. For
the overnight period Wednesday night, the focus for concern
is across the northern portions of these zones, roughly north
of a line from Crater Lake to Summer Lake.

* THUNDERSTORMS...Scattered thunderstorms with abundant lightning are
expected today. On Wednesday, scattered to widespread
thunderstorms are possible. Storms are likely to be wet, but
lightning strikes outside of precipitation cores are possible,
and cause for concern for new fire starts.

* OUTFLOW WINDS...Gusts of 35 to 50 mph could travel outward up
to 25 miles from thunderstorm cores.

* DETAILED URL...View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr
</description>
        <instruction>Follow all fire restrictions. You can find your county's
emergency sign up form as well as links to fire restrictions at
weather.gov/medford/wildfire. One less spark, one less wildfire.

Be sure you're signed up for your county's emergency alert
system. Familiarize yourself with your emergency plan and make
sure you listen to emergency services. Visit ready.gov/plan for
more information.

A Red Flag Warning is issued when we identify weather conditions
that promote rapid spread of fire which may become life-
threatening. This does not mean there is a fire. These conditions
are either occurring now or will begin soon. It is important to
have multiple ways to receive information from authorities.

If you have not packed your go kit yet, now is the time to do so.
This includes items like important documents and essentials you
cannot live without. Fill your vehicle's fuel tank. Visit
ready.gov/kit for more information.

A Fire Weather Watch means that critical fire weather conditions
are possible during the valid watch time. These conditions could
promote the rapid spread of wildfires which could become life-
threatening. Check weather.gov/medford for forecast updates and a
possible upgrade of the this watch to a Red Flag Warning.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>RFWMFR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS86 KMFR 290827</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>RED FLAG WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM THIS AFTERNOON TO 11 PM PDT THIS EVENING FOR ABUNDANT LIGHTNING ON DRY FUELS FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 623, 624, AND 625... ...FIRE WEATHER WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH THURSDAY MORNING FOR ABUNDANT LIGHTNING ON DRY FUELS FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 623, 624, AND 625</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KMFR.FW.W.0012.250729T2100Z-250730T0600Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-29T23:00:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southern Oregon Cascades; Klamath Basin and the Fremont-Winema National Forest; South Central Oregon Desert including the BLM Land in Eastern Lake and Western Harney Counties</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041029</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041035</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041037</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041025</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORZ623</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORZ624</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORZ625</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>