<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ec088d0779945893dd8ea978f50d36ec995d92d5.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-02T16:41:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-02T16:41:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-06-02T16:41:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-05T00:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Sioux Falls SD</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued June 2 at 4:41PM CDT by NWS Sioux Falls SD</headline>
        <description>The following is transmitted in collaboration with the Nebraska
Department of Health and Human Services and the Nebraska
Department of Environment and Energy...

WHAT...Air Quality Alert

WHERE...Eastern Nebraska

WHEN...6/3/2025 3:00 PM until 06/4/2025 12:00 AM

POLLUTANT...PM 2.5 particulates

AIR QUALITY INDEX...Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups to Unhealthy

ADDITIONAL DETAILS...

An alert for possible Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups (Air Quality
Index orange category)due to smoke has been issued for the
following Nebraska counties: Burt, Butler, Cass, Colfax, Cuming,
Dakota, Dodge, Douglas, Gage, Jefferson, Johnson, Lancaster,
Nemaha, Otoe, Pawnee, Richardson, Saline, Sarpy, Saunders, Seward,
Thurston, and Washington, from June 3, 3:00 pm through June 4,
12:00 am.

During Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups AQI (orange category)
conditions, members of sensitive groups may experience health
effects. Sensitive groups include people with heart or lung
disease, older adults, children and teenagers, pregnant women, and
outdoor workers. When conditions rise to the orange category,
sensitive groups are advised to reduce prolonged or heavy exertion
and avoid intense outdoor activities.

During Unhealthy AQI (red category) conditions, some members of
the general public may experience health effects and members of
sensitive groups may experience more serious health effects.
Sensitive groups include people with heart or lung disease, older
adults, children and teenagers, pregnant women, and outdoor
workers. When conditions rise to the red category, everyone is
advised to avoid prolonged or heavy exertion and those in
sensitive groups should consider moving activities indoors or
rescheduling.

Smoke from Canadian wildfires may affect the air quality in
Nebraska.  Smoke levels and wind directions are monitored by
Nebraska and other states to predict when impacts to the air
quality may occur.

Information regarding wildfires and Impacts in Nebraska is
available from the Nebraska Department of Environment and Energy
(NDEE) at https://dee.nebraska.gov/wildfires-and-impacts-nebraska

Alerts are based on data available from weather forecasts, smoke
plume modeling, satellite imagery, and from air quality monitors
located in Omaha, Bellevue, Blair, Lincoln, Beatrice, Grand
Island, and Scottsbluff.

Advisories for smoke and air quality are issued for affected areas
by the Nebraska Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) and
Department of Environment and Energy (NDEE) and posted on agency
webpages and social media sites.  By notifying the media and local
health departments, alerts help citizens protect their health by
informing them of days where outdoor activities should be reduced
or avoided to minimize exposure to smoke.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAFSD</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS73 KFSD 022141</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Dakota</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>031043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NEZ014</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>