<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.cf5687c7e9773bdcaa7b347324ccab6f30b01566.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-11T13:26:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-11T13:26:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-11T13:26:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-11T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 11 at 1:26PM EDT until August 11 at 7:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of piedmont North Carolina, including the
following county, Gaston.

* WHEN...Until 415 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 109 PM EDT, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges
indicate heavy rainfall is gradually tapering off from south
to north from Crowders to Gastonia, Ranlo, and Dallas across
central and southern Gaston County.  However, rainfall totals
of 1-2 inches have been observed over the past 30-45 minutes,
which is heavy enough to result in excessive runoff and
rapidly rising smaller streams.  Developing areas of nuisance
flooding, especially within the city of Gastonia, are
possible over the next 60 minutes.

Areas of greatest concern include, but are not limited to:
1) Catawba Creek from W Garrison Blvd to S Marietta St to
Ferguson Park and the Catawba Creek Golf Course, to Union Rd
and Fern Forest Dr along the Catawba Creek Greenway.
2) Blackwood Creek near All American Park and from S Linwood
Rd to Old West Ln to Davis Park Rd.
3) Kaglor Branch near W Davidson Ave, Tulip Dr, and Rankin
Lake Park.

- Moderate to heavy rainfall is expected to persist for the
next 15 minutes before tapering off.  This may result in
another half-inch to inch of rainfall.  However, additional
moderate to heavy rainfall is possible into the later
afternoon hours.  Given antecedent conditions, if additional
rainfall develops, more significant flash flooding may occur
and a Flash Flood Warning may be issued.  Caution is advised
near any stream or other vulnerable area.  Seek higher ground
immediately if heavy rain develops.  Please have a plan in
place should flash flooding develop and do not hesitate to
act.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Gastonia, Bessemer City, South Gastonia, Dallas, Cramerton,
Lowell, Ranlo, Lake Wylie and Crowders.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Move to higher ground now. Act quickly to protect your life.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 111726</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 415 PM EDT THIS AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0103.250811T1726Z-250811T2315Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-11T19:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Gaston, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.15,-81.07 35.15,-81.08 35.15,-81.11 35.15,-81.12 35.15,-81.13 35.16,-81.15 35.16,-81.21 35.24,-81.23 35.31,-81.28 35.35,-81.24 35.34,-81.2 35.3,-81.11 35.17,-81.07 35.15,-81.07</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC071</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>