<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.fe41f166d9b41e4dc05196d9afca1692256b091e.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-11T16:10:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.cf5687c7e9773bdcaa7b347324ccab6f30b01566.001.1,2025-08-11T13:26:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-11T16:10:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-11T16:10:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-11T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 11 at 4:10PM EDT until August 11 at 7:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...Central and South-Central Gaston County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Through 430 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 324 PM EDT, Heavy rain responsible for excessive runoff
and rapid rises on small streams from Dallas to Ranlo,
Gastonia, and Crowders has ended and many of these streams
have crested and are receding back below critical (bankfull)
levels.  Residual nuisance flooding of a few streams may
continue for the next 30 minutes, but the flood-threat is
ending.  Therefore, the Flood Advisory will continue through
430 PM, at which time it will be cancelled.

Earlier, Gaston County Emergency Management reported Robinson
St was closed in Dallas due to flooding.  While flood waters
have receded, barricades may still be in place.  Please obey
all barricades, even if roads are no longer flooded, to allow
crews to assess road stability.  It is possible roads were
compomised underneath the surface due to rapid flow.

An NC streamgauge on Catawba Creek at E Hudson Blvd crested
above Minor Flood Stage at 11.66 feet at 220 PM, but has
quickly fallen below Action Stage and bankfull.  Earlier
nuisance to Minor flooding of the Catawba Creek Greenway near
Fern Forest Rd and Union Rd has abated.

- Additional moderate to heavy rainfall is possible into the
later afternoon and evening hours as additional showers
approach Gaston County from South Carolina.  Given antecedent
conditions, if additional rainfall develops (generally
exceeding 1-2 inches in 60 minutes), more significant flash
flooding may occur and a Flash Flood Warning may be issued.
Stay weather aware.  Caution is advised near any stream or
other vulnerable area.  Seek higher ground immediately if
heavy rain develops.  Please have a plan in place should
flash flooding develop and do not hesitate to act.

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Gastonia, Bessemer City, South Gastonia, Dallas, Ranlo, and
Crowders.


- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Move to higher ground now. Act quickly to protect your life.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 112010</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 715 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0103.000000T0000Z-250811T2315Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-11T19:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Gaston, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.15,-81.07 35.15,-81.08 35.15,-81.11 35.15,-81.12 35.15,-81.13 35.16,-81.15 35.16,-81.21 35.24,-81.23 35.31,-81.28 35.35,-81.24 35.34,-81.2 35.3,-81.11 35.17,-81.07 35.15,-81.07</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC071</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>