<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.400164a25c5b392da0c461dc0367d7088c26bb9f.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-11T15:15:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a8944286d861397ce728dda2d598205672eb3292.001.1,2025-08-11T12:44:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-11T15:15:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-11T15:15:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-11T16:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 11 at 3:15PM EDT until August 11 at 4:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall is ongoing.

* WHERE...A portion of central Rutherford County, North Carolina.

* WHEN...Until 415 PM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 259 PM EDT, Heavy rainfall has ended across Rutherford
County and additional heavy rainfall is not expected for at
least the next couple of hours.  However, streams remain
elevated following storm-total rainfall of 3-5 inches, which
occurred between 600 AM this morning and noon.  Smaller
streams are likely either cresting or have already crested,
but high flows from these streams are moving into larger
streams, which are still rising.  Therefore, isolated areas
of nuisance flooding are expected to continue across central
Rutherford County for the next 1-2 hours while the floodwaves
move through the area.  The Flood Advisory will remain in
effect through the mid-afternoon hours to allow streams to
crest and recede below bankfull levels.

Earlier, Rutherford County Emergency Management reported the
following road closures due to nuisance to Minor flooding:

1) Charlotte Rd near/at Railroad Ave
2) Charlotte Rd near/at Cleghorn St
3) Green St near/at N Main St
4) Green St near/at Cedar St
5) Crestview St near/at Edward St.

While flooding conditions have largely abated at these
locations, please obey all barricades that remain in place to
allow crews to assess road stability.  It is possible the
road was compomised underneath the surface due to rapid flow.

Additional areas of concern include. but are not limited to:
1) Catheys Creek from US 64 to Whitesides Rd to Old Ball Park
Rd to Hudlow Rd and Rock Corner Rd.
2) Hollands Creek from Westbrook Dr to Rock Rd to Old Ball
Park Rd to Old Ross Rd.
3) Cleghorn Creek and Charles Creek near Coxe Rd and Cleghorn
Mill Rd.
4) Floyds Creek from Bettany Church Rd, Tanners Grove Rd, and
Morningstar Lake Rd to Henson Rd.
5) Second Broad River from Cherry Mountain St to Low Bridge
Rd.

- Additional heavy rainfall is possible later today.  Given
antecedent conditions and high stream flows, any additional
heavy rainfall, especially if it results in another 1-3+
inches of accumulation in 60-120 minutes, may necessitate a
Flash Flood Warning.  Caution is advised near any stream or
other vulnerable area.  Seek higher ground immediately if
heavy rain develops.  Please have a plan in place should
flash flooding develop and do not hesitate to act.

- Some locations that may continue to experience nuisance
flooding include...
Forest City, Rutherfordton, Spindale, Bostic, Alexander
Mills, Caroleen and Henrietta.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Keep children away from storm drains, culverts, creeks and streams.
Water levels can rise rapidly and sweep children away.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 111915</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 415 PM EDT THIS AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KGSP.FA.Y.0102.000000T0000Z-250811T2015Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-11T16:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.34d13422107c3ae47a8845fa21a87444899d9d0e.001.1,2025-08-11T11:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Rutherford, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.33,-82.01 35.41,-81.98 35.37,-81.79 35.26,-81.79 35.33,-82.01</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037161</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC161</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>