<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 30 Sep 2022 08:57:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640D5CA804.TropicalStormWarning.12641195A790SC.ILMTCVILM.8e4ac62cae1f49ecf6dfa044697450ab</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-30T16:57:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Inland Georgetown (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Tropical Storm Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>TRW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-30T16:57:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-10-01T01:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Wilmington (Northeastern South Carolina and Southeastern North Carolina - Wilmington)</senderName>
<headline>Tropical Storm Warning issued September 30 at 4:57PM EDT until further notice by NWS Wilmington</headline>
<description>...TROPICAL STORM WARNING IN EFFECT...
...HURRICANE WARNING IS CANCELLED...
A Tropical Storm Warning means tropical storm-force winds are
expected somewhere within this area within the next 36 hours
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Andrews
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Tropical Storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 30-40 mph with gusts to 50 mph
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- The wind threat has decreased from the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Last minute efforts to protect property should now
be complete. The area remains subject to limited wind
damage.
- ACT: Now is the time to shelter from hazardous wind.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main wind event are unfolding.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Localized storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for around 1
foot above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: through this evening
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 1 foot above ground
- The storm surge threat has increased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Shelter against storm surge flooding greater than 1
foot above ground.
- PREPARE: All flood preparations should be complete. Expect
flooding of low-lying roads and property.
- ACT: Stay away from storm surge prone areas. Continue to
follow the instructions of local officials.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main surge event are unfolding.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: No additional significant rainfall
forecast
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
localized flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has decreased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
localized flooding from heavy rain.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Localized flooding from rainfall may occur, especially in
low-lying and poor drainage areas. Some rivers and creeks
may rise as a result of the rain. Small streams, creeks,
and ditches may overflow in some locations.
- Several storm drains and retention ponds may become full
and begin to overflow. Some brief road closures are
possible.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is unfavorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Tornadoes not expected
- The tornado threat has decreased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Tornadoes are not expected. Showers and thunderstorms
with gusty winds may still occur.
- PREPARE: Little to no preparations needed to protect
against tornadoes at this time. Keep informed of the latest
tornado situation.
- ACT: Listen for changes in the forecast.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Little to None
- Little to no potential impacts from tornadoes.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://www.weather.gov/ilm/Tropics
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ055</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXA.KILM.TR.W.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/
/O.CAN.KILM.HU.W.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Inland Georgetown</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ055</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>