<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 30 Sep 2022 09:03:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640D5CB9FC.HurricaneLocalStatement.12641195AD6CSC.GSPHLSGSP.eda6b953e46e4163bf3cb1309b0c549d</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-30T17:03:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Abbeville; Anderson; Central Greenville; Cherokee; Chester; Greater Oconee; Greater Pickens; Greenville Mountains; Greenwood; Laurens; Northern Spartanburg; Oconee Mountains; Pickens Mountains; Southern Greenville; Southern Spartanburg; Union; York (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-10-02T12:17:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-10-01T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 30 at 5:03PM EDT  by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>This product covers the western Carolinas and NE Georgia
**IAN BECOMES POST-TROPICAL BUT THE
FLOODING AND HIGH WIND THREAT CONTINUES**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Cabarrus, Catawba,
Chester, Davie, Gaston, Iredell, Lincoln, Mecklenburg, Rowan,
Union NC, and York
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 130 miles southeast of Charlotte NC
- 33.9N 79.2W
- Storm Intensity 70 mph
- Movement North or 350 degrees at 15 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Ian has made landfall on the South Carolina coast and is now moving
north to north-northwest into the Carolinas and Virginia, and
weakening as it does so. Ian has now become post tropical cyclone Ian
as it takes on extratropical characteristics. Wind gusts of 35kts to
40kts in the tropical storm warning area will continue through this
evening, and gradually taper off after dark.
An additional 2&quot; of rain remains possible through this evening and
into the overnight period in areas within a couple counties of the
Charlotte Metro area, with reduced amounts further west. Some ares may
see localized flooding as soils become increasing saturated. The flood
threat will primarily affect the Piedmont, northern foothills, and
northern mountains of North Carolina, and the eastern Upstate of South
Carolina.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across the Western Carolinas east of I-26 as well
as the mountains of Western North Carolina and the Blue Ridge
Escarpment. Potential impacts include:
- Flooding may prompt evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, arroyos, and
ditches may become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas,
runoff may run quickly down valleys while
increasing susceptibility to rockslides and mudslides. Flood
control systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Driving conditions become dangerous.
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
the western Piedmont of North Carolina and eastern Piedmont of South
Carolina, including the Charlotte metro area. Potential impacts in
this area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
Elsewhere across the western Carolinas and northeast Georgia,
occasional strong wind gusts could knock down a few tree limbs or
power lines.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
It is important to remain calm, informed, and focused during an
emergency. Be patient and helpful with those you encounter.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Greenville-Spartanburg SC around 11 PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ010-017-018-026-028-029-NCZ033-035>037-048>053-056>059-062>065-068>072-082-501>510-SCZ008>014-019-101>109</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Abbeville; Anderson; Central Greenville; Cherokee; Chester; Greater Oconee; Greater Pickens; Greenville Mountains; Greenwood; Laurens; Northern Spartanburg; Oconee Mountains; Pickens Mountains; Southern Greenville; Southern Spartanburg; Union; York</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045059</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045083</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ008</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ012</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ014</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ102</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ104</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ105</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ106</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ108</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ109</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>