<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b36a314215d4cd4da0b9887c81df9f20fae8f26e.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-04-20T04:11:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-04-20T04:11:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-04-20T04:11:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-04-20T10:15:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Springfield MO</senderName>
        <headline>Flash Flood Warning issued April 20 at 4:11AM CDT until April 20 at 10:15AM CDT by NWS Springfield MO</headline>
        <description>FFWSGF

The National Weather Service in Springfield has issued a

* Flash Flood Warning for...
Barry County in southwestern Missouri...
Lawrence County in southwestern Missouri...

* Until 1015 AM CDT Sunday.

* At 411 AM CDT, Doppler radar indicated thunderstorms producing
heavy rain across the warned area. Between 1 and 2 inches of rain
have fallen. The expected rainfall rate is 0.5 to 1.5 inches in 1
hour. Flash flooding is ongoing or expected to begin shortly.

HAZARD...Flash flooding caused by thunderstorms.

SOURCE...Radar.

IMPACT...Flash flooding of small creeks and streams, urban
areas, highways, streets and underpasses as well as
other poor drainage and low-lying areas.

* Some locations that will experience flash flooding include...
Monett, Aurora, Mount Vernon, Cassville, Marionville, Pierce City,
Purdy, Seligman, Exeter, Miller, Wheaton, Verona, Washburn, Shell
Knob, Butterfield, Golden, Emerald Beach, Stotts City, Eagle Rock,
Pioneer, Halltown, Freistatt, Chain-O-Lakes, Arrow Point, Hoberg,
Chesapeake, Pleasant Ridge, Mcdowell, Madry, Jenkins,
Wheelerville, Ridgley, Wayne, Red Oak, Table Rock Lake and Roaring
River State Park.

This includes the following low water crossings...
Turnback Creek at County Road 2100, Flat Creek at Highway C, Flat
Creek at Highway Y, Spring River at County Road 2110, Shoal Creek
at Farm Road 2110, Flat Creek at Highway U and Rockhouse Creek at
Farm Road 2145.
This includes the following streams and drainages...
Goose Creek, Sycamore Branch, Cave Spring Branch, Limestone Creek,
Shoal Creek, White River, Truitt Creek, Kelly Creek, Douthit
Branch, Owl Creek, Rock Creek, Gunter Creek, West Fork Limestone
Creek, Panther Creek, Dry Valley Branch, Butler Creek, Stansberry
Creek, Itson Branch, Turnback Creek, Beaver Creek, Blacksmith
Branch, Jenkins Creek, Elm Branch, Hewlett Branch, Otter Creek,
Rockhouse Creek, Hemphill Branch, Pruitt Branch, Trent Creek,
Willow Branch, Joyce Creek, Zerbert Branch, Hall Branch, Little
Crane Creek, Woodward Creek, Coon Creek, Johns Branch, Sinking
Creek, East Fork Rock Creek, Deer Creek, Sac River, Mikes Creek,
Chesapeake Branch, Roaring River, Mill Branch, Clear Creek, Crane
Creek, Dry Fork, East Fork Jenkins Creek, Stahl Creek, Indian
Creek, Fortune Branch, Honey Creek, Hudson Creek, North Sycamore
Branch, White Oak Creek, Capps Creek, Williams Creek, Stubblefield
Branch, Ward Branch, Flat Creek, Pogue Creek, Sycamore Creek, Dry
Creek, Spring River, Calton Creek, Center Creek and Big Sugar
Creek.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Many flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFWSGF</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS53 KSGF 200911</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDetection</valueName>
            <value>RADAR INDICATED</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KSGF.FF.W.0010.250420T0911Z-250420T1515Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-04-20T10:15:00-05:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Barry, MO; Lawrence, MO</areaDesc>
            <polygon>37.28,-93.61 36.82,-93.61 36.82,-93.57 36.5,-93.58 36.5,-94.08 37.29,-94.05 37.28,-93.61</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>029009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>029109</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MOC009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MOC109</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>