<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.3049b6ae837e53370ae5c379c1558b0b96bc4364.001.3</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-29T13:19:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Fire Weather Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FWA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-29T13:19:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-01T14:00:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-30T05:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Medford OR</senderName>
        <headline>Fire Weather Watch issued June 29 at 1:19PM PDT until July 1 at 8:00PM PDT by NWS Medford OR</headline>
        <description>...FIRE WEATHER WATCH IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH
TUESDAY EVENING FOR FOR ABUNDANT LIGHTNING ON DRY FUELS FOR
FIRE WEATHER ZONES 280, 281, AND 284...

The National Weather Service in Medford has upgraded the Fire
Weather Watch to a Red Flag Warning, which is in effect from 2 PM
to 8 PM PDT Monday. Another Fire Weather Watch has also been
issued. This Fire Weather Watch is in effect from Tuesday
afternoon through Tuesday evening.

* IMPACTS...Given the long stretch of dry and hot and very
conditions, lightning efficiency will be high to very high for
fire starts. Any fires that develop will likely spread
rapidly.

* AFFECTED AREA...All of Fire Weather Zones 280, 281, and 284.

* THUNDERSTORMS...Isolated to scattered thunderstorms.
Lightning strikes outside of precipitation cores are
possible, and cause for concern.

* OUTFLOW WINDS...Gust up to 35 mph. These outflow winds can
travel up to 50 miles away from the thunderstorm that caused
it.

* ADDITIONAL INFORMATION...Storms will tend to be isolated to
start then increasing during the afternoon into the early
evening hours both Monday and Tuesday. Thunderstorms are
expected to trend wetter later in the afternoon and early
evening both Monday and Tuesday, but remain a mix of wet and dry
storms.


* DETAILED URL...View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr
</description>
        <instruction>Follow all fire restrictions. You can find your county's
emergency sign up form as well as links to fire restrictions at
weather.gov/medford/wildfire. One less spark, one less wildfire.

Be sure you're signed up for your county's emergency alert
system. Familiarize yourself with your emergency plan and make
sure you listen to emergency services. Visit ready.gov/plan for
more information.

A Red Flag Warning is issued when we identify weather conditions
that promote rapid spread of fire which may become life-
threatening. This does not mean there is a fire. These conditions
are either occurring now or will begin soon. It is important to
have multiple ways to receive information from authorities.

Follow all fire restrictions. Avoid activities that could cause
sparks. Visit weather.gov/medford/wildfire for links to fire
restrictions in your area.

If you have not packet your go kit yet, now is the time to do so.
This includes items like important documents and essentials you
cannot live without. Fill your vehicle's fuel tank. Visit
ready.gov/kit for more information.

A Fire Weather Watch means that critical fire weather conditions
are possible during the valid watch time. These conditions could
promote the rapid spread of wildfires which could become life-
threatening. Check weather.gov/medford for forecast updates and a
possible upgrade of the this watch to a Red Flag Warning.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>RFWMFR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS86 KMFR 292019</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>RED FLAG WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM TO 8 PM PDT MONDAY FOR FOR ABUNDANT LIGHTNING ON DRY FUELS FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 280, 281, AND 284</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMFR.FW.A.0002.250701T2100Z-250702T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-07-01T20:00:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Western Klamath National Forest; Central Siskiyou County Including Shasta Valley; Siskiyou County from the Cascade Mountains East and South to Mt Shasta</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006093</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ280</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ281</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ284</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>