<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 26 Jan 2024 04:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12688587B4B4.FloodAdvisory.126885973CE0NC.GSPFLSGSP.226d09e946917561899b8037eae61651</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-26T11:21:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Henderson; Transylvania (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-26T11:21:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-27T13:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Advisory issued January 26 at 11:21AM EST until January 27 at 1:00PM EST by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...The Flood Advisory continues for the following rivers in North
Carolina...
French Broad River At Blantyre affecting Henderson and
Transylvania Counties.
.Moderate rainfall over the upper French Broad River watershed
resulted in 1-2 inches of accumulation on Thursday.  Excessive
runoff caused significant stream rises on tributaries as well as the
upper French Broad River, resulting in isolated areas of bankfull
rises and nuisance flooding of adjacent, low-lying areas.  The upper
French Broad River from Brevard to Penrose, Blantyre, and Etowah is
nearing crest at 15.6 feet and will begin a slow recession this
afternoon into the evening hours.  However, additional heavy
rainfall is possible on Saturday and given high streamflows and
saturated soils, additional rises on the French Broad River and
associated tributaries are likely.  In anticipation of new rises, a
River Flood Warning may be issued later today for Minor flooding
along the upper French Broad River later Saturday into Sunday.
Residents, business owners, and other interested parties should stay
weather aware and monitor the latest forecasts.
...FLOOD ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL EARLY TOMORROW AFTERNOON...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.
* WHERE...French Broad River at Blantyre.
* WHEN...Until early tomorrow afternoon.
* IMPACTS...At 16.0 feet, Minor Flood Stage. Farmland flooding
continues on both sides of the French Broad River. Floodwaters
begin to impact boat access areas at Grove Bridge Rd and Crab
Creek Rd.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 11:01 AM EST Friday the stage was 15.6 feet and nearing
crest.
- Forecast...The river is currently cresting around 15.6 feet
and will begin a slow recession late Friday afternoon through
Saturday morning.  New river rises are possible later
Saturday morning through Saturday night with additional heavy
rainfall expected.  A Flood Warning may be necessary for a
Minor Flood Stage exceedance late Saturday into Sunday.  Stay
weather aware and monitor the latest forecasts.
- Action/Advisory Stage is 15.0 feet.
- Minor Flood Stage is 16.0 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Caution is urged when walking near riverbanks.
If you encounter a flooded roadway, turn around and find an
alternative route.
For detailed information including observed and forecast stages,
flood impacts, flood history, FEMA Flood Hazard Layers, and more,
please visit: https://water.weather.gov/ahps2/index.php?wfo=gsp
The next statement will be issued before Saturday morning at 1000 AM
EST.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC089-175</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.KGSP.FL.Y.0009.000000T0000Z-240127T1800Z/
/BLAN7.N.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Henderson; Transylvania</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.38,-82.57 35.37,-82.5 35.29,-82.54 35.21,-82.67 35.26,-82.74 35.34,-82.61 35.38,-82.57</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037175</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC175</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>