<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f666a727a442f28015bbb74c278ad38064a94986.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-03T13:23:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>High Surf Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-03T13:23:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-06T00:00:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-04T03:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Los Angeles/Oxnard CA</senderName>
        <headline>High Surf Advisory issued November 3 at 1:23PM PST until November 7 at 6:00PM PST by NWS Los Angeles/Oxnard CA</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the first High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of
10 to 14 feet with dangerous rip currents. For the second High
Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 15 to 18 feet, with local
sets to 20 feet possible, and dangerous rip currents. For the
Coastal Flood Advisory, moderate coastal flooding possible.
Breaking waves at Morro Bay are possible for the second High
Surf Advisory.

* WHERE...San Luis Obispo County Beaches and Santa Barbara County
Central Coast Beaches. Largest surf focused across west facing
beaches.

* WHEN...For the first High Surf Advisory, until 3 AM PST Tuesday.
For the second High Surf Advisory, from 12 AM PST Thursday to 6
PM PST Friday. For the Coastal Flood Advisory, from 4 AM
Thursday to 2 PM PST Friday.

* IMPACTS...For the High Surf Advisory, there is an increased risk
for ocean drowning. Rip currents can pull swimmers and surfers
out to sea. Large breaking waves can cause injury, wash people
off beaches and rocks, and capsize small boats near shore. For
the Coastal Flood Advisory, flooding of sea water is likely,
around the time of high tide, over vulnerable low- lying coastal
areas such as parking lots, beaches, and walkways. Significant
damage to roads or structures is NOT expected.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...High tides between 6.9 to 7.1 feet are
expected between 9 and 1030 AM both Thursday and Friday.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. Do
NOT drive around barricades or through water of unknown depth.

Remain out of the water due to dangerous surf conditions, or stay
near occupied lifeguard towers. Rock jetties can be deadly in
such conditions, stay off the rocks.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWLOX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS46 KLOX 032123</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 3 AM PST TUESDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 12 AM THURSDAY TO 6 PM PST FRIDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 4 AM THURSDAY TO 2 PM PST FRIDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KLOX.SU.Y.0024.251106T0800Z-251108T0200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-07T18:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>San Luis Obispo County Beaches; Santa Barbara County Central Coast Beaches</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006079</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006083</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ340</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ346</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>