<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5dd4da68aeb3cc625121cdaa40de3139c2813819.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T23:33:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T23:33:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T23:33:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T05:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 11:33PM EDT until May 13 at 5:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance to Minor flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
expected.

* WHERE...Central and southeastern Laurens County in South Carolina

* WHEN...Until 515 AM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.


* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1119 PM EDT, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges
training heavy rain due to numerous thunderstorms extending
from the Salud River to the Enoree River across central
Laurens County, from Waterloo to Cross Hill to Mountville to
Laurens, Clinton, and Ora.  These storms have produced 1-2
inches of rain over the past 2 hours, and additional heavy
rain is likely through 1 am.  Resultant excessive runoff will
produce significant rises on small streams across the
Advisory area including Cane Creek near Waterloo and Harris
Springs, the Little River near Laurens, and Duncan Creek near
Ora.  Several streams may exceed bankfull, causing nuisance
to Minor flooding of adjacent low-lying areas.  As these
storms train over the city of Laurens, storm drains and
culverts may be quickly overwhelmed creating areas of roadway
and property flooding.  Flooding of Little River Park is
likely.

Areas of immediate concern include near Harris Springs Rd (SC
19) and Blakely Rd, Neely Ferry Rd (SC 54), US 221 near
Waterloo, and Little River in Laurens.  Drivers are urged to
avoid flooded roadways.

- If heavy rainfall persists over the next 60-90 minutes, a
Flash Flood Warning may be issued.  If rapid stream rises are
observed, avoid all low-lying areas near streams and be
prepared to seek higher ground.  Drivers are urged to avoid
any flooded roadways and Turn Around Don't Drown.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Laurens, Clinton, Ware Shoals, Joanna, Cross Hill, Waterloo,
Mountville and Ora.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130333</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 515 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0027.250513T0333Z-250513T0915Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T05:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Laurens, SC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>34.63,-81.93 34.6,-81.91 34.6,-81.89 34.59,-81.89 34.59,-81.87 34.58,-81.86 34.6,-81.84 34.58,-81.81 34.56,-81.72 34.32,-81.91 34.24,-82.0 34.27,-82.05 34.3,-82.08 34.31,-82.12 34.32,-82.13 34.33,-82.16 34.36,-82.18 34.39,-82.23 34.63,-81.98 34.63,-81.93</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045059</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCC059</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>