<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a05851a70660ee9b01abc691b0b811bc9635a847.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T21:12:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T21:12:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T21:12:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T02:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 9:12PM EDT until May 13 at 2:45AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...Eastern Buncombe County, northeastern Henderson County,
and western Rutherford County in North Carolina.

* WHEN...Until 245 AM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 850 PM EDT, Periods of light rainfall continue to pivot
into the central Blue Ridge Escarpment of North Carolina
following several rounds of light to moderate rainfall which
began early Monday morning.  While short-term rates have not
been significant enough to cause flash-flood concerns, the
Advisory area has seen 1.5-3 inches since early Monday
morning.  This rainfall is beginning to produce excessive
runoff into the following streams and associated tributaries:

(Rocky) Broad River near Gerton, Bat Cave and Chimney Rock;
Swannanoa River near Montreat, Black Mountain, and Swannanoa;
Clear Creek near Edneyville;
and Cane Creek near Fairview.

Over the next several hours, stream levels are expected to
gradually rise and exceed bankfull levels in several
locations.  Flood-prone areas along these streams are likely
to see developing nuisance flood conditions over the next
several hours.  Areas of imminent concern include along the
Rocky Broad River near Bat Cave, Chimney Rock, and Lake Lure,
where rising stream levels are currently approaching bankfull
or Action Stage.

High flows from the headwaters of the Swannanoa River may
cause rising stream levels downstream from Swannanoa to
Biltmore Village, but absent additional and prolonged heavy
rainfall, levels are expected to stay below bankfull levels.

High flows from the headwaters of the Broad River may cause
rising stream levels downstream of Lake Lure, resulting in
stream levels approaching bankfull conditions.  Stay weather
aware and heed guidance from local officials as necessary.

- Rounds of moderate to heavy showers and a few embedded
thunderstorms are possible generally after 10pm as the best
instability moves through the Advisory area.  Once they
begin, these showers and storms may persist for 2-4 hours
during the overnight period.  Given the saturated soils and
increasing stream flows, resultant runoff from this activity
may be significant enough to produce flash flooding.
Therefore, those in the Advisory area are encouraged to stay
weather aware later tonight as a Flash Flood Warning or two
may be needed should those heavier rainfall rates
materialize.  A Flood Watch for flash flooding remains in
effect through 8am Tuesday.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance to Minor flooding
include...Black Mountain, Swannanoa, Fairview, town of Lake
Lure, Chimney Rock Village, Bat Cave, Chimney Rock State
Park, Montreat, Gerton, Edneyville, Dana, and Shingle Hollow.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130112</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 245 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0024.250513T0112Z-250513T0645Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T02:45:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Buncombe, NC; Henderson, NC; Rutherford, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.64,-82.39 35.72,-82.36 35.74,-82.32 35.71,-82.28 35.68,-82.29 35.67,-82.28 35.61,-82.27 35.59,-82.29 35.57,-82.26 35.52,-82.15 35.54,-82.06 35.39,-82.11 35.41,-82.16 35.4,-82.18 35.4,-82.25 35.38,-82.28 35.31,-82.31 35.3,-82.33 35.4,-82.44 35.51,-82.41 35.64,-82.39</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037021</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037089</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037161</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC021</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC089</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC161</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>