<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7456ce60cc4592abd2c4d588404b00df2edb0ec3.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T16:45:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T16:45:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T16:45:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T21:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Aberdeen SD</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued May 12 at 4:45PM CDT by NWS Aberdeen SD</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency has issued an Air
Quality Alert for ozone pollution. The Air Quality Index (AQI) is
expected to reach the Orange or Unhealthy for Sensitive Groups
category.

* WHERE...West central, east central, central, south central,
southwest, north central, and northwest Minnesota.

* WHEN...From noon CDT to 9 PM CDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease
(including asthma), heart disease, children and older adults, and
people who are active outdoors, may experience health effects.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Ground-level ozone is expected to be high once
again during the afternoon hours on Tuesday across roughly the
western two-thirds of Minnesota, including the Twin Cities Metro.
Mostly sunny skies, warm temperatures and low humidity will provide a
favorable environment for two types of pollutants (volatile organic
compounds and nitrogen oxides) to react with sunlight in the air to
produce ground-level ozone. Ozone will remain elevated on Wednesday
as sunny skies, warm temperatures and dry conditions persist.
</description>
        <instruction>Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease (including
asthma), heart disease, children and older adults, and people who are
active outdoors, should limit prolonged or heavy outdoor exertion.

Reduce or eliminate activities that contribute to air pollution, such
as outdoor burning, and use of residential wood burning devices.
Reduce vehicle trips and vehicle idling as much as possible.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAABR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS73 KABR 122145</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FROM NOON CDT TO 9 PM CDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Traverse; Big Stone</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027155</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ046</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>