<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a15e63c01bbbc2834cdb39170f26a8aa5fee20b3.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T23:58:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T23:58:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T23:58:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T11:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 11:58PM EDT until May 13 at 11:45AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of Caldwell County, North Carolina.

* WHEN...Until 1145 AM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1145 PM EDT, An axis of training showers moved from Lake
Rhodhiss and Sawmills to Lenoir, Kings Creek, and Patterson
between 9 and 10 pm Monday evening, producing a quick 1-1.5
inches of rainfall.  This rainfall occurred on top of soils
saturated by numerous rounds of light to moderate rainfall
which impacted Caldwell County since early Monday morning.
While short-term rates have not been significant enough to
cause flash-flood concerns, the Advisory area has seen 2.5-4
inches of storm-total rainfall since early Monday morning.
This rainfall is beginning to produce excessive runoff into
the following streams and associated tributaries:

Yadkin River headwaters near Patterson, including along
Buffalo Creek;
Lower Creek near Lenoir;
and Gunpowder Creek near Hudson, Sawmills, and Granite Falls.

Over the next several hours, stream levels are expected to
gradually rise and exceed bankfull levels in several
locations.  Flood-prone areas along these streams are likely
to see developing nuisance flood conditions over the next
several hours.  Areas of imminent concern include along
Yadkin River Rd near Patterson and Happy Valley, Lower Creek
from Cedar Rock to Lenoir, and poor-drainage areas from
Sawmills to Granite Falls.

- Rounds of moderate to heavy showers and a few embedded
thunderstorms are possible generally between midnight and 3am
as additional forcing and instability moves through the
Advisory area.  These showers and storms may persist for 1-2
hours during this timeframe.  Given the saturated soils and
increasing stream flows, resultant runoff from this activity
may be significant enough to produce flash flooding.
Therefore, those in the Advisory area are encouraged to stay
weather aware later tonight as a Flash Flood Warning may be
needed should those heavier rainfall rates materialize.  A
Flood Watch for flash flooding remains in effect through 8am
Tuesday.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance to Minor flooding
include...
Lenoir, Sawmills, Granite Falls, Gamewell, Hudson, Cajah's
Mountain, Blowing Rock, Cedar Rock, and Patterson.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130358</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 1145 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0028.250513T0358Z-250513T1545Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T11:45:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Caldwell, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.08,-81.43 36.05,-81.39 36.04,-81.4 36.04,-81.38 36.04,-81.37 35.97,-81.42 35.85,-81.45 35.79,-81.45 35.78,-81.56 35.82,-81.6 35.82,-81.61 35.85,-81.64 35.93,-81.64 35.99,-81.67 36.12,-81.66 36.11,-81.54 36.1,-81.52 36.1,-81.48 36.07,-81.44 36.08,-81.43</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037027</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC027</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>