<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.24f19e3776d0b9de24a8626fe542fbf80934d940.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T20:38:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T20:38:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T20:38:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T08:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 8:38PM EDT until May 13 at 8:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance to Minor flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
expected.

* WHERE...Central and western McDowell County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 815 AM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 823 PM EDT, Rounds of light to moderate rainfall continue
to pivot into McDowell County, impacting the upper Catawba
River and associated tributaries, including the North Fork
Catawba River, Mill Creek, Crooked Creek, Curtis Creek,
Mackey Creek, Buck Creek, Nix Creek, and Toms Creek.  While
short-term rates have not been significant enough to cause
flash-flood concerns, the Advisory area has seen 1.5-3 inches
since early Monday morning.  This rainfall is beginning to
produce excessive runoff into the above streams and
associated tributaries.  Over the next several hours, stream
levels are expected to gradually rise and exceed bankfull
levels in several locations.  Flood-prone areas along these
streams from Old Fort to Lackeytown to Greenlee, Sunnyvale,
Pleasant Gardens, Marion, and Woodlawn are likely to see
developing nuisance flood conditions over the next several
hours.  As these high flows move into the upper Catawba River
into the nighttime hours, expect the upper Catawba River to
approach and possibly exceed bankfull levels later tonight.

- Rounds of moderate to heavy showers and a few embedded
thunderstorms are possible generally after 10pm as the best
instability moves through the Advisory area.  These showers
and storms may persist for several hours into the overnight.
Given the saturated soils and increasing stream flows,
resultant runoff from this activity my be significant enough
to produce flash flooding.  Therefore, those in the Advisory
area are encouraged to stay weather aware later tonight as a
Flash Flood Warning or two may be needed should those heavier
rainfall rates materialize.  A Flood Watch for flash flooding
remains in effect through 8am Tuesday.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance to Minor flooding
include...
Marion, Old Fort, Lake James State Park, Pleasant Gardens,
Sugar Hill, Woodlawn,  Little Switzerland, and Nebo.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130038</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 815 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0023.250513T0038Z-250513T1215Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T08:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>McDowell, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.54,-82.06 35.52,-82.15 35.55,-82.21 35.56,-82.25 35.59,-82.29 35.62,-82.26 35.65,-82.29 35.67,-82.28 35.68,-82.29 35.7,-82.29 35.7,-82.28 35.7,-82.26 35.74,-82.19 35.77,-82.16 35.79,-82.17 35.8,-82.16 35.85,-82.1 35.86,-82.04 35.72,-81.87 35.67,-81.97 35.54,-82.06</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037111</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC111</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>