<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.656fadf8f54d2c6719e0783a88cb3f6d35c59b2c.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T19:05:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T19:05:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T19:05:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T07:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 7:05PM EDT until May 13 at 7:00AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...Central and southern Henderson County, North Carolina

* WHEN...Until 700 AM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 646 PM EDT, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges
indicated several rounds of moderate to heavy rain have
fallen over the Mud Creek, Bat Fork Creek, and Green River
watersheds of central and southern Henderson County since
4pm.  One to two inches of rain has fallen over the past 2-3
hours, with storm-total rainfall of 2-3 inches across the
Advisory area since early Monday morning.  Saturated soils
are contributing to excessive runoff into area streams, and
rapid rises are developing, especially across the Green River
and Mud Creek headwaters from Crab Creek to Tuxedo to Flat
Rock.  Isolated to scattered bankfull conditions are expected
to develop across the Advisory area over the next 1-2 hours,
resulting in nuisance flooding of flood-prone, low-lying
areas adjacent to impacted streams.  High flows along Mud
Creek will move downstream into Hendersonville over the next
2-4 hours as well, likely resulting in nuisance flooding of
flood-prone areas in and near Hendersonville, especially
Crooked Creek Golf Course, farmland near Erkwood Dr, and
William H King Memorial Park.

- Additional significant rainfall is not expected for at least
the next few hours.  However, bands of additional heavy
rainfall cannot be ruled out later tonight through the early
morning hours on Tuesday.  Any additional heavy rainfall on
top of saturated soils and elevated streams may result in
flash flooding.  Individuals within the Advisory area are
urged to stay weather aware, avoid all low-lying areas
adjacent to streams, and be prepared to seek higher ground
should flash-flooding develop.  Regardless, elevated flows
along larger streams including Mud Creek and the Green River
may persist into Tuesday morning.  A Flood Watch remains in
effect through Tuesday morning.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Hendersonville, Flat Rock, Etowah, Mountain Home, Laurel
Park, Saluda, Dupont State Forest, Jones Gap State Park,
Valley Hill, Crab Creek, East Flat Rock, Tuxedo, Horse Shoe
and Dana.

- Http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 122305</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 7 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0022.250512T2305Z-250513T1100Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T07:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Henderson, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.4,-82.44 35.3,-82.33 35.28,-82.35 35.24,-82.35 35.24,-82.36 35.19,-82.35 35.18,-82.37 35.22,-82.39 35.2,-82.42 35.17,-82.44 35.18,-82.48 35.16,-82.53 35.16,-82.55 35.15,-82.58 35.16,-82.59 35.26,-82.6 35.26,-82.62 35.29,-82.61 35.3,-82.62 35.39,-82.51 35.4,-82.44</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037089</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC089</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>