<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.daca3ba76ae4c4db243272beecb3fffa6a44b49d.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T22:32:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T22:32:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T22:32:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T10:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 12 at 10:32PM EDT until May 13 at 10:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.

* WHERE...A portion of western North Carolina, including the
following counties, Avery and Mitchell.

* WHEN...Until 1015 AM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1012 PM EDT, Rounds of light to moderate rainfall continue
to pivot into western Avery County and central and southern
Mitchell County, following several rounds of light to
moderate rainfall which began early Monday morning.  While
short-term rates have not been significant enough to cause
flash-flood concerns, the Advisory area has seen 2-3.5 inches
since early Monday morning.  This rainfall is beginning to
produce excessive runoff into the following streams and
associated tributaries:

Elk River from Banner Elk to Elk Park;
North Toe River from Newland to Minneapolis to Altamont,
Ingalls, and Spruce Pine;
Grassy Creek near Spruce Pine;
and Cane Creek near Bakersville

Over the next several hours, stream levels are expected to
gradually rise and exceed bankfull levels in several
locations.  Flood-prone areas along these streams are likely
to see developing nuisance flood conditions over the next
several hours.  Areas of imminent concern include along
Grassy Creek south of Spruce Pine along and near NC 226, the
headwaters of the Elk River in Banner Elk near Elk River Club
and along and near NC 184, and the North Toe River from
Newland and points downstream including along Cow Camp Rd and
Old Toe River Rd.

- Rounds of moderate to heavy showers and a few embedded
thunderstorms are possible generally after 10pm as the best
instability moves through the Advisory area.  These showers
and storms may persist for several hours into the overnight.
Given the saturated soils and increasing stream flows,
resultant runoff from this activity may be significant enough
to produce flash flooding.  Therefore, those in the Advisory
area are encouraged to stay weather aware later tonight as a
Flash Flood Warning or two may be needed should those heavier
rainfall rates materialize.  A Flood Watch for flash flooding
remains in effect through 8am Tuesday.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Spruce Pine, Elk Park, Bakersville, Beech Mountain, Ingalls,
Altamont, Minneapolis, and Bandana.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.

Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130232</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 1015 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0026.250513T0232Z-250513T1415Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T10:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Avery, NC; Mitchell, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.13,-82.05 36.12,-82.03 36.28,-81.93 36.28,-81.9 36.24,-81.9 36.24,-81.91 36.1,-81.95 35.88,-81.98 35.87,-82.0 35.89,-82.02 35.86,-82.04 35.85,-82.1 35.82,-82.14 35.93,-82.15 35.93,-82.17 35.95,-82.2 35.96,-82.19 36.02,-82.2 36.1,-82.13 36.1,-82.08 36.13,-82.05</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037121</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC121</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>