<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.c1f2fde14268d660d973a09b128ac0c73625bdbb.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-12T19:49:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-12T19:49:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-12T19:49:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T07:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued May 12 at 7:49PM EDT until May 13 at 7:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Minor to moderate flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
expected.

* WHERE...A portion of western North Carolina, including the
following counties, Avery, Burke, Caldwell and McDowell.

* WHEN...Until 715 AM EDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Common, deeper flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to
area streams is developing with lesser impacts to vulnerable
property. Expect extensive flooding of farmland, parks, greenways,
boat-access areas, and golf courses.  Inundation may be several
feet deep. Other flood-prone areas will be impacted including
low-lying roadways, low-water crossings, underpasses, and parking
lots. Several low-water crossings, roads, and bridges may be
flooded and impassible, with deeper flows over roadways possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 725 PM EDT, Doppler radar indicated moderate to heavy
rainfall have redeveloped over the northern North Carolina
Blue Ridge Escarpment, with another 0.50 inches to 1.5 inches
falling over the past 1-2 hours.  Storm-total rainfall since
early Monday morning is exceeding 3-5 inches across the
Warning area.  Isolated totals of over 6 inches are being
observed, including near Sugar Mountain, Linville Falls, and
Jonas Ridge.

Resultant excessive runoff is causing several areas of
nuisance to Minor flooding across the Warning area, including
along the Linville River near Linville, Pineola, and
Crossnore, the North Toe River near Newland, Elk River near
Banner Elk, and Wilson Creek from Edgemont to Adako Rd.
Steady rises along these and other streams, including Warrior
Fork in northwestern Burke County, North Fork Catawba River
in northeastern McDowell County, and Johns River in western
Caldwell County and northern Burke County, will continue well
into the late evening and early overnight hours.  As a
result, additional areas of nuisance to Minor flooding are
expected to develop.  Isolated areas of Moderate flooding,
capable of threatening primary roadways and structures,
cannot be ruled out over the next several hours as flood
conditions continue to worsen.  Individuals near streams
should move away from streams and take action to protect life
and property.

High flows will gradually work downstream into Johns River
later this evening into the early morning hours on Tuesday,
where Minor flooding is likely.  High flows into the upper
Catwaba River reservoirs are also likely through tomorrow
morning.

- Because of the prolonged accumulation of steady rainfall and
the fact that it has taken well over six-to-eight hours for
streams to approach Minor Flood Stage, a Flood Warning has
been issued.  However, additional rounds of moderate to heavy
showers and a few embedded thunderstorms are possible later
tonight into early Tuesday morning. Given the potential for
heavy rainfall rates with these showers and storms on top of
saturated soils and elevated stream flows, resultant runoff
from this activity may be significant enough to produce
considerable flash flooding, with the potential to impact
several roadways and structures.  Therefore, those in the
Warning area are encouraged to stay weather aware later
tonight as a Flash Flood Warning or two may be needed should
those heavier rainfall rates materialize.  A Flood Watch for
flash flooding remains in effect through 8am Tuesday.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance, Minor, and/or
Moderate flooding include...
Newland, Banner Elk, Crossnore, Sugar Mountain, Seven Devils,
Table Rock, Linville Falls, Lake James State Park, Jonas
Ridge, Edgemont, Pineola, Linville, Ashford and Globe.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.

Heavy rain is increasing the risk of landslides, especially in areas
where slides have occurred in the past. Be especially alert if you
are near a stream, especially at the base of a mountain or in a
cove. Watch for loose-moving soil and rocks or a sudden increase in
streamflow. Leave the area quickly if this is observed. When driving
along roads where the terrain is steep or rocky, watch and listen
for falling rocks, mud, trees, and other debris.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLWGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS42 KGSP 122349</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT UNTIL 715 AM EDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.W.0001.250512T2349Z-250513T1115Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T07:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Avery, NC; Burke, NC; Caldwell, NC; McDowell, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.89,-81.98 35.92,-81.97 36.1,-81.95 36.24,-81.91 36.24,-81.9 36.23,-81.91 36.22,-81.91 36.19,-81.89 36.19,-81.86 36.17,-81.83 36.11,-81.81 36.12,-81.66 35.99,-81.67 35.93,-81.64 35.85,-81.64 35.78,-81.73 35.72,-81.88 35.85,-82.05 35.88,-82.01 35.87,-82.0 35.89,-81.98</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037027</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037111</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC027</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC111</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>