<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.13a5b15267b6b0415b6d13ef879f7c0e269373b7.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-11T03:56:00-06:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-11T03:56:00-06:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-11T14:00:00-06:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-11T16:00:00-06:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS El Paso Tx/Santa Teresa NM</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Watch issued October 11 at 3:56AM MDT until October 12 at 6:00PM MDT by NWS El Paso Tx/Santa Teresa NM</headline>
        <description>Moisture from the remnants of former Tropical Storm Priscilla will
mostly stay north and west of the area today. But increasing
moisture from the remnants of Tropical Storm Raymond will get pulled
into the area this afternoon and interact with a slow-moving upper
level trough, possibly lasting through Monday. Expect increasing
showers and thunderstorms in Southwestern New Mexico this afternoon
and overnight, with localized torrential downpours. Additional bouts
of tropical showers and isolated thunderstorms will continue on
Sunday, especially in the Bootheel Region. Rain coverage in the Gila
Region is a little less certain on Sunday. Additional rainfall is
possible on Monday, and this Flood Watch may need to be extended
later as forecasts come into sharper focus.

* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is possible.

* WHERE...Portions of southwestern New Mexico, including the
Bootheel Region, all of Hidalgo County, and southern Grant County.

* WHEN...From 2 PM MDT this afternoon through Sunday afternoon.

* IMPACTS...The risk of localized flash flooding will mainly be this
afternoon and overnight Saturday night, as thunderstorms with
torrential downpours develop. Flooding is possible in arroyos, low
water crossings, and low-lying areas with poor drainage. This will
be followed by more moderate rainfall rates on Sunday, mainly
focused over the Bootheel Region. While tributary arroyo flows may
diminish on Sunday, some of the slower-reacting main washes, such
as Animas Creek, may continue to flood, and could cut off access
to some rural roads in the Bootheel.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFAEPZ</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS64 KEPZ 110956</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WATCH IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM MDT THIS AFTERNOON THROUGH SUNDAY AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KEPZ.FA.A.0014.251011T2000Z-251013T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-12T18:00:00-06:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southwest Desert/Lower Gila River Valley; Lowlands of the Bootheel; Uplands of the Bootheel</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>035017</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>035023</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NMZ404</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NMZ405</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NMZ406</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>