<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 25 Dec 2022 02:54:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA12641EEF3F78.HydrologicOutlook.12641EF17450CA.MTRESFMTR.27ac3de1c2d1a062ca2d5588e8e4263a</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-24T18:54:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Alameda; Contra Costa; Monterey; Napa; San Benito; San Francisco; San Mateo; Santa Clara; Santa Cruz (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-24T18:54:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-25T09:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued December 24 at 6:54PM PST  by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>...Moderate to heavy rain will cause rapid rises along rivers and
streams late Monday through Tuesday...
...Additional storms will bring periods of wet weather through
the remainder of the year...
* WHAT...A significant winter storm will impact the region late
Monday into Tuesday, with showers lingering into Wednesday. This
potent system is tapping into a very moist subtropical plume,
which will allow for moderate, to periods of heavy,
precipitation. Precipitation will begin in the North Bay on
Monday, becoming moderate to heavy late Monday night, then
spreading south across the region during the day on Tuesday.
Rainfall totals will range from 1 to 3 inches, with higher
elevations receiving upward of 3 to 5 inches. Locally up to 7
inches are possible over favored peaks and higher terrain of the
Sonoma Coastal Range where prolonged moderate to heavy
precipitation and higher rain rates are currently forecast.
Moderate to heavy rain will lead to rapid rises of area rivers,
streams, and creeks. This system will result in an increased
risk of mudslides and debris flow over wildfire burn areas.
Localized ponding of water in low-lying or poorly drained areas
as well as localized flooding is possible due to blocked
culverts, drainages, and storm drains. Main stem rivers are
presently forecast to remain below flood stage, but may rise
above monitor stage.
* WHERE...Entire forecast area from Napa and Sonoma counties south
through Monterey and San Benito counties. Latest model guidance
suggests the North Bay Mountains, the coastal slopes of the
Santa Cruz Mountains and Santa Lucia Mountains above Big Sur
will most likely receive the greatest accumulation of
precipitation.
* WHEN...Monday night through Tuesday with greatest impacts
expected Monday night and Tuesday morning. Showers will linger
through Wednesday, with runoff expected to continue.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...There is a concern for mud, rock, and
debris flows that may occur across burn areas. In addition,
strong and gusty winds are expected late Monday night and
Tuesday. Debris from gusty winds may cause drainage blockages
which could create a localized flooding threat, especially in
mountainous terrain. Localized ponding of water is likely in
low-lying or poorly drained areas, such as freeway offramps.
While no mainstem river flooding is forecast at this time,
mainstream rivers will see rapid rises, and may exceed monitor
stage. The Carmel Lagoon could also see a rapid rise. Roadways
will be extra slick and roadway ponding is likely. Please
monitor the latest forecast for the most up to date weather
information. Confidence is high that we will receive widespread
rainfall from this system.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC001-013-053-055-069-075-081-085-087</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Alameda; Contra Costa; Monterey; Napa; San Benito; San Francisco; San Mateo; Santa Clara; Santa Cruz</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC087</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>