<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.73f152e6f1193deff9250a52c2dcfe52df9ae5c3.001.4</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-14T19:56:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8fd12a375ee71a9ee3e9ac6a54c01bf562a3f4ea.001.2,2025-09-14T16:10:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>High Surf Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-14T19:56:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-15T02:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-15T08:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>High Surf Advisory issued September 14 at 7:56PM EDT until September 15 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, 1 to 2 feet of
inundation above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous
rip currents, large breaking waves expected, and strong
longshore currents in the surf zone. For the High Surf Advisory,
large breaking waves of 5 to 10 feet expected in the surf zone.

* WHERE...Northern Outer Banks and Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 8 PM EDT Tuesday.
For the Beach Hazards Statement, through Monday evening. For
the High Surf Advisory, from 2 AM to 8 PM EDT Monday.

* IMPACTS...Flooding of lots, parks, and roads with only isolated
road closures expected. Dangerous swimming and surfing
conditions and localized beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep
even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper water.
Dangerous shore break can throw a swimmer or surfer head first
into the bottom causing neck and back injuries. Strong longshore
currents will create dangerous swimming conditions.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 8:00 AM Monday.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.

Strong longshore currents can sweep swimmers and surfers into rip
currents, piers, jetties and other hazardous areas. In many
cases, the longshore current is strong enough to prevent swimmers
from being able to keep their feet on the bottom making it
difficult to return to shore.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 142356</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT TUESDAY... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT THROUGH MONDAY EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 2 AM TO 8 PM EDT MONDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KMHX.SU.Y.0007.250915T0600Z-250916T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-09-15T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Outer Banks; Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>