<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a4ecc89cfbf568f5a43f7e907d7ee32769dd03de.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-05T23:31:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-05T23:31:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-05T23:31:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-06T07:45:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Charleston SC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 5 at 11:31PM EDT by NWS Charleston SC</headline>
        <description>HLSCHS

This product covers southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia

**CHANTAL STRENGTHENING AS IT DRAWS CLOSER TO THE SOUTH CAROLINA
COAST**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Charleston

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 70 miles east of Charleston SC
- 32.7N 78.8W
- Storm Intensity 50 mph
- Movement North or 350 degrees at 8 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Storm Chantal continues to gradually strengthen as it
moves northward toward the South Carolina coast. The center of Chantal
is forecast to move onshore north of the Santee River early Sunday
morning.

Through the overnight, Chantal will produce a few limited impacts
across southeast South Carolina, primarily along the coast. Gusty
winds will continue to occur along the Charleston County coast,
especially from around Charleston to McClellanville. Also, clusters of
rain showers will continue to pass through the area, with the bulk of
the activity being limited to eastern Berkeley and upper Charleston
counties. Additional rainfall amounts of up to an inch will be
possible in these areas. Finally other coastal hazards will persist
including an elevated risk of rip currents, high surf with breaking
waves of 4 to 6 feet, and beach erosion.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
coastal Charleston County. Remain well sheltered from hazardous
wind having limited impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or uprooted,
but with greater numbers in places where trees are shallow
rooted.
- Some roads impassable due to debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded locations. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways, especially for high
profile vehicles.
- Isolated to scattered power and communications outages.

Elsewhere across southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia,
little to no impact is anticipated.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
eastern Berkeley County and upper Charleston County. Remain well
guarded against locally hazardous flood waters having limited impacts.
If realized, these impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding could prompt a few rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries could quickly rise with swifter
currents. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches could
become swollen and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter a few structures, especially in normally
vulnerable spots. Rapid ponding of water could occur at
underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage areas. Several
storm drains and retention ponds become near-full and begin to
overflow. Some brief road and bridge closures.

Elsewhere across southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia,
little to no impact is anticipated.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
High surf will continue along the Charleston County coast. Also, an
elevated risk of rip currents will persist along the entire southeast
South Carolina and southeast Georgia coast.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Charleston SC around 5 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSCHS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KCHS 060331</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>CHANTAL STRENGTHENING AS IT DRAWS CLOSER TO THE SOUTH CAROLINA
COAST</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Berkeley; Charleston; Tidal Berkeley</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ050</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ052</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>