<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b63a08b6ae7683c0b96f8ba3e22c889e146283ac.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-05T23:12:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-05T23:12:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-05T23:12:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-06T07:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wilmington NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 5 at 11:12PM EDT by NWS Wilmington NC</headline>
        <description>HLSILM

This product covers southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina

**TROPICAL STORM CHANTAL WILL APPROACH THE SOUTH CAROLINA COAST
TONIGHT**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Central Horry,
Coastal Brunswick, Coastal Georgetown, Coastal Horry, Coastal
New Hanover, Coastal Pender, and Inland Georgetown

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 120 miles south-southwest of Wilmington NC or about 70
miles south of Myrtle Beach SC
- 32.7N 78.8W
- Storm Intensity 50 mph
- Movement North or 350 degrees at 8 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Storm Chantal will approach the South Carolina coast
tonight, strengthening slightly before landfall. The main impact for
the Carolinas will be locally heavy rainfall with potential for
isolated flooding tonight through Sunday. Strong rip currents and
dangerous surf are also expected. Hazardous surf conditions will
continue through early next week.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across southeast North Carolina and coastal areas
of northeast South Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- Moderate flooding from rainfall may prompt some evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rise and overspill their banks in a few
places, especially in the typical prone locations. Small creeks
and ditches may overflow.
- Flood waters may enter some structures. Underpasses, low-lying
spots along roadways, and poor drainage areas may become
submerged by rising water. Some secondary streets and parking
lots may flood as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
- Driving conditions will become hazardous, and some road
closures can be expected.

Protect against locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across northeast South Carolina and the Pee Dee region.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Life-threatening rip currents possible at all area beaches Saturday and
Sunday. High surf forecasted for the beaches of northeast SC and Brunswick
county through Sunday, with breaking wave heights of six feet likely and
minor beach erosion possible.

* SURGE:
Protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
along the coastline of southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation and minor overwash are possible, mainly
along immediate shorelines and other vulnerable low-lying areas
along the coast. Low spots along waterways and tidal creeks may
also be impacted.
- Some portions of near-shore roads and parking lots may become
covered by surge water. Driving conditions may become hazardous
in places where the surge covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion is possible, mainly in vulnerable
locations along the oceanfront.
- Minor damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers is
possible. A few small craft may break away from moorings if not
properly secured.
- Navigation may be difficult near inlets and waterways, as
navigational aids may be off station or missing.

Elsewhere across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina, little to no impact is anticipated.

* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina. Potential
impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes is possible. Unsecured lightweight objects may be
blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted or
weak trees may snap or be knocked down. Some fences and roadway
signs will be damaged.
- A few roads may become impassable due to debris, particularly
within urban or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving
conditions are possible, especially for high profile vehicles
on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.

* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina.
Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder preparedness
actions during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Tornadoes can cause damage to trees, vehicles, boats, and
buildings. Unsecured mobile homes and poorly constructed
structures are particularly vulnerable.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to bring to completion all preparations to protect
life and property in accordance with your emergency plan.

Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.

Check-in with your emergency points of contact among family, friends,
and workmates. Inform them of your status and well-being. Let them
know how you intend to ride out the storm and when you plan to
check-in again.

Keep cell phones well charged and handy. Also, cell phone chargers
for automobiles can be helpful after the storm. Locate your chargers
and keep them with your cell phone.

In emergencies it is best to remain calm. Stay informed and focused
on the situation at hand. Exercise patience with those you encounter.
Be a Good Samaritan and helpful to others.

If relocating to a nearby shelter or to the home of a family member
or friend, drive with extra caution, especially on secondary roads.
Remember, many bridges and causeways will be closed once higher winds
arrive. Also, if you encounter water covering the road, seek an
alternate route. Always obey official road signs for closures and
detours.

If you are a visitor and still in the area, listen for the name of
the city or town in which you are staying within local news updates.
Be sure you know the name of the county or parish in which it
resides. Pay attention for instructions from local authorities.

Closely monitor NOAA Weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes to
the forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Wilmington NC around 6 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSILM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KILM 060312</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM CHANTAL WILL APPROACH THE SOUTH CAROLINA COAST
TONIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Pender; Coastal Pender; Inland New Hanover; Coastal New Hanover; Inland Brunswick; Coastal Brunswick; Coastal Horry; Inland Georgetown; Coastal Georgetown; Central Horry; Northern Horry</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037141</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037129</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ105</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ106</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ107</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ108</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ109</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ054</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ059</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>