<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7d80cd6edc0f28b90ff5b551ab7c049f7395d256.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-05T04:53:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.80a04482f2795a3eb907a325b6df39287b90763b.001.1,2025-07-04T22:40:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>TRA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-05T04:53:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-05T04:53:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-05T13:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wilmington NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued July 5 at 4:53AM EDT by NWS Wilmington NC</headline>
        <description>* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Surfside Beach
- Myrtle Beach
- North Myrtle Beach

* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Below tropical storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 25-35 mph with gusts to 45 mph

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- The wind threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Efforts to protect property should now be
underway. Prepare for limited wind damage.
- ACT: Act now to complete preparations before the wind
becomes hazardous.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes is possible. Unsecured lightweight objects may
be blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted
or weak trees may snap or be knocked down. Some fences and
roadway signs will be damaged.
- A few roads may become impassable due to debris,
particularly within urban or heavily wooded places.
Hazardous driving conditions are possible, especially for
high profile vehicles on bridges and other elevated
roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.

* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Localized storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for up to 2 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: through this evening

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 1 foot above ground
- The storm surge threat has increased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for storm surge flooding greater than 1 foot
above ground.
- PREPARE: Complete preparations for storm surge flooding,
especially in low-lying vulnerable areas, before conditions
become unsafe.
- ACT: Leave immediately if evacuation orders are given for
your area.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Localized inundation and minor overwash are possible,
mainly along immediate shorelines and other vulnerable
low-lying areas along the coast. Low spots along waterways
and tidal creeks may also be impacted.
- Some portions of near-shore roads and parking lots may
become covered by surge water. Driving conditions may
become hazardous in places where the surge covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion is possible, mainly in vulnerable
locations along the oceanfront.
- Minor damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers is
possible. A few small craft may break away from moorings if
not properly secured.
- Navigation may be difficult near inlets and waterways, as
navigational aids may be off station or missing.

* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: Additional 3-6 inches, with locally
higher amounts

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
moderate flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has increased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
moderate flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues
are possible.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action may result in serious injury or loss of life.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Moderate flooding from rainfall may prompt some evacuations
and rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rise and overspill their banks in a
few places, especially in the typical prone locations.
Small creeks and ditches may overflow.
- Flood waters may enter some structures. Underpasses,
low-lying spots along roadways, and poor drainage areas may
become submerged by rising water. Some secondary streets
and parking lots may flood as storm drains and retention
ponds overflow.
- Driving conditions will become hazardous, and some road
closures can be expected.

* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is unfavorable for tornadoes

- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Tornadoes not expected
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Tornadoes are not expected. Showers and thunderstorms
with gusty winds may still occur.
- PREPARE: Little to no preparations needed to protect
against tornadoes at this time. Keep informed of the latest
tornado situation.
- ACT: Listen for changes in the forecast.

- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Little to None
- Little to no potential impacts from tornadoes.

* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://www.weather.gov/ilm/tropical
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes
- http://scemd.org
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>TCVILM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KILM 050853</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KILM.TR.A.1003.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0fda04de3b38e3787d06bf6e53fbf0e1e9647119.001.1,2025-07-04T17:32:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Coastal Horry</areaDesc>
            <polygon>33.848,-78.538 33.840,-78.597 33.833,-78.606 33.805,-78.704 33.764,-78.772 33.749,-78.795 33.699,-78.865 33.572,-78.997 33.572,-79.101 33.610,-79.100 33.611,-79.104 33.601,-79.109 33.606,-79.120 33.739,-78.950 33.832,-78.803 33.852,-78.760 33.903,-78.602 33.848,-78.538</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ054</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>