<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0d356ddfbd7180f52a3f34b897c1b519c4e5b0ef.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-05T17:08:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-05T17:08:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-05T17:08:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-06T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Charleston SC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 5 at 5:08PM EDT by NWS Charleston SC</headline>
        <description>HLSCHS

This product covers southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia

**CHANTAL MOVING CLOSER TO THE COAST OF SOUTH CAROLINA**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Charleston

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 90 miles southeast of Charleston SC or about 140 miles
east of Savannah GA
- 31.9N 78.7W
- Storm Intensity 45 mph
- Movement North or 360 degrees at 7 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Storm Chantal will meander closer to the Southeast U.S.
coast this evening, making landfall along the middle and upper South
Carolina coast overnight or early Sunday morning.

As Chantal nears the coast, breezy northwest winds will occur as the
system interacts with high pressure to the north. Wind gusts are
forecast to remain the strongest along the South Carolina beaches,
with gusts around 40 mph possible. In addition, wind gusts across the
elevated bridges around the Charleston Metro area may exceed 45 mph at
times today.

Rain bands will continue to push onshore along the coast of the South
Carolina Lowcountry into tonight. These bands may drift slowly inland
as the system nears the coast bringing as much as 1 to 2 inches of
rain. The rain may become locally heavy at times, resulting in
flooding, mainly in low-lying and poor drainage areas. Widespread
flash flooding is unlikely at this time.

Nearing landfall, there is a chance of waterspouts forming within
these rainbands over the nearshore Charleston waters and potentially
moving onshore over extreme northern Charleston County through tonight
into Sunday morning.

Gusty winds and building waves will result in strong rip currents
along the South Carolina and Georgia coast through this weekend. In
addition, beach erosion and high surf with breakers of 4 to 6 feet
could occur along the beaches of Charleston County.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
Charleston County. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or uprooted,
but with greater numbers in places where trees are shallow
rooted.
- Some roads impassable due to debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded locations. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways, especially for high
profile vehicles.
- Isolated to scattered power and communications outages.

Elsewhere across southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia,
little to no impact is anticipated.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across the South Carolina Lowcountry. Potential
impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding could prompt a few rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries could quickly rise with swifter
currents. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches could
become swollen and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter a few structures, especially in normally
vulnerable spots. Rapid ponding of water could occur at
underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage areas. Several
storm drains and retention ponds become near-full and begin to
overflow. Some brief road and bridge closures.

Elsewhere across southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia,
little to no impact is anticipated.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Gusty winds and increasing wave activity will result in strong rip
currents and high surf along the South Carolina and Georgia coasts
through this weekend.

* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
extreme northern Charleston County. Potential impacts include:
- Isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution of emergency plans.
- Isolated locations could experience tornado damage, along with
power and communications disruptions.
- In isolated locations, tornadoes could damage trees, vehicles,
boats and buildings, especially mobile homes and other poorly
constructed structures.

Elsewhere across southeast South Carolina and southeast Georgia,
little to no impact is anticipated.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* EVACUATIONS:
Follow the advice of local officials.

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.

Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Charleston SC around 11 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSCHS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KCHS 052108</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>CHANTAL MOVING CLOSER TO THE COAST OF SOUTH CAROLINA</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hampton; Inland Colleton; Dorchester; Inland Berkeley; Inland Jasper; Beaufort; Coastal Colleton; Charleston; Coastal Jasper; Tidal Berkeley</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045049</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045029</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045035</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045053</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045013</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ042</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ044</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ047</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ048</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ049</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ050</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ052</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>