<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.9b01040268b47742031ba1a8e41018d3488df70d.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-05T05:05:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-05T05:05:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-05T05:05:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-05T13:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wilmington NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 5 at 5:05AM EDT by NWS Wilmington NC</headline>
        <description>HLSILM

This product covers southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina

**TROPICAL DEPRESSION THREE WILL APPROACH SOUTH CAROLINA COAST TONIGHT**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch has been issued for Coastal Brunswick

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Coastal Brunswick,
Coastal Georgetown, and Coastal Horry

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 240 miles south of Wilmington NC or about 200 miles south
of Myrtle Beach SC
- 30.8N 78.6W
- Storm Intensity 35 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 2 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Depression Three will approach the South Carolina coast
tonight, strengthening into a tropical storm before landfall. The
largest impact on the Carolinas should be locally heavy rainfall with
potential for isolated flooding Saturday night through Sunday.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible significant
impacts east of I-95. Potential impacts include:
- Moderate flooding from rainfall may prompt some evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rise and overspill their banks in a few
places, especially in the typical prone locations. Small creeks
and ditches may overflow.
- Flood waters may enter some structures. Underpasses, low-lying
spots along roadways, and poor drainage areas may become
submerged by rising water. Some secondary streets and parking
lots may flood as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
- Driving conditions will become hazardous, and some road
closures can be expected.

Prepare for locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts along and west of I-95.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Life-threatening rip currents possible at all area beaches Saturday and
Sunday. High surf forecasted for the beaches of northeast SC and Brunswick
county Saturday through Sunday, with breaking wave heights of six
feet likely and minor beach erosion possible.

* WIND:
Prepare for hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across coastal
northeast SC and coastal Brunswick. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes is possible. Unsecured lightweight objects may be
blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted or
weak trees may snap or be knocked down. Some fences and roadway
signs will be damaged.
- A few roads may become impassable due to debris, particularly
within urban or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving
conditions are possible, especially for high profile vehicles
on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.

Elsewhere across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina, little to no impact is anticipated.

* SURGE:
Prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited impacts
across coastal northeast SC and coastal Brunswick. Potential impacts in
this area include:
- Localized inundation and minor overwash are possible, mainly
along immediate shorelines and other vulnerable low-lying areas
along the coast. Low spots along waterways and tidal creeks may
also be impacted.
- Some portions of near-shore roads and parking lots may become
covered by surge water. Driving conditions may become hazardous
in places where the surge covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion is possible, mainly in vulnerable
locations along the oceanfront.
- Minor damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers is
possible. A few small craft may break away from moorings if not
properly secured.
- Navigation may be difficult near inlets and waterways, as
navigational aids may be off station or missing.

Elsewhere across southeast North Carolina and northeast South
Carolina, little to no impact is anticipated.

* TORNADOES:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across southeast
North Carolina and northeast South Carolina.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track as there are inherent forecast uncertainties
which must be taken into account.

If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low lying or poor
drainage area, plan to move to safe shelter on higher ground

Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any orders
that are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives
of others.

Closely monitor NOAA Weather Radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for possible changes to the
forecast.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Wilmington NC around 12 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSILM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KILM 050905</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL DEPRESSION THREE WILL APPROACH SOUTH CAROLINA COAST TONIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Brunswick; Coastal Brunswick; Coastal Horry; Inland Georgetown; Coastal Georgetown; Central Horry; Northern Horry</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ109</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ054</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ059</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>