<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5bd27efbec8e35666215f529728fb82f633734f1.002.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-26T00:50:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Lake Effect Snow Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Extreme</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>LEW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-26T00:50:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-27T01:00:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-26T09:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Cleveland OH</senderName>
        <headline>Lake Effect Snow Warning issued November 26 at 12:50AM EST until November 29 at 1:00AM EST by NWS Cleveland OH</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Heavy lake effect snow expected. Total snow accumulations
between 8 and 16 inches. Highest accumulations are expected across
the northern portion of the county. Winds gusting as high as 45
mph.

* WHERE...Crawford County.

* WHEN...From 1 AM Thursday to 1 AM EST Saturday.

* IMPACTS...Roads, and especially bridges and overpasses, will
likely become slick and hazardous. Visibilities may drop below 1/4
mile due to falling and blowing snow. The strong winds may down
power lines and could cause sporadic power outages. Whiteout
conditions are expected and will make travel difficult to
impossible. The hazardous conditions will impact busy Thanksgiving
holiday travel.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Heavy lake effect snow will push inland
Thursday morning. Intensity of snowbands is expected to increase
throughout the day when snow may quickly accumulate on untreated
surfaces. Snowfall rates may exceed 1 inch per hour at times on
Thursday.
</description>
        <instruction>If you must travel, keep an extra flashlight, food, and water in
your vehicle in case of an emergency.

The Pennsylvania Department of Transportation and Pennsylvania
Turnpike Commission strongly encourage motorists to heed all travel
restrictions and delay unnecessary travel. Visit www.511pa.com for
the latest travel, roadway, and traffic conditions.

Persons should delay all travel if possible. If travel is absolutely
necessary, drive with extreme caution and be prepared for sudden
changes in visibility. Leave plenty of room between you and the
motorist ahead of you, and allow extra time to reach your
destination. Avoid sudden braking or acceleration, and be especially
cautious on hills or when making turns. Make sure your car is
winterized and in good working order.

During lake effect snow, the weather can vary from bands of locally
heavy snow to dry weather just a few miles away. Visibilities can
also vary greatly. Be prepared for rapid changes in weather,
visibility, and road conditions.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWCLE</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS41 KCLE 260550</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>LAKE EFFECT SNOW WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 1 AM THURSDAY TO 1 AM EST SATURDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXA.KCLE.LE.W.0006.251127T0600Z-251129T0600Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-29T01:00:00-05:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Crawford</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>042039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>PAZ003</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>