<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.590a061025f56c0a3242cbbcf57d81c7aed694ff.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-27T12:54:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-27T12:54:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-27T12:54:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-29T00:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS San Diego CA</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued November 27 at 12:54PM PST by NWS San Diego CA</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The South Coast AQMD has issued a mandatory wood-burning
ban for residents in the South Coast Air Basin. The No-Burn rule
bans burning wood, pellets, and manufactured fire logs in any indoor
or outdoor wood-burning device.

* WHERE...The South Coast Air Basin, which includes Orange County
and non-desert portions of Los Angeles, Riverside, and San
Bernardino counties. No-Burn Day alerts do not apply to areas above
3,000 feet in elevation, the Coachella Valley, or the High Desert.
Homes that rely on wood as a sole source of heat, low-income
households and those without natural gas service also are exempt
from the requirement.

* WHEN...midnight to midnight on Friday.

* IMPACTS...Particles in smoke can get deep into the lungs and cause
health problems (including asthma attacks), increases in emergency
room visits, and hospitalizations. No-Burn Days are needed to
protect public health when fine particle pollution levels are
expected to be high anywhere in the South Coast Air Basin. No-Burn
Days are based on fine particle pollution levels that are forecasted
for an entire 24-hour period, which may not be reflected in
real-time air quality maps.
</description>
        <instruction>To protect your health, check current and forecasted air quality
levels at www.aqmd.gov or download the mobile app at
www.aqmd.gov/mobileapp. When air quality is poor in your area,
limited extended or intense outdoor activity and remain inside with
windows and doors closed. Run your air conditioner and/or an air
purifier and avoid using devices that bring in outside air like a
swamp cooler or whole house fan if you have other ways to stay cool.

Additional details for this air quality alert are available at
www.aqmd.gov/advisory. Information on the South Coast AQMD Check
Before You Burn program is available at www.aqmd.gov/cbyb.

For the latest air quality forecasts and information, visit the
website at aqmd.gov.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQASGX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS76 KSGX 272054</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT: MANDATORY WOOD-BURNING BAN IN EFFECT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>San Bernardino and Riverside County Valleys-The Inland Empire; Riverside County Mountains; San Gorgonio Pass Near Banning; Orange County Coastal; Orange County Inland</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006059</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ048</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ552</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ554</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>