<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 17 Sep 2022 12:30:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-VI12640C9332F8.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640C94659CVI.JSJHLSSJU.9168991cccb5b53ea133039c6c9fed6b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-16T20:30:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for St Croix; St.Thomas...St. John.. and Adjacent Islands (Virgin Islands) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-16T18:01:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-17T04:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS San Juan (San Juan, Puerto Rico)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 16 at 8:30PM AST  by NWS San Juan</headline>
<description>This product covers Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands
**CENTER OF FIONA VERY NEAR GUADELOUPE**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Central Interior,
Culebra, Eastern Interior, Mayaguez and Vicinity, North
Central, Northeast, Northwest, Ponce and Vicinity, San Juan and
Vicinity, Southeast, Southwest, St Croix, St.Thomas...St.
John...and Adjacent Islands, Vieques, and Western Interior
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 320 miles east-southeast of San Juan PR or about 230
miles east-southeast of Saint Croix VI
- 16.5N 61.5W
- Storm Intensity 50 mph
- Movement West or 280 degrees at 15 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Fiona is near the Lesser Antilles, as detected on the Guadeloupe
Radar. Thunderstorms and heavy rain are now affecting Guadeloupe and
surrounding waters and will move into the Northeast Caribbean later
tonight. Tropical storm conditions are likely across the U.S. Virgin
Islands as early as early Saturday morning and in Puerto Rico as early
as Saturday morning. At 8 PM AST (00Z UTC), the center of Tropical
Storm Fiona was located about 320 miles east-southeast of San Juan, or
about 230 miles east-southeast of St. Croix. On the latest National
Hurricane Center track forecast, the center of Fiona is expected to
move near or just south of the U.S. Virgin Islands and Puerto Rico
Saturday into Sunday. The main threat with this system remains the
rainfall, which will persist through the weekend into early next week,
with overall, multi-day totals in excess of 4-8 inches for some areas
around the local islands, including a forecast for 8 to 12 inches for
southeastern and southwestern Puerto Rico. This amount of rainfall will
result in life-threatening flash and urban flooding, as well as
mudslides or rockfalls and river flooding. The greatest threat for
these dangerous flooding conditions is Saturday through at least
Monday. Marine and coastal conditions are also forecast to deteriorate,
starting as early as this evening. Seas building to around 15 feet are
forecast, continuing through the weekend. Maximum sustained winds to
near 60 mph with higher gusts are expected for portions of the forecast
area.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across eastern and southern Puerto Rico. Potential
impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, arroyos, and
ditches may become dangerous rivers. In mountain areas,
destructive runoff may run quickly down valleys while
increasing susceptibility to rockslides and mudslides. Flood
control systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible significant
impacts across the rest of the region.
* WIND:
Prepare for dangerous wind having possible significant impacts across
Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential impacts include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent
in areas with above ground lines.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
* SURGE:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across Puerto
Rico and the US Virgin Islands. Potential impacts in this area
include:
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
- If you are exceptionally vulnerable to wind or water hazards from
tropical systems, consider voluntary evacuation, especially if being
officially recommended. Relocate to a predetermined shelter or safe
destination.
- If evacuating away from the area or relocating to a nearby shelter,
leave early before weather conditions become hazardous.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to bring to completion all preparations to protect
life and property in accordance with your emergency plan.
Outside preparations should be wrapped up as soon as possible before
weather conditions completely deteriorate. Any remaining evacuations
and relocations should be expedited before the onset of tropical
storm force wind.
If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible. If
heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or own a
pet. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.
Check the latest weather forecast before departing.
Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.
Check-in with your emergency points of contact among family, friends,
and workmates. Inform them of your status and well-being. Let them
know how you intend to ride out the storm and when you plan to
check-in again.
Keep cell phones well charged and handy. Also, cell phone chargers
for automobiles can be helpful after the storm. Locate your chargers
and keep them with your cell phone.
If you are a visitor and still in the area, listen for the name of the
city or town in which you are staying within local news updates. Be
sure you know the name of the county or parish in which it resides. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.
Closely monitor NOAA Weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes to
the forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in San Juan PR around 11 PM AST, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PRZ001>013-VIZ001-002</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>St Croix; St.Thomas...St. John.. and Adjacent Islands</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>078030</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VIZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>VIZ002</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>