<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 12 Dec 2021 04:41:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA1261CA1F1C04.FlashFloodWatch.1261CA3C7F10CA.MTRFFAMTR.3a1741fe20330406c158cc0756ea4b4b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2021-12-12T08:41:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Santa Lucia Mountains and Los Padres National Forest; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flash Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FFA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2021-12-12T20:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2021-12-14T01:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Flash Flood Watch issued December 12 at 8:41AM PST until December 14 at 1:00AM PST by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>.Heavy rainfall is forecast to fall over the Dolan burn scar and the
broader Santa Lucia region beginning this evening and continuing
through late Monday night. Rain rates in excess of established
thresholds could trigger debris flow movement over the Dolan burn
scar as well as lead to other localized flooding in the vicinity of
the region.  Soils will not saturated immediately and there may be a
delayed flooding or debris flow response to the heaviest rain as
runoff increases. Rain rates will taper off through Monday night but
additional rain showers may persist into early Tuesday.
...FLASH FLOOD WATCH FOR THE DOLAN BURN AREA IN EFFECT FROM 8 PM PST
THIS EVENING THROUGH LATE MONDAY NIGHT...
* WHAT...Flash flooding and debris flows caused by excessive
rainfall are possible over the Dolan burn area.
* WHERE...A portion of northern California, including the following
areas, Santa Lucia Mountains and Los Padres National Forest and
Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast.
* WHEN...From 8 PM PST this evening through late Monday night.
* IMPACTS...Heavy rainfall over the Dolan burn area is expected up
to and during the period of the watch. Residents near the Dolan
burn area should prepare for potential flooding impacts. Be sure
to stay up to date with information from local authorities. Heavy
rainfall could trigger flash flooding of creeks, low-lying areas,
and debris flows in and near recent wildfire burn scars. Soils may
become saturated and excessive runoff may result in flooding of
rivers, creeks, streams, and other low-lying and flood-prone
locations.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- National Weather Service Meteorologists are forecasting heavy
rainfall over the Dolan burn area, which may lead to flash
flooding and debris flows.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood</description>
<instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be prepared to take action
should Flash Flood Warnings be issued.
Local emergency services are monitoring the situation and will issue
a public statement as conditions warrant. PLAN NOW so you will know
what to do in an emergency. Keep informed by listening to local
radio and television for statements and possible warnings. Follow
the advice of public safety officials.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ517-530</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KMTR.FF.A.0004.211213T0400Z-211214T0900Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Santa Lucia Mountains and Los Padres National Forest; Southern Monterey Bay and Big Sur Coast</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ517</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ530</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>