<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 13 Sep 2022 10:16:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-AK12640C597FE0.SpecialWeatherStatement.12640C74F6BCAK.AFGSPSWCZ.f7cdd8f979fc3f941edd9a639abcfe08</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-13T14:16:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Eastern Norton Sound and Nulato Hills; Southern Seward Peninsula Coast; St Lawrence Island and Bering Strait Coast; Yukon Delta (Alaska) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-13T14:16:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-14T18:15:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Fairbanks (Northern Alaska - Fairbanks)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued September 13 at 2:16PM AKDT  by NWS Fairbanks</headline>
<description>A series of low pressure systems will impact the West Coast with
strong winds, heavy rain and coastal flooding beginning late
Wednesday and continuing through Saturday.
The first and weakest of these Bering Sea storms is a 975 mb low
that will move into the Bering Sea to be located 150 nm southwest
of St Lawrence Island low Thursday morning. This will bring a
round of rain and gusty winds to the YK Delta and late Wednesday
night and Thursday The rain and wind will push north into Norton
Sound and the Seward Peninsula Thursday and Thursday night. This
storm will bring elevated water levels in the 1 to 2 foot range
above the normal high tide levels along south and west facing
coastlines from Hooper Bay to the Bering Strait late Wednesday
and through the day on Thursday.
The second low is forecasted to be a very strong storm with the
remnants of Tropical Storm Merbok that will move north and east
out of the Northern Pacific Thursday into the Southern Bering Sea
Thursday night and into the Central Bering Sea on Friday. This
low will encounter favorable conditions aloft for deep and rapid
cyclogenisis. Computer models continue to indicate rapid
deepening of this low from around 965 mb early on Thursday to 950
mb to 945 mb on Friday. Weather models vary on the track of this
feature, but are starting to converge on a track taking the low
over the Central Bering Sea to be located as a 948 mb low 100 nm
south of St Lawrence Island by Saturday morning. This track will
bring very strong winds and heavy rain to coastal areas south of
the Bering Strait beginning Friday afternoon and continuing into
Saturday. The track of this low will greatly affect which areas
will receive the worst impacts as far as coastal erosion and
flooding along the coast. We will continue to closely monitor this
storm. Those with interests on or near the West Coast should keep
close tabs on this storm and be prepared to take protective
actions. This storm has the potential to produce significant
coastal flooding south of the Bering Strait.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ211>214</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Eastern Norton Sound and Nulato Hills; Southern Seward Peninsula Coast; St Lawrence Island and Bering Strait Coast; Yukon Delta</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002158</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>002180</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ211</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ212</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ213</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>AKZ214</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>