<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.87d0705970af4dd1206b2d34f9acf83c26bf1114.004.3</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-12T09:51:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.83f743d6b7519bb0e9694c6a050300aad530ead9.006.3,2025-10-12T04:19:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-12T09:51:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-12T09:51:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-12T22:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued October 12 at 9:51AM EDT until October 12 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Warning, 3 to 5 feet of inundation
above ground level with this afternoon's high tide in low-
lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways. For the High
Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 10 to 15 feet in the surf
zone. For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents,
large breaking waves, and strong longshore currents in the surf
zone.

* WHERE...Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Warning, until 5 PM EDT Monday.
For the High Surf Advisory, until 1 AM EDT Tuesday. For the
Beach Hazards Statement, until 8 PM EDT this evening.

* IMPACTS...Up to 3 to 5 feet of inundation above ground level
is possible with this afternoon's high tide in some areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways resulting in a significant
threat to life and property. Severe flooding will extend
inland from the waterfront causing flooding of many homes and
businesses with some structural damage possible. In some
areas, battering waves will cause additional damage to
property. Numerous roads will be impassable under several feet
of water and vehicles will be submerged. Some neighborhoods
will be isolated and some areas may need to be evacuated.
Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and localized beach
erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away
from shore into deeper water. Dangerous shore break can throw
a swimmer or surfer head first into the bottom causing neck
and back injuries. Strong longshore currents will create
dangerous swimming conditions.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.

Strong longshore currents can sweep swimmers and surfers into rip
currents, piers, jetties and other hazardous areas. In many
cases, the longshore current is strong enough to prevent swimmers
from being able to keep their feet on the bottom making it
difficult to return to shore.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 121351</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 5 PM EDT MONDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 1 AM EDT TUESDAY... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KMHX.BH.S.0087.000000T0000Z-251013T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.75e94500701365f1a2b615efb659916c29e52736.004.2,2025-10-11T20:14:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>