<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2e690cffffcb5a0b8913222d064adf1c772e6a65.001.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-12T14:58:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.83f743d6b7519bb0e9694c6a050300aad530ead9.003.2,2025-10-12T04:19:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.87d0705970af4dd1206b2d34f9acf83c26bf1114.001.2,2025-10-12T09:51:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>High Surf Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-12T14:58:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-12T14:58:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-13T03:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>High Surf Advisory issued October 12 at 2:58PM EDT until October 13 at 8:00AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Warning, up to 2 to 4 feet of
inundation above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking
waves of 10 to 15 feet in the surf zone. For the Beach Hazards
Statement, dangerous rip currents, large breaking waves, and
strong longshore currents in the surf zone.

* WHERE...East Carteret County.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Warning, until 4 AM EDT Monday.
For the High Surf Advisory, until 8 AM EDT Monday. For the
Beach Hazards Statement, until 8 PM EDT this evening.

* IMPACTS...Up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation above ground level
is possible in some areas near shorelines and tidal waterways
resulting in an elevated threat of property damage. Flooding
will extend inland from the waterfront threatening some homes
and businesses. Numerous road closures and flooding of
vehicles will be possible. Dangerous swimming and surfing
conditions and localized beach erosion. Rip currents can sweep
even the best swimmers away from shore into deeper water.
Dangerous shore break can throw a swimmer or surfer head first
into the bottom causing neck and back injuries. Strong
longshore currents will create dangerous swimming conditions.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.

Strong longshore currents can sweep swimmers and surfers into rip
currents, piers, jetties and other hazardous areas. In many
cases, the longshore current is strong enough to prevent swimmers
from being able to keep their feet on the bottom making it
difficult to return to shore.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 121858</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 4 AM EDT MONDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 AM EDT MONDAY... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KMHX.SU.Y.0009.000000T0000Z-251013T1200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-13T08:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.75e94500701365f1a2b615efb659916c29e52736.001.4,2025-10-11T20:14:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.41ca3970a251b3c246e8a46ee5444803a8ed6791.003.3,2025-10-11T15:19:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2d94010fe76a5c01dcf16e8bb2dcc71d7b58d669.003.2,2025-10-11T05:02:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7b5d5c8e58e289a51322b15422db8ecd3fb73af9.003.4,2025-10-10T19:59:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.bc9662962de6042bd9911c30c8549fcaabead1b7.003.1,2025-10-10T15:29:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>East Carteret</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037031</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ196</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>