<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 23 Dec 2022 09:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA12641ED39444.SpecialWeatherStatement.12641EEEDC40CA.REVSPSREV.c6bc21414239e99491cc37c6bb8972b0</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-23T13:21:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Lassen-Eastern Plumas-Eastern Sierra Counties; Mono; Surprise Valley California (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-24T01:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-24T16:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Reno (Western Nevada)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 23 at 1:21PM PST  by NWS Reno</headline>
<description>...ACTIVE WEATHER PATTERN RETURNS NEXT WEEK WITH STRONGER WINDS,
HEAVY MOUNTAIN SNOW AND VALLEY RAIN...
For the Christmas weekend, dry and mild conditions will prevail
with valley inversions producing areas of haze especially in urban
areas, and patchy nighttime and morning freezing fog in fog-prone
Sierra valleys.
A series of storms next week will bring periods of gusty winds,
heavy mountain snow and valley rain with potential for widespread
travel and recreation impacts. The strongest storm is currently
expected to affect eastern California and western Nevada Monday
night through Tuesday night.
* WINDS: The strongest winds are most likely from Monday night
through Tuesday morning. For lower elevations of northeast
California, the Tahoe basin and western Nevada, wind gusts of
45-55 mph are anticipated, with gusts possibly exceeding 65 mph
especially in wind prone areas. Gusts well over 100 mph will
occur over Sierra ridges.
* SIERRA RAIN AND SNOW: The heaviest rain and snowfall rates are
expected late Monday night through Tuesday. Snow could begin to
accumulate over the main Sierra passes starting late Tuesday
morning, and into the Lake Tahoe basin and higher elevation
roads of northeast California by Tuesday afternoon, continuing
through Tuesday night. Storm snowfall totals of 2 or more feet
are possible above 8000 feet, with several inches to over 1 foot
possible between 5500 and 8000 feet.
* LOWER ELEVATION RAIN: The heaviest rain is most likely in
western Nevada valleys and foothills Tuesday morning and
afternoon. Rainfall totals could reach 1 inch in the main urban
areas of Reno-Sparks, Carson City and Minden, with up to 2
inches in foothill locations and lighter amounts farther east
into west central Nevada. The rain may end as a short period of
snow or a rain-snow mix by late Tuesday night in foothill
locations, with light snow accumulations possible near and above
5500 feet including areas near Virginia City.
Later next week through the New Year`s holiday weekend,
additional storm systems remain possible. The best chances for
more snow continue to favor the Sierra, but light accumulations
may occur in some western Nevada and eastern California valleys.
The New Year`s Eve period could see an elevated risk for winter
travel impacts and increased winds.
The quiet weather through this weekend brings an opportunity to
plan for winter driving conditions and alternate options if
traveling next week, and to secure or remove outdoor decorations
if they are at risk of damage from strong winds.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ070>073-NVZ001>005</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Lassen-Eastern Plumas-Eastern Sierra Counties; Mono; Surprise Valley California</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006063</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ072</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ073</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>