<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 06 May 2022 03:50:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-ND1263F41627F8.FloodWarning.1263F43423C0ND.FGFFLSFGF.d5cad260f16f3ead0728614531b5e181</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-05-06T10:50:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Richland (North Dakota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-05-06T10:50:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-05-08T07:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Eastern ND and Grand Forks (Northeastern North Dakota and Northwestern Minnesota)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Warning issued May 06 at 10:50AM CDT until May 08 at 7:00AM CDT by NWS Eastern ND and Grand Forks</headline>
<description>...The Flood Warning is extended for the following rivers in
Minnesota...North Dakota...
Red River of the North at Wahpeton affecting Wilkin and Richland
Counties.
Wild Rice River (MN) at Hendrum affecting Norman County.
...The Flood Warning is cancelled for the following rivers in
Minnesota...
Snake River AT Alvarado affecting Marshall County.
...The Flood Warning continues for the following rivers in
Minnesota...North Dakota...
Red River of the North at Halstad affecting Norman and Traill
Counties.
Buffalo River near Dilworth affecting Clay County.
Red Lake River at Crookston affecting Polk County.
Two Rivers River near Hallock affecting Kittson County.
Sheyenne River at Lisbon affecting Ransom County.
Maple River near Enderlin affecting Ransom and Cass Counties.
Goose River at Hillsboro affecting Traill County.
Red River of the North at Pembina affecting Kittson and Pembina
Counties.
Red River of the North at Drayton affecting Marshall, Kittson,
Walsh and Pembina Counties.
Red River of the North at Fargo affecting Cass and Clay Counties.
Red River of the North at East Grand Forks affecting Polk and
Grand Forks Counties.
Red River of the North at Oslo affecting Walsh, Marshall, Polk
and Grand Forks Counties.
Sheyenne River Diversion at West Fargo affecting Cass County.
Sheyenne River at Harwood affecting Cass County.
Sheyenne River near Kindred affecting Richland and Cass Counties.
Maple River near Mapleton (South of I-94) affecting Cass County.
Pembina River at Walhalla affecting Pembina and Cavalier Counties.
Pembina River at Neche affecting Pembina County.
.Major flooding will persist at Oslo, Drayton and Pembina on the Red
River through the forecast period. Pembina is approaching crest
while all other forecast points are at crest or have crested.
Additional rainfall is expected this weekend, but how river levels
are affected is still uncertain. This forecast does not take into
account forecasted rainfall this weekend.
Additional information is available at www.weather.gov.
...FLOOD WARNING NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL SUNDAY MORNING...
* WHAT...Minor flooding is occurring and minor flooding is forecast.
* WHERE...Red River of the North at Wahpeton.
* WHEN...Until Sunday morning.
* IMPACTS...At 11.0 feet, MINOR FLOOD.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 10:30 AM CDT Friday the stage was 11.1 feet.
- Recent Activity...The maximum river stage in the 24 hours
ending at 10:30 AM CDT Friday was 11.3 feet.
- Forecast...The river is expected to fall below flood stage
just after midnight tonight and continue falling to 10.3 feet
Friday morning.
- Flood stage is 11.0 feet.
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Motorists should not attempt to drive around barricades or drive
cars through flooded areas.
Safety message - Turn around, don`t drown. Don`t travel through
flooded areas. Most flood deaths occur in vehicles.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNC167-NDC077</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXT.KFGF.FL.W.0075.000000T0000Z-220508T1200Z/
/WHNN8.1.ER.220501T0730Z.220502T2300Z.220507T0600Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Richland</areaDesc>
<polygon>46.5,-96.84 46.5,-96.63 46.03,-96.41 46.02,-96.72 46.5,-96.84</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>038077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NDC077</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>