<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.94b67023b275f771daaed13c4c43441d2da67438.003.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-06-22T03:11:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5a6b8c218bba5e5d21a024470b5c6df86c8a51fe.003.2,2025-06-21T11:22:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Extreme Heat Watch</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>XHA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-06-22T03:11:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-06-23T12:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-06-22T16:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Upton NY</senderName>
        <headline>Extreme Heat Watch issued June 22 at 3:11AM EDT until June 24 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Upton NY</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Heat Advisory, heat index values up to 99 expected.
For the Extreme Heat Watch, dangerously hot conditions with heat
index values up to 105 possible.

* WHERE...In Connecticut, Southern Middlesex and Southern New London
Counties. In New York, Northern Nassau, Northwest Suffolk,
Southern Nassau, and Southwest Suffolk Counties.

* WHEN...For the Heat Advisory, from noon today to 8 PM EDT this
evening. For the Extreme Heat Watch, from Monday afternoon through
Tuesday evening.

* IMPACTS...Extreme heat and humidity will significantly increase
the potential for heat related illnesses, particularly for those
working or participating in outdoor activities. Hot temperatures
and high humidity may cause heat illnesses.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The highest heat index values will take place
each day during the afternoon, especially on Monday and Tuesday.
</description>
        <instruction>An Extreme Heat Watch means that the combination of heat and
humidity could create a dangerous situation in which heat illnesses
are possible. Take extra precautions if you work or spend time
outside. When possible, reschedule strenuous activities to early
morning or evening. Know the signs and symptoms of heat exhaustion
and heat stroke. Wear light weight and loose fitting clothing when
possible, and drink plenty of water.

Seniors and those with chronic health problems or mental health
conditions are at an increased risk. Homes without air conditioning
can be much hotter than outdoor temperatures.

Use air conditioning to stay cool at home or go to a place that has
air conditioning. If you don't have home air conditioning, continue
to seek out cool spaces each day as long as it remains hot, and for
a few days after if your home is still hot. Check on vulnerable
friends, family members and neighbors.

To reduce risk during outdoor work, the Occupational Safety and
Health Administration recommends scheduling frequent rest breaks in
shaded or air conditioned environments. Anyone overcome by heat
should be moved to a cool and shaded location. Heat stroke is an
emergency! In cases of heat stroke call 9 1 1.

A Heat Advisory is issued when the combination of heat and humidity
is expected to make it feel like it is 95 to 99 degrees for two or
more consecutive days, or 100 to 104 degrees for any length of time.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>NPWOKX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS71 KOKX 220711</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HEAT ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM NOON TODAY TO 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...EXTREME HEAT WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM MONDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH TUESDAY EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KOKX.XH.A.0001.250623T1600Z-250625T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-06-24T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.64875df0b10a59ffbf101662ce33046dc92800c2.002.1,2025-06-21T02:24:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.bc5e58bd41bd6a7f60d6b7a740d60257d1995f37.002.1,2025-06-20T14:10:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southern Middlesex; Southern New London; Northwest Suffolk; Southwest Suffolk; Northern Nassau; Southern Nassau</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>009007</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>009011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036059</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CTZ011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CTZ012</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ078</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ080</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ177</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ179</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>