<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.647ba58d8e58d08f712d7ec578ebfe512775b658.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-23T15:30:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-23T15:07:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-23T15:07:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-25T23:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Aberdeen SD</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued July 23 at 3:07PM CDT by NWS Aberdeen SD</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency has issued an Air
Quality Alert for fine particles pollution. The Air Quality Index
(AQI) is expected to reach the Red or Unhealthy category.

* WHERE...West central Minnesota.

* WHEN...From 12 AM CDT Thursday to 11 PM CDT Friday.

* IMPACTS...Some members of the general public may experience health
effects. Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease
(including asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, may
experience health effects.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...A band of heavy smoke from wildfires in
Saskatchewan and Manitoba is moving south across northwest Minnesota
on Wednesday. The smoke will remain over the northwest part of the
state through the end of Wednesday, but by Thursday morning the smoke
will reach southwest MN. Smoke will also move into the northeast and
central portions of the state Thursday morning, and by Thursday
afternoon smoke will reach east central and south central MN. Some
uncertainty remains regarding how far south the ground-level smoke
will reach by Friday morning, when winds are expected to become
southerly and push the smoke back to the north. Air quality should
improve gradually from south to north beginning Friday afternoon,
with improvement in fine particle levels below the alert threshold
expected by the end of Friday.
</description>
        <instruction>Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease (including
asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, should avoid
prolonged or heavy exertion. The general public should limit
prolonged or heavy exertion.

Reduce or eliminate activities that contribute to air pollution, such
as outdoor burning, and use of residential wood burning devices.
Reduce vehicle trips and vehicle idling as much as possible.

Keep windows closed overnight to prevent smoke from getting indoors.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAABR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS73 KABR 232030</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FROM 12 AM CDT THURSDAY TO 11 PM CDT FRIDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Traverse; Big Stone</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027155</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>027011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ039</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MNZ046</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>