<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f507fdb589638ad92436758fc9030dbadad9c88e.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-06T13:24:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-06T13:24:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-06T13:24:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-07T15:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued July 6 at 1:24PM AKDT by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>Following a front bringing rain across the Panhandle today, a
developing low is expected to move into the SE Gulf Monday into
Tuesday. This system is still expected to bring enhanced rainfall
to the far southern Panhandle, particularly Ketchikan and
Metlakatla. Forecast confidence continues to grow that the less
impactful solution is still the most likely. This would have the
low continue to be more progressive and the moisture plume stay
further south before wrapping around to impact the eastern half of
Clarence Strait / Misty Fjords late Monday night into Tuesday
morning.

While overall 24-hr rain amounts are now ranging from around 0.75
for coastal communities on Prince of Wales Island to 1.5 inches
for Ketchikan and Metlakatla, the heaviest rainfall and rates are
expected along southerly facing mountains in eastern portions of
the Ketchikan Gateway Borough and Annette Island. It is not out of
the question for one of those areas to get an outlier amount of as
much as 2 inches. Fast-responding rivers and lakes may reach bank
full conditions, but no flooding is expected at this time. Winds
in Clarence Strait and the SE Gulf will increase out of the S and
SE with fresh to strong breezes (18 - 24 kt) for Monday morning as
it approaches the outer coast.

Later in the week, Thursday and Friday, it is looking like a more
impactful frontal system, with an associated weak to moderate
atmospheric river, will move over the Panhandle. This will
bring heavier rainfall &amp; some relatively gusty conditions to a
more widespread area. The heaviest precipitation again looks to
focus on the southern Panhandle with isolated areas of 1.5 to 2
inches in 24 hours. The heaviest of this precipitation is expected
to fall Thursday over areas along the coast. Ensembles are
showing a &gt;70% chance that winds along the NE Gulf will reach
strong breezes to Gale force winds of 30 to 35 kts. We will
continue to monitor this system as it gets closer.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWAK87 PAJK 062124</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HEAVY RAIN POTENTIAL FOR SOUTHERN PANHANDLE THROUGH THE WEEK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>City and Borough of Sitka; Prince of Wales Island; Ketchikan Gateway Borough; Annette Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002220</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002198</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002130</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ323</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ328</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ330</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ332</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>