<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ed8c83167202baa8ec3cd302669a4f93ddc9a1c2.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-06T08:08:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-06T08:08:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-06T08:08:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-06T16:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wilmington NC</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued July 6 at 8:08AM EDT by NWS Wilmington NC</headline>
        <description>HLSILM

This product covers southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina

**TROPICAL STORM CHANTAL CONTINUES TO MOVE INLAND THROUGH NORTHEAST SOUTH
CAROLINA AND SOUTHEAST NORTH CAROLINA**

NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Central Horry,
Coastal Brunswick, Coastal Georgetown, Coastal Horry, Coastal
New Hanover, Coastal Pender, and Inland Georgetown

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 80 miles west-southwest of Wilmington NC or about 30
miles northwest of Myrtle Beach SC
- 34.0N 79.2W
- Storm Intensity 40 mph
- Movement North-northwest or 345 degrees at 8 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

Tropical Storm Chantal is slowly moving northward through extreme
northeastern SC into southeastern NC. Periods of heavy rain could
produce localized flooding in areas of southeastern NC including
Columbus, Bladen, and Robeson County. Due to the slow movement of
Chantal, the potential for isolated flooding may continue through this
afternoon. Strong rip currents and dangerous surf are also expected,
even as the storm moves inland. Hazardous surf conditions are expected
to continue through early next week.

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
northern Horry County in South Carolina and portions of southeast
North Carolina. Remain well guarded against dangerous flood waters
having possible significant impacts. If realized, these impacts
include:
- Moderate flooding from rainfall may prompt some evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rise and overspill their banks in a few
places, especially in the typical prone locations. Small creeks
and ditches may overflow.
- Flood waters may enter some structures. Underpasses, low-lying
spots along roadways, and poor drainage areas may become
submerged by rising water. Some secondary streets and parking
lots may flood as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
- Driving conditions will become hazardous, and some road
closures can be expected.

* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Life-threatening rip currents and dangerous surf are ongoing at all
area beaches today. High surf forecasted for the beaches of northeast
SC and Brunswick county through this evening, with breaking wave
heights of six feet likely and minor beach erosion possible.

* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
southeast North Carolina and northeast South Carolina. Remain well
sheltered from hazardous wind having additional limited impacts.
If realized, these impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes is possible. Unsecured lightweight objects may be
blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted or
weak trees may snap or be knocked down. Some fences and roadway
signs will be damaged.
- A few roads may become impassable due to debris, particularly
within urban or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving
conditions are possible, especially for high profile vehicles
on bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.

* TORNADOES:
Potential impacts from tornadoes are still unfolding across southeast
North Carolina and northeast South Carolina. Remain well braced
against a tornado event having possible limited impacts. If realized,
these impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder preparedness
actions during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Tornadoes can cause damage to trees, vehicles, boats, and
buildings. Unsecured mobile homes and poorly constructed
structures are particularly vulnerable.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to remain safely sheltered from the storm. Stay
inside and away from windows. Listen for updates and be ready in case
you lose electrical power. Locate your battery powered radio and
flashlight from your Emergency Supplies Kit. Keep these items close.

During the peak of the storm, keep your shoes on and rain gear handy.
Boots and tennis shoes offer the best foot protection if you become
unexpectedly exposed to the elements.

Continue to keep your cell phone well charged for as long as
possible. If you lose power, use it more sparingly and mainly for
personal emergencies and check-ins. Do not overload communications
systems with idle chatter.

* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Wilmington NC around 11 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSILM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KILM 061208</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>TROPICAL STORM CHANTAL CONTINUES TO MOVE INLAND THROUGH NORTHEAST SOUTH
CAROLINA AND SOUTHEAST NORTH CAROLINA</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Pender; Coastal Pender; Inland New Hanover; Coastal New Hanover; Inland Brunswick; Coastal Brunswick; Coastal Horry; Inland Georgetown; Coastal Georgetown; Central Horry; Northern Horry</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037141</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037129</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045051</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045043</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ105</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ106</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ107</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ108</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ109</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ054</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ059</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>