<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:22:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GA12640D3C6828.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D3DBF20GA.JAXHLSJAX.5de47e0e847b7c0ffb9adcdb8b55d506</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-28T05:22:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Appling; Atkinson; Bacon; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Coffee; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Jeff Davis; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Pierce; Southern Ware; Wayne; Western Charlton (Georgia) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-28T05:22:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-28T14:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Jacksonville (Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 28 at 5:22AM EDT  by NWS Jacksonville</headline>
<description>This product covers Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia
**POTENTIAL FOR EXTREME FLOODING IMPACTS FROM HEAVY RAINFALL OVER PARTS OF
NORTHEAST FLORIDA WITH IAN**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Coastal Duval, Coastal Flagler, Coastal Nassau, Coastal St.
Johns, Eastern Clay, Eastern Putnam, Inland St. Johns, and
South Central Duval
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Coastal Camden and Coastal Glynn
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Central Marion,
Eastern Marion, Inland Flagler, Trout River, Western Clay,
Western Duval, Western Marion, and Western Putnam
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Baker, Bradford,
Brantley, Eastern Alachua, Gilchrist, Inland Camden, Inland
Glynn, Inland Nassau, Northeastern Charlton, Union, Wayne,
Western Alachua, and Western Charlton
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 340 miles south-southwest of Jacksonville FL or about 250
miles south of Ocala FL
- 25.6N 82.9W
- Storm Intensity 140 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 15 degrees at 10 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Major Hurricane Ian, located near 25.6 north, 82.9 west at 5 AM EDT
Wednesday morning , is expected to move north northeast today while
decreasing in forward speed. A turn to the north is expected Thursday.
On this track, Ian is forecast to move toward southwest Florida and
make landfall on the southwest Florida coast this afternoon. Ian has
strengthened to a category 4 hurricane with maximum winds currently
near 140 mph with higher gusts.
A tropical storm warning and a storm surge warning remain in effect
for the entire northeast Florida coast and the entire St. Johns River
basin. A tropical storm warning is in effect for coastal Glynn,
coastal Camden, coastal Nassau, Duval, Clay, St. Johns, Flagler,
Putnam, and Marion Counties. A tropical storm watch remains in effect
for Wayne, inland Glynn, inland Camden, Brantley, inland Nassau,
Baker, Charlton, Union, Bradford, Alachua, and Gilchrist counties.
The start of tropical storm winds likely are to begin tonight and
early Thursday morning across north central and northeast Florida, and
midday Thursday over parts of southeast Georgia.
Increasing rain chances are expected through the day from south to
north, with more rain and rain squalls and possibly embedded
thunderstorms occurring tonight through Friday. Heavy rainfall with
significant to extensive flash flooding is expected across parts of
northeast FL. A Flood Watch is in effect for for much of northeast
Florida and portions of southeast Georgia.
There is a concern for isolated tornadoes across parts of northeast
and north central Florida from this evening through at least Thursday
evening.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
devastating impacts across northeast Florida and north central
Florida. Potential impacts include:
- Extreme rainfall flooding may prompt numerous evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may overwhelmingly overflow their banks
in many places with deep moving water. Small streams, creeks,
canals, and ditches may become raging rivers. Flood control
systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter numerous structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Numerous places where flood waters may cover escape
routes. Streets and parking lots become rivers of raging water
with underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become very
dangerous. Numerous road and bridge closures with some weakened
or washed out.
Protect against life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
significant to extensive impacts across Suwannee Valley of northeast
Florida and parts of southeast Georgia.
* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across coastal southeast Georgia, coastal northeast Florida,
intracoastal waterway, and the St. Johns River basin. Potential impacts
in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across inland Glynn and Camden counties.
* WIND:
Protect against life-threatening wind having possible extensive
impacts across portions of northeast Florida, north central Florida, and
southeast Georgia. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Also, protect against dangerous wind having possible limited to
significant impacts across inland parts of northeast Florida
and southeast Georgia.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a dangerous tornado event having possible significant
impacts across Flagler county. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of scattered tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- Several places may experience tornado damage with a few spots
of considerable damage, power loss, and communications failures.
- Locations could realize roofs torn off frame houses, mobile
homes demolished, boxcars overturned, large trees snapped or
uprooted, vehicles tumbled, and small boats tossed about.
Dangerous projectiles can add to the toll.
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across north central Florida and portions of northeast Florida.
Elsewhere across Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia, little to
no impact is anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so immediately.
For those not under evacuation orders, assess the risk from wind,
falling trees, and flooding at your location. If you decide to move,
relocate to a safer location nearby. If you do not relocate,
help keep roadways open for those under evacuation orders.
If evacuating, leave with a destination in mind and allow extra
time to get there. Take your emergency supplies kit. Gas up
your vehicle ahead of time.
Let others know where you are going prior to departure. Secure loose
items and pets in the car, and avoid distracted driving.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and emergency supplies
kit and take necessary actions to protect your family and secure your
home or business.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, plan to move to safe shelter.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low-lying or poor
drainage area, in a valley, or near an already swollen river, plan to
move to safe shelter on higher ground.
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.
When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.
There is a threat from tornadoes with this storm. Have multiple ways
to receive Tornado Warnings. Be ready to shelter quickly.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Jacksonville FL around 1130 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ020-021-023-024-030-031-033-035-038-122-124-125-132-133-136>138-140-222-225-232-236-237-240-325-340-425-GAZ132>136-149-151>154-162-163-165-166-250-264-350-364</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Appling; Atkinson; Bacon; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Coffee; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Jeff Davis; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Pierce; Southern Ware; Wayne; Western Charlton</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013161</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013229</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013299</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013305</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ132</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ134</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ135</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ136</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ151</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ152</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ153</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ162</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ163</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ165</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ166</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ250</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ350</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ364</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>