<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 28 Sep 2022 09:05:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640D3E3644.TropicalStormWatch.12640D4B0B6CSC.ILMTCVILM.6eef8d6b7460c8f1c3ef2b624541d1e9</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-28T17:05:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Dillon (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Tropical Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>TRA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-28T17:05:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-29T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Wilmington (Northeastern South Carolina and Southeastern North Carolina - Wilmington)</senderName>
<headline>Tropical Storm Watch issued September 28 at 5:05PM EDT until further notice by NWS Wilmington</headline>
<description>...TROPICAL STORM WATCH IN EFFECT...
A Tropical Storm Watch means tropical storm-force winds are possible
somewhere within this area within the next 48 hours
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Dillon
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Below tropical storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 20-30 mph with gusts to 40 mph
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 39
to 57 mph
- The wind threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for hazardous wind of equivalent tropical storm
force.
- PREPARE: Efforts to protect property should now be
underway. Prepare for limited wind damage.
- ACT: Act now to complete preparations before the wind
becomes hazardous.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes is possible. Unsecured lightweight objects may
be blown about.
- Some large limbs may break from trees. A few shallow rooted
or weak trees may snap or be knocked down. Some fences and
roadway signs damaged.
- A few roads may become impassable due to debris,
particularly within urban or heavily wooded locations.
Hazardous driving conditions are possible, especially for
high profile vehicles on bridges and other elevated
roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages are possible.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: 3-6 inches, with locally higher
amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
moderate flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
moderate flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues
are possible.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action may result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Moderate flooding from rainfall may prompt some evacuations
and rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rise and overspill their banks in a
few places, especially in the typical prone locations.
Small creeks and ditches may overflow.
- Flood waters may enter some structures. Underpasses,
low-lying spots along roadways, and poor drainage areas may
become submerged by rising water. Some secondary streets
and parking lots may flood as storm drains and retention
ponds overflow.
- Driving conditions will become hazardous, and some road
closures can be expected.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is unfavorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Tornadoes not expected
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Tornadoes are not expected. Showers and thunderstorms
with gusty winds may still occur.
- PREPARE: Little to no preparations needed to protect
against tornadoes at this time. Keep informed of the latest
tornado situation.
- ACT: Listen for changes in the forecast.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Little to None
- Little to no potential impacts from tornadoes.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://www.weather.gov/ilm/Tropics
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ024</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KILM.TR.A.1009.220928T2105Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Dillon</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ024</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>