<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:07:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640D4ABA2C.HurricaneWatch.12640D4BF5CCSC.CHSTCVCHS.64785cac9c9a3809d44e3e94d2e724ff</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-28T23:07:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Inland Berkeley (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HUA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-28T23:07:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-29T07:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Charleston (the Southern end of South Carolina and Eastern Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Watch issued September 28 at 11:07PM EDT until further notice by NWS Charleston</headline>
<description>...TROPICAL STORM WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...HURRICANE WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT...
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Goose Creek
- Moncks Corner
- Saint Stephen
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Strong Tropical Storm force
wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 45-60 mph with gusts to 75 mph
- Window for Tropical Storm force winds: Friday morning until
early Saturday morning
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 58
to 73 mph
- The wind threat has increased from the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for dangerous wind of equivalent strong tropical
storm force.
- PREPARE: Remaining efforts to protect life and property
should be completed as soon as possible. Prepare for
significant wind damage.
- ACT: Move to safe shelter before the wind becomes hazardous.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with
damage to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few
buildings experiencing window, door, and garage door
failures. Mobile homes damaged, especially if unanchored.
Unsecured lightweight objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within
urban or heavily wooded places. A few bridges and access
routes impassable.
- Travel by vehicle or on foot increasingly difficult. Danger
of death or injury from falling objects such as trees or
electric wires outside.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more
prevalent in areas with above ground lines, which could
persist for hours or days.
- Some poorly secured small craft could break loose from
their moorings.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: 4-8 inches, with locally higher
amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for major
flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
major flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues are
likely.
- PREPARE: Strongly consider protective actions, especially
if you are in an area vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action will likely result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Extensive
- Major rainfall flooding could prompt many rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries could rapidly overflow their banks
in multiple locations. Small streams, creeks, canals,
ditches may become dangerous rivers. Flood control systems
and barriers could become stressed.
- Flood waters could enter many structures within multiple
communities; some structures become uninhabitable or are
washed away. Flood waters could cover multiple escape
routes. Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving
water with underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become
dangerous. Many road and bridge closures with some weakened
or washed out.
- Drinking water and sewer services could be negatively
impacted.
- Hazardous containers and materials could possibly be
present in flood waters.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is somewhat favorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for a few
tornadoes
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for a
few tornadoes.
- PREPARE: If your shelter is particularly vulnerable to
tornadoes, prepare to relocate to safe shelter before
hazardous weather arrives.
- ACT: If a tornado warning is issued, be ready to shelter
quickly.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- Isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution of emergency
plans.
- Isolated locations could experience tornado damage, along
with power and communications disruptions.
- In isolated locations, tornadoes could damage trees,
vehicles, boats and buildings, especially mobile homes and
other poorly constructed structures.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- https://weather.gov/chs
- https://ready.gov/hurricanes</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ045</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KCHS.HU.A.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/
/O.CON.KCHS.TR.W.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Inland Berkeley</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ045</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>