<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 28 Aug 2023 03:12:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12665B5351A0.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B548B4CFL.MFLHLSMFL.a57584ef0b105e904e67aabbc67588e1</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-28T11:12:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Broward County; Coastal Collier County; Coastal Miami Dade County; Coastal Palm Beach County; Far South Miami-Dade County; Glades; Hendry; Inland Broward County; Inland Collier County; Inland Miami-Dade County; Inland Palm Beach County; Mainland Monroe; Metro Broward County; Metro Palm Beach County; Metropolitan Miami Dade (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-28T11:04:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-28T19:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Miami (Southern Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 28 at 11:12AM EDT  by NWS Miami</headline>
<description>This product covers South Florida
**Tropical Storm Warning now in effect for coastal Collier County**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Watch has been upgraded to a Tropical Storm
Warning for Coastal Collier County
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Coastal Collier County
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Inland Collier County
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 470 miles southwest of Miami FL or about 430 miles
south-southwest of Naples FL
- 20.8N 85.2W
- Storm Intensity 65 mph
- Movement North or 360 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Idalia continues to strengthen in the Yucatan
Channel this morning. The storm is forecast to move into the southeast
Gulf of Mexico tonight into Tuesday. Idalia is forecast to keep
strengthening over the eastern Gulf as it moves closer to the west
coast of Florida.
The following are the primary hazards of concern with Idalia:
* Coastal Flooding/Surge - Higher than usual tides due to the
combination of surge from Idalia and the full moon could lead to
coastal flooding of 1 to 3 feet in vulnerable, low-lying coastal
areas along the Gulf coast of southern Florida. Other vulnerable
coastal areas of southern Florida could also experience minor coastal
flooding, especially around the times of high tide.
* Rainfall - The majority of the rainfall associated with the system
is forecast to fall from this afternoon through Wednesday. The
greatest risk for flash flooding will be near the Gulf coast. Storm
total rain amounts of 2 to 3 inches with localized higher amounts.
The highest amounts are anticipated along the Gulf coast.
* Wind - Increasingly gusty winds are forecast Tuesday through
Thursday, particularly along the Gulf coast and adjacent coastal
waters. A reasonable worst case scenario would have tropical storm
force winds across Collier County between Monday night and Wednesday.
Areas of the East Coast and Atlantic waters could also see gusty
winds up to 35 mph during the same time frame.
* Tornadoes - A low-end tornado threat is possible through early
Thursday as banding from the system moves ashore. The focus for
tornadic activity could be in the western half of southern Florida.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across coastal Collier County. Potential impacts in
this area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of near-shore roads and parking lots become overspread
with surge water. Driving conditions dangerous in places where
surge water covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
Elsewhere across South Florida, little to no impact is anticipated.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across South Florida. Potential impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding may prompt a few evacuations.
- Ditches and canals may quickly rise with swift currents.
- Flood waters can enter a few structures, especially in usually
vulnerable spots. A few places where rapid ponding of water
occurs at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Several storm drains and retention ponds become
near-full and begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge
closures.
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
Southwest Florida. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
Elsewhere across South Florida, little to no impact is anticipated.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across South Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, mobile
homes pushed off foundations or overturned, large tree tops and
branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees knocked over, moving
vehicles blown off roads, and small boats pulled from moorings.
Elsewhere across South Florida, little to no impact is anticipated.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
For those not under evacuation orders, assess the risk from wind,
falling trees, and flooding at your location. If you decide to move,
relocate to a safer location nearby. If you do not relocate, help keep
roadways open for those under evacuation orders.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible.
Allow extra time to reach your destination. Many roads and bridges
will be closed once strong winds arrive. Check the latest weather
forecast before departing and drive with caution.
Keep cell phones well charged. Cell phone chargers for automobiles can
be helpful, but be aware of your risk for deadly carbon monoxide
poisoning if your car is left idling in a garage or other poorly
ventilated area.
If you are a visitor, be sure to know the name of the city or town in
which you are staying and the name of the county or parish in which
it resides. Listen for these locations in local news updates. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.
Storm surge is the leading killer associated with tropical storms and
hurricanes! Make sure you are in a safe area away from the surge
zone. Even if you are not in a surge-prone area, you could find
yourself cutoff by flood waters during and after the storm. Heed
evacuation orders issued by the local authorities.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Miami FL around 5 PM EDT, or sooner if conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ063-066>075-168-172>174</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Broward County; Coastal Collier County; Coastal Miami Dade County; Coastal Palm Beach County; Far South Miami-Dade County; Glades; Hendry; Inland Broward County; Inland Collier County; Inland Miami-Dade County; Inland Palm Beach County; Mainland Monroe; Metro Broward County; Metro Palm Beach County; Metropolitan Miami Dade</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012086</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012087</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012099</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ063</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ066</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ067</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ072</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ074</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ168</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ172</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ173</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ174</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>