<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 28 Aug 2023 09:18:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GA12665B543E58.HurricaneLocalStatement.12665B611448GA.JAXHLSJAX.559d5c6f09acb5f26088f2a54044361d</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-28T17:18:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Atkinson; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Southern Ware; Western Charlton (Georgia) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-28T17:00:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-29T01:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Jacksonville (Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued August 28 at 5:18PM EDT  by NWS Jacksonville</headline>
<description>This product covers Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia
**HURRICANE WARNINGS POSTED ALONG THE I-75 CORRIDOR OF INLAND
NORTHEAST FLORIDA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Hurricane Watch has been upgraded to a Hurricane Warning
for Gilchrist, Suwannee, Western Alachua, and Western Marion
- A Tropical Storm Watch has been issued for Atkinson, Brantley,
and Northern Ware
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Hurricane Warning is in effect for Gilchrist, Suwannee,
Western Alachua, and Western Marion
- A Storm Surge Watch and Tropical Storm Watch are in effect for
Coastal Camden and Coastal Glynn
- A Hurricane Watch is in effect for Baker, Bradford, Central
Marion, Clinch, Eastern Alachua, Echols, Hamilton, Northeastern
Charlton, Northern Columbia, Southern Columbia, Southern Ware,
Union, and Western Charlton
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Atkinson, Brantley,
Coastal Duval, Coastal Flagler, Coastal Nassau, Coastal St.
Johns, Eastern Clay, Eastern Marion, Eastern Putnam, Inland
Camden, Inland Flagler, Inland Glynn, Inland Nassau, Inland St.
Johns, Northern Ware, South Central Duval, Trout River, Western
Clay, Western Duval, and Western Putnam
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 660 miles south-southwest of Jacksonville FL or about 560
miles south-southwest of Ocala FL
- 21.4N 85.1W
- Storm Intensity 70 mph
- Movement North or 360 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Idalia is forecast to track northward into the southeast
Gulf of Mexico tonight. Idalia is forecast to strengthen to Hurricane
intensity tonight, and rapid strengthening is possible as the Idalia
accelerates north-northeastward towards the Florida Big Bend on Tuesday.
Idalia is expected to make landfall at Category 3 hurricane strength
Wednesday morning, and the hurricane should then turn northeastward
as it accelerates across our area Wednesday afternoon. Idalia may maintain
hurricane intensity as it reaches the Atlantic waters adjacent to Camden
and Glynn Counties in coastal southeast Georgia by Wednesday evening.
Local impacts from Idalia will begin on Tuesday afternoon and evening,
as spiral rain bands begin to overspread our region from southwest to
northeast. Heavy rainfall will then continue through the day
Wednesday. Tornadoes will be possible across the area on Tuesday night
and Wednesday, with higher chances along and east of the Idalia`s
center. Sustained tropical storm force winds will begin to be felt
across north central Florida and the Suwannee Valley during the
overnight or predawn hours on Wednesday, with conditions deteriorating
quickly towards sunrise, when hurricane force wind gusts can be expected
along the I-75 corridor of inland Northeast Florida. Sustained tropical
storm force winds and occasional hurricane force wind gusts are expected.
The core of the hurricane force winds are forecast to move offshore
of coastal southeast Georgia by early Wednesday evening. Storm surge
potential will increase on Wednesday, especially along the southeast
Georgia coast, where life threatening inundation of greater than 3 feet
above ground level is possible.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Prepare for life-threatening wind having possible devastating impacts
across along and west of I-75 in northeast Florida. Potential impacts
in this area include:
- Structural damage to sturdy buildings, some with complete roof
and wall failures. Complete destruction of mobile homes. Damage
greatly accentuated by large airborne projectiles. Locations
may be uninhabitable for weeks or months.
- Numerous large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Many roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Many bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Widespread power and communications outages.
Also, prepare for life-threatening wind having possible significant
to extensive impacts across the rest of northeast Florida and
southeast Georgia.
* TORNADOES:
Prepare for a dangerous tornado event having possible significant
impacts across northeast Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of scattered tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- Several places may experience tornado damage with a few spots
of considerable damage, power loss, and communications failures.
- Locations could realize roofs torn off frame houses, mobile
homes demolished, boxcars overturned, large trees snapped or
uprooted, vehicles tumbled, and small boats tossed about.
Dangerous projectiles can add to the toll.
Prepare for a tornado event having possible limited impacts across
southeast Georgia.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Prepare for life-threatening rainfall flooding having possible
extensive impacts across inland Northeast Florida and inland Southeast
Georgia. Potential impacts include:
- Major rainfall flooding may prompt many evacuations and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may
become dangerous rivers. Flood control systems and barriers may
become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter many structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Many places where flood waters may cover escape routes.
Streets and parking lots become rivers of moving water with
underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become dangerous.
Many road and bridge closures with some weakened or washed out.
Prepare for dangerous rainfall flooding having possible limited to
significant impacts across coastal Southeast Georgia and coastal Northeast
Florida.
* SURGE:
Prepare for life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across coastal Southeast Georgia. Potential impacts in
this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, prepare for locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across coastal Northeast Florida including the St. Johns
River Basin.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
For those not under evacuation orders, assess the risk from wind,
falling trees, and flooding at your location. If you decide to move,
relocate to a safer location nearby. If you do not relocate, help
keep roadways open for those under evacuation orders.
If evacuating, leave with a destination in mind and allow extra time
to get there. Take your emergency supplies kit. Gas up your vehicle
ahead of time.
Let others know where you are going prior to departure. Secure loose
items and pets in the car, and avoid distracted driving.
If evacuating, follow designated evacuation routes. Seek traffic
information on roadway signs, the radio, and from official sources.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to check your emergency plan and emergency supplies
kit and take necessary actions to protect your family and secure your
home or business.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging
wind gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the
center of the storm.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, plan to move to safe shelter.
If you live in a place particularly vulnerable to flooding, such as
near the ocean or a large inland lake, in a low-lying or poor
drainage area, plan to move to safe shelter on higher ground.
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.
When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of
strong gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness
activities to become unsafe.
Be sure to let friends and family members know of your intentions for
weathering the storm and your whereabouts. Have someone located away
from the threatened area serve as your point of contact. Share vital
contact information with others. Keep cell phones handy and charged.
Check on those who may not be fully aware of the situation or who are
unable to make personal preparations.
If you are a visitor, know the name of the county in which you are
located and where it is relative to current watches and warnings. If
staying at a hotel, ask the management staff about their onsite
disaster plan. Listen for evacuation orders, especially pertaining to
area visitors.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.
There is a threat from tornadoes with this storm. Have multiple ways
to receive Tornado Warnings. Be ready to shelter quickly.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Jacksonville FL by 1AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ020-021-023-024-030-031-033-035-038-122-124-125-132-133-136>138-140-222-225-232-236-237-240-325-340-425-GAZ149-152>154-162-163-165-166-250-264-350-364</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Atkinson; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Southern Ware; Western Charlton</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013299</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ152</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ153</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ162</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ163</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ165</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ166</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ250</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ350</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ364</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>