<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 28 Aug 2023 08:24:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MN12665B5419A0.AirQualityAlert.12665B713530MN.ABRAQAABR.afe9eeb9e527f6b9fa5810fdb27cfd94</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-28T15:24:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Big Stone; Traverse (Minnesota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Air Quality Alert</event>
<urgency>Unknown</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Unknown</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-28T15:22:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-30T06:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Aberdeen (Northern and Northeastern South Dakota)</senderName>
<headline>Air Quality Alert issued August 28 at 3:24PM CDT  by NWS Aberdeen</headline>
<description>...AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FROM 6 AM CDT TUESDAY TO 6 AM CDT
WEDNESDAY...
* WHAT...The Minnesota Pollution Control Agency has issued an Air
Quality Alert for fine particles pollution. The Air Quality Index
(AQI) is expected to reach the Orange or Unhealthy for Sensitive
Groups category.
* WHERE...Western Minnesota.
* WHEN...From 6 AM CDT Tuesday to 6 AM CDT Wednesday.
* IMPACTS...Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease
(including asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, may
experience health effects.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Heavy ground-level smoke from wildfires in the
Northwest Territories and northern Alberta is currently blanketing
most of western Canada. This smoke will be brought into the Dakotas
and western Minnesota early Tuesday morning by northerly winds. The
smoke will quickly move south across the western one-third of the
state, impacting northwest Minnesota in the morning, then the
southwest part of the state in the afternoon through early Wednesday
morning. The duration of smoke impacts will be brief at any one
location, but concentrations may be very high and reach the Red AQI
category for a few hours. Air quality will improve across southwest
Minnesota Wednesday morning.
For information on current air quality conditions in your area and to
sign up for daily air quality forecasts and alert notifications by
email, text message, phone, or the EPA AirNow mobile app, visit
https://www.pca.state.mn.us/air-water-land-climate/current-air-
quality-conditions. You can find additional information about health
and air quality at https://www.pca.state.mn.us/air-water-land-
climate/air-quality-and-health.</description>
<instruction>Sensitive groups, such as people with lung disease (including
asthma), heart disease, and children and older adults, should limit
prolonged or heavy exertion.
Reduce or eliminate activities that contribute to air pollution, such
as outdoor burning, and use of residential wood burning devices.
Reduce vehicle trips and vehicle idling as much as possible.
Keep windows closed overnight to prevent smoke from getting indoors.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ039-046</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Big Stone; Traverse</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027155</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ046</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>