<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 29 Aug 2023 03:12:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12665B60BF20.FlashFloodWarning.12665B6156B0NC.GSPFFSGSP.562f1961921fd96cda7ef29116f413a8</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-08-28T23:12:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Iredell (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
<urgency>Immediate</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FFW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-08-28T23:12:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-08-29T03:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flash Flood Warning issued August 28 at 11:12PM EDT until August 29 at 3:00AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...FLASH FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 3 AM EDT TUESDAY FOR
CENTRAL IREDELL COUNTY...
At 1112 PM EDT, The slow-moving storms responsible for the
torrential rainfall across central Iredell County have moved well
east of the area.  Storm-total rainfall of 2-5 inches fell within
1-2 hours across the warned area, with isolated totals of 5-6 inches
per reports from Emergency Management.  Rainfall of this intensity
historically produces areas of significant flash flooding.
A few flood-prone locations, including along Davie Ave, the Fourth
Creek Greenway, the Statesville Soccer Complex, and Old Mocksville
Rd, have been impacted by flash flooding, but no additional
significant impacts have been reported.  However, given the amount
of rain that has fallen over a large area in a very short period of
time, it is likely other impacts have occurred but are difficult to
see in the dark.  Therefore, please exercise extreme caution on area
roadways as flooded or washed out roadways can be very difficult to
see at night.  This remains a dangerous, life-threatening
situation.  Please stay away from all streams and adjacent low-lying
areas for the next several hours.
Light to isolated moderate rainfall is ongoing across the warned
area and light rain is expected to persist for at least the next
hour but this is not expected to contribute to the ongoing
flash-flood threat. Nevertheless, it will take at least a few more
hours for the floodwaves to work through area streams, including
Fourth Creek; therefore, even though the heavy rain threat has
ended, streams will continue to rise and remain above bankfull for
some time.
HAZARD...Life threatening flash flooding. Thunderstorms producing
flash flooding.
SOURCE...Radar and Rain Gauges
IMPACT...Life-threatening flash flooding of small creeks and
streams, urban areas, highways, streets and underpasses.
Deeper flooding of common, flood-prone areas is likely,
including farmland, parks, greenways, boat-access areas,
golf courses, underpasses, and parking lots.
Campgrounds adjacent to streams may see significant
flash flooding, capable of lifting campers.  Rapid
stream flows over roadways is likely with culvert
washouts possible.  A few low-water crossings may become
impassible.  A few structures adjacent to streams may be
inundated.
Some locations that may continue to experience flash flooding
include...
Statesville, Scotts and Cool Springs.
The heaviest rainfall and greatest flash flood threat is along and
near Fourth Creek from Statesville and points east, including near
Statesville Country Club, US 64, E Broad St, Bell Farm Rd, I-40, Old
Mocksville Rd, and Beechwood Farm Rd.  This area received 3-5 inches
of rainfall in less than two hours.
Pockets of moderate rain may develop over the next couple of hours,
capable of producing a quick half inch to one inch of rain in a
short period of time, and while this is not likely to cause new
flooding, it may prolong ongoing high flow conditions along small
streams.  Later into the overnight hours, additional heavy rain
cannot be ruled out.  Stay weather aware.
FLASH FLOOD...RADAR INDICATED
FLASH FLOOD DAMAGE THREAT...CONSIDERABLE</description>
<instruction>Turn around, don`t drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.
Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC097</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KGSP.FF.W.0017.000000T0000Z-230829T0700Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Iredell</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.87,-80.81 35.84,-80.72 35.78,-80.73 35.71,-80.76 35.73,-80.89 35.81,-81.08 35.86,-81.04 35.92,-81.02 35.87,-80.81</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC097</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>