<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 05 Jun 2022 09:37:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NM1263F9FDAC04.AirQualityAlert.1263FA0C91B0NM.ABQAQAABQ.36a2df1e0eaf48084eed4f8f86ad54cc</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-06-05T15:37:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Lower Rio Grande Valley; San Agustin Plains and Adjacent Lowlands; South Central Highlands; Southwest Mountains (New Mexico) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Air Quality Alert</event>
<urgency>Unknown</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Unknown</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-06-05T15:37:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-06-06T13:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Albuquerque (Northern and Central New Mexico)</senderName>
<headline>Air Quality Alert issued June 05 at 3:37PM MDT  by NWS Albuquerque</headline>
<description>...AIR QUALITY ALERT...
The following message is transmitted at the request of the New Mexico
Departments of Health and Environment, United States Forest Service
and the Interagency Wildland Fire Air Quality Response Program.
* WHAT...Localized areas of unhealthy air quality will continue for
areas near the Black Fire in the Gila National Forest. New and
residual smoke here will be transported toward the east and
southeast later today and into the evening. Outside the immediate
Black Fire area, smoke impacts in the state are not expected to be
widespread or significant.
* WHERE...Significant impacts will be localized across western
Socorro, Catron, northeast Grant, northern Dona Ana, and far
western Sierra counties. More details on impacted locations and
latest air quality information can be found at:
https://fire.airnow.gov
* WHEN...Remainder of this afternoon through at least 1 pm MDT,
Monday, June 6th.
* IMPACTS...Those with conditions such as asthma, chronic obstructive
pulmonary disease, interstitial lung disease, lung cancer, and heart
disease will be especially vulnerable to impacts from poor air
quality, as will adults over age 65, young children, and pregnant
women if smoke concentrations become unhealthy.
* HEALTH INFORMATION...Remember, your eyes are your best tools to
determine if it is safe to be outside. Use the 5-3-1 Method available
at https://nmtracking.doh.nm.gov/environment/air/FireAndSmoke.html.
If visibility is:
Under 5 miles, the air quality is unhealthy for young children,
adults over age 65, pregnant women, and people with heart
and/or lung disease, asthma or other respiratory illness.
Outdoor activity should be minimized.
Around 3 miles, young children, adults over age 65, pregnant
women, and people with heart and/or lung disease, asthma or other
respiratory illness should avoid all outdoor activities.
Around 1 mile, the air quality is unhealthy for everyone. People
should remain indoors and avoid all outdoor activities including
running errands. Unless an evacuation has been issued, stay inside
your home, indoor workplace, or in a safe shelter.
With the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic affecting New Mexico and with the
wildfire season underway, New Mexicans will need to take extra
precautions. Smoke from wildfires may cause people to have more
severe reactions if they are infected COVID-19. The best way to
protect against the potentially harmful effects of wildfire smoke and
to reduce the spread of COVID-19 is to stay home and create a clean
indoor air space. NMDOH offers tips here:
https://nmtracking.doh.nm.gov/environment/air/IndoorQuality.html and
https://cv.nmhealth.org
New Mexicans will also need to take steps to keep their homes cool to
avoid heat-related illnesses. NMDOH offers tips here:
https://nmtracking.doh.nm.gov/health/climate/HeatIllness.html.
For smoke forecast outlooks from the Interagency Wildland Fire Air
Quality Response Program please visit:
https://outlooks.wildlandfiresmoke.net.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ208-220-224-241</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Lower Rio Grande Valley; San Agustin Plains and Adjacent Lowlands; South Central Highlands; Southwest Mountains</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ208</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ220</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ224</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ241</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>