<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ddbd959b602ad79a10dc1a00e1c9632c8efa9852.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-13T00:24:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-13T00:24:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-13T00:24:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-13T06:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued May 13 at 12:24AM EDT until May 13 at 6:15AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Nuisance to Minor flooding caused by excessive rainfall is
expected.

* WHERE...Portions of northeast Georgia, including the following
county, Rabun and western North Carolina, including the following
county, Macon.

* WHEN...Until 615 AM EDT.

* IMPACTS...Nuisance flooding of low-lying areas adjacent to streams
and other poor-drainage areas, including farmland, parks,
greenways, boat-access areas, golf courses, underpasses, and
parking lots.  Isolated, shallow flows over roadways is possible.
A few flood-prone, low-water crossings may become impassible.  A
small culvert washout or two is possible.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 1223 AM EDT, Another round of training thunderstorms has
developed across central and western Rabun County and
southwestern Macon County over the past 60 minutes.  This has
produced a quick 1-1.5 inches of rainfall over soils already
saturated from heavy rainfall which occurred on Monday.
Storm-total rainfall of 3-6 inches has been observed, which
has caused significant rises on area streams.  New rapid
stream rises are imminent, including along Tiger Creek
between Clayton and Lakemont, the headwaters of the Tallulah
River in the Persimmon Creek community, the Little Tennessee
headwaters near Dillard and Otto, and the headwaters of the
Nantahala River near Rainbow Springs.  Areas of nuisance
flooding may develop along these streams and associated
tributaries over the next 1-3 hours.

- If heavy rainfall persists over the next 60-90 minutes, a
Flash Flood Warning may be issued.  If rapid stream rises are
observed, avoid all adjacent low-lying areas and seek higher
ground.  Drivers are urged to avoid any flooded roadways and
Turn Around Don't Drown.

- Some locations that may experience nuisance flooding
include...
Clayton, Mountain City, Tiger, Dillard, Sky Valley, Black
Rock Mountain State Park, Lakemont, Otto, and Rainbow
Springs.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Be especially cautious at night when it is harder to recognize the
dangers of flooding.

In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.

Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS82 KGSP 130424</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 615 AM EDT THIS MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0029.250513T0424Z-250513T1015Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-13T06:15:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Rabun, GA; Macon, NC</areaDesc>
            <polygon>35.0,-83.35 34.74,-83.39 34.73,-83.4 34.75,-83.43 34.73,-83.45 34.73,-83.51 34.77,-83.56 34.81,-83.57 34.99,-83.55 34.99,-83.48 35.0,-83.51 35.0,-83.52 35.02,-83.52 35.04,-83.54 35.04,-83.56 35.07,-83.57 35.13,-83.63 35.13,-83.37 35.0,-83.35</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>013241</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037113</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>GAC241</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCC113</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>