<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 21 Dec 2023 12:22:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA126672BDBFD8.FloodWatch.126672BF16D0CA.LOXFFALOX.5fadcf5d5c857fad6b7711009a94de4a</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-12-20T16:22:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for San Luis Obispo County Beaches; San Luis Obispo County Inland Central Coast; San Luis Obispo County Interior Valleys; San Luis Obispo County Mountains; Santa Lucia Mountains; Southern Salinas Valley (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-12-20T16:41:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-12-21T01:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Oxnard (The Los Angeles Area)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Watch issued December 20 at 4:22PM PST until December 21 at 1:00AM PST by NWS Oxnard</headline>
<description>...FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH LATE THURSDAY NIGHT...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues to be
possible.
* WHERE...A portion of southwest California, including the following
areas, Antelope Valley, Calabasas and Agoura Hills, Catalina and
Santa Barbara Islands, Central Ventura County Valleys, Cuyama
Valley, Eastern Antelope Valley Foothills, Eastern San Fernando
Valley, Eastern San Gabriel Mountains, Eastern Santa Monica
Mountains Recreational Area, Interstate 5 Corridor, Lake Casitas,
Los Angeles County Beaches, Los Angeles County Inland Coast
including Downtown Los Angeles, Los Angeles County San Gabriel
Valley, Malibu Coast, Northern Ventura County Mountains, Ojai
Valley, Palos Verdes Hills, San Luis Obispo County Beaches, San
Luis Obispo County Inland Central Coast, San Luis Obispo County
Interior Valleys, San Luis Obispo County Mountains, San Miguel and
Santa Rosa Islands, Santa Barbara County Central Coast Beaches,
Santa Barbara County Inland Central Coast, Santa Barbara County
Interior Mountains, Santa Barbara County Southeastern Coast, Santa
Barbara County Southwestern Coast, Santa Clarita Valley, Santa
Cruz and Anacapa Islands, Santa Lucia Mountains, Santa Susana
Mountains, Santa Ynez Mountains Eastern Range, Santa Ynez
Mountains Western Range, Santa Ynez Valley, Southeastern Ventura
County Valleys, Southern Salinas Valley, Southern Ventura County
Mountains, Ventura County Beaches, Ventura County Inland Coast,
Western Antelope Valley Foothills, Western San Fernando Valley,
Western San Gabriel Mountains and Highway 14 Corridor and Western
Santa Monica Mountains Recreational Area.
* WHEN...Through late Thursday night.
* IMPACTS...There is a high risk of extensive roadway flooding,
especially in low-lying areas. There will likely be rock and
mudslide activity on and below canyon and mountain roadways.
Significant travel delays and road closures are likely. There is a
risk of flash flooding and debris flows in and around recent burn
scars, especially the South Fire burn scar in Ventura County.
Significant creek flooding is expected, with enhanced river flows
and a low but present risk of flooding of the Ventura River.
Swiftwater rescues are expected.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- Periods of moderate to heavy rain are expected with this
storm system. There is also a chance of thunderstorms.
Rainfall totals of 2 to 5 inches are likely in most of the
forecast area, with 5 to 10 inches probable on and below
south facing foothills and coastal slopes. Rainfall rates of
0.30 to 0.60 inches per hour are likely, with rates up to
1.00 inch per hour near thunderstorms, and on and below
favored south facing slopes.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood</description>
<instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ038-087-088-340>358-362-366>383-548>550</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KLOX.FA.A.0008.000000T0000Z-231222T1200Z/
/00000.0.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>San Luis Obispo County Beaches; San Luis Obispo County Inland Central Coast; San Luis Obispo County Interior Valleys; San Luis Obispo County Mountains; Santa Lucia Mountains; Southern Salinas Valley</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ340</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ341</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ342</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ343</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ344</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ345</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>