<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 04 Jan 2024 10:02:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CT12688438E628.HydrologicOutlook.12688439124CCT.BOXESFBOX.3bf519414e1e5b5176438533aa88c81e</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-04T17:02:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Hartford; Tolland; Windham (Connecticut) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-04T17:02:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-04T18:15:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Boston (Southeast New England)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued January 04 at 5:02PM EST  by NWS Boston</headline>
<description>...THE WINTER/SPRING FLOOD POTENTIAL HAS EXPIRED...
The winter/spring freshwater flood potential is above normal
across most of southern New England, but is near normal on
Cape Cod and the Islands. The threat of flooding due to ice
jams is below normal for early January.
For a graphical depiction of this outlook, go to:
http://www.weather.gov/nerfc/springfloodpotential
This is the first winter/spring flood potential outlook of the
2024 season. This outlook is based on current and forecast
conditions including temperatures, precipitation, snow cover,
snow water content, river flows, soil moisture, and ice coverage.
...RECENT TEMPERATURES AND PRECIPITATION...
December, 2023 was a warm and wet month in southern New England.
Temperatures averaged 3 to 6 degrees above normal for the month.
It was the second warmest December on record in Hartford and
Worcester and the third warmest December on record in Boston and
Providence.
Precipitation averaged 1 to 4 inches above normal, but was as
much
as 5 to 6 inches above normal from parts of Connecticut into
northwest Rhode Island and interior northeast Massachusetts. It
was
drier on Cape Cod and the Islands where precipitation totals were
1 to 2 inches below normal for December.
...OBSERVED SNOW DEPTHS AND SNOW WATER CONTENT...
The ground is currently bare with little or no snow cover in
southern New England. This is below normal for early January.
...SOIL MOISTURE, RIVER FLOWS, AND GROUND WATER CONDITIONS...
Soil moisture was well above normal. The wettest conditions
were found in Connecticut, Rhode Island, and in western, central,
and
interior eastern Massachusetts.
Streamflows were above normal, except were near to below normal
across
parts of Cape Cod. The highest streamflows were found in
northeast
Massachusetts along the Sudbury, Charles, and Concord Rivers.
River
ice was non existent.
Groundwater levels were mostly above normal, but were near normal
from far southern Rhode Island into extreme southeastern
Massachusetts,
and were below normal on Marthas Vineyard, Nantucket, and the
outer
portion of Cape Cod. Nantucket reported its lowest median
groundwater
level in its 40 year period of record to begin January. Edgartown
reported close to its lowest median groundwater level on record
for
early January in its 43 year period of record. Wellfleet reported
its
lowest median record for early January in its 59 year period of
record.
...TEMPERATURE AND PRECIPITATION OUTLOOK...
An active weather pattern looks to continue for the next few
weeks. The
first storm system Sunday should bring accumulating snow to much
of
southern New England, then a warmer storm around the middle of
next week
could bring flooding rain in addition to runoff from melting
snow. Over
the next seven days, precipitation should average 2 to 4 inches.
Looking farther ahead, odds favor a continuation of the warm and
wet
weather pattern through the end of January.
...SUMMARY...
The winter/spring flood outlook for freshwater flooding is above
normal in southern New England, except near normal on Cape Cod
and the Islands.
The overall weather pattern has led to above normal precipitation
and temperatures across most of the region except on Cape Cod and
the Islands where conditions have been drier than normal. An
active
weather pattern is expected to continue for the next couple of
weeks, along with above average temperatures, which favors an
increased potential for flooding.
Flooding rain can occur any time during the year. The Graphical
Hazardous Weather Outlook can provide a heads-up for excessive
rainfall over the next five days:
https://www.weather.gov/erh/ghwo?wfo=box
The next Winter/Spring Flood Potential Outlook will be issued on
Thursday, January 18.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CTC003-013-015-MAC001-005-007-009-011-013-015-017-019-021-023-025-027-RIC001-003-005-007-009</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Hartford; Tolland; Windham</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>009003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>009013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>009015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CTC003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CTC013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CTC015</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>