<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.e75e54e5b93a8175802c73a3023f1228aabe9166.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-16T11:04:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-16T11:04:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-16T11:04:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-17T15:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Medford OR</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued July 16 at 11:04AM PDT by NWS Medford OR</headline>
        <description>Oregon Department of Environmental Quality has issued an Air
Quality Advisory...in effect until 10 AM PDT Thursday.

The Oregon Department of Environmental Quality issued an air quality
advisory for Klamath County. Check current air quality conditions
and advisories on DEQs Air Quality Index or by downloading the
OregonAIR on your app on your smartphone.

Many county health and local air agencies have also issued wood
burning restrictions limiting the use of wood stoves, fireplaces and
outdoor burning. There are often exceptions for those who use wood
exclusively to heat their homes and those with limited income. Check
with your local heath or air agency for current restrictions.

People can take the following precautions to protect their health:

- Follow local burn restrictions to prevent deteriorating air
quality.
- Avoid strenuous outdoor activity during periods of poor air quality.
- People with heart or lung problems and young children are
especially vulnerable. These people should stay indoors while smoke
levels are high.
- Use certified High Efficiency Particulate Air (HEPA) filters in
indoor heating, ventilation, cooling and air purification systems.
- Avoid using wood-burning stoves and other sources of indoor smoke
if possible.

DEQs color-coded Air Quality Index provides current air quality
conditions and ranks air quality as follows: Green is good. Yellow is
moderate. Orange is unhealthy for sensitive groups such as children,
the elderly, pregnant women and those with respiratory conditions.
Red is unhealthy for everyone. Purple is very unhealthy for all
groups. Maroon is hazardous.

Pollutants in smoke can cause burning eyes, runny nose, aggravate
heart and lung diseases, and aggravate other serious health
problems. Limit outdoor activities and keep children indoors if it
is smoky. Please follow medical advice if you have a heart or lung
condition.

For additional information...please visit the web site at
https://oregonsmoke.org
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAMFR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS76 KMFR 161804</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT UNTIL 10 AM PDT THURSDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Klamath, OR; Lake, OR</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041035</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041037</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORC035</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORC037</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>