<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.de4339707da48a0de4cca4f160e3ccc1136e0b56.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-07-16T09:10:00-06:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-07-16T09:10:00-06:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-07-16T09:10:00-06:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-07-17T09:00:00-06:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Pueblo CO</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued July 16 at 9:10AM MDT by NWS Pueblo CO</headline>
        <description>The Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment has
issued the following...

WHAT...Air Quality Health Advisory for Wildfire Smoke.

WHERE...Mesa, Garfield, Eagle, Pitkin, Lake, Delta, Gunnison,
Chaffee, Montrose, San Miguel and Ouray Counties. Locations
include, but are not limited to Grand Junction, Glenwood Springs,
Eagle, Vail, Aspen, Leadville, Delta, Gunnison, Buena Vista,
Salida, Montrose, Nucla, Telluride and Ouray.

WHEN...800 AM Wednesday July 16 to 900 AM Thursday July 17

IMPACTS...Multiple wildfires will produce periods of moderate to
heavy smoke across the advisory area through early Thursday
morning. The heaviest smoke impacts will likely be in close
proximity to the South Rim fire in eastern Montrose County, the
Sowbelly Fire and Turner Gulch fires in southern Mesa County, and
areas directly downwind of the Deer Creek fire in Montrose and San
Miguel Counties. Thunderstorms are possible near the fires on
Wednesday, and may produce gusty, erratic winds that can send
smoke in any direction.

HEALTH INFORMATION...Public Health Recommendations: If smoke is
thick or becomes thick in your neighborhood you may want to remain
indoors. This is especially true for those with heart disease,
respiratory illnesses, the very young, and older adults. Consider
limiting outdoor activity when moderate to heavy smoke is present.
Consider relocating temporarily if smoke is present indoors and is
making you ill. If visibility is less than 5 miles in smoke in
your neighborhood, smoke has reached levels that are unhealthy.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAPUB</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS75 KPUB 161510</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY HEALTH ADVISORY FOR WILDFIRE SMOKE FROM 800 AM WEDNESDAY UNTIL 900 AM THURSDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Lake, CO; Chaffee, CO</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>008065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>008015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>COC065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>COC015</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>