<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 18 Dec 2022 01:24:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MS12641E8611B0.SpecialWeatherStatement.12641E955648MS.LIXSPSLIX.da1727d12480e388f516d90bd247eccb</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-18T07:24:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson (Mississippi) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-17T20:07:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-19T07:30:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS New Orleans (Southeastern Louisiana)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 18 at 7:24AM CST  by NWS New Orleans</headline>
<description>...Rare and Hazardous Arctic Airmass for the Gulf South Expected
at the End of the Week and Through Christmas...
An extremely cold airmass is expected to surge towards the Gulf
coast late this week and will bring a multitude of hazardous
conditions to the area. Hard Freeze and dangerous Wind Chill
conditions would begin as early as late Thursday night and we will
continue to deal with the Arctic air through Christmas Day. Now
is the time to start taking measures to protect your family, pets,
friends, property, and yourself from the likelihood of extreme
and prolonged freezing conditions for southern Mississippi and
southeast Louisiana.
Arctic airmass surging south out of Canada and across the central
United States will quickly move into the Lower Mississippi
Thursday and Thursday night. The cold front is expected to move
into southwestern Mississippi and Southeast Louisiana during the
evening hours with temperatures dropping 20 to 30 degrees or more
in only a few hours. Temperatures will continue to plummet
through the overnight hours with almost the entire area below
freezing before sunrise. Not only will the temperatures plunge but
this will be accompanied by very strong wind and by sunrise
Friday morning there is a high chance that many areas will
experience wind chill readings (apparent temperatures) in the
lower teens and single digits. This has no impact on pipes but for
people and pets the rapidly moving air speeds up the heat loss
over our bodies and can quickly lead to hypothermia. As for pipes,
plants, and property, temperatures will struggle to get above
freezing, if they even do Friday, and there is a chance that many
locations could be below freezing for 24 to possibly even more
than 36 hours. And even if temperatures climb above freezing
Friday or in southwestern Mississippi and the adjacent Louisiana
parishes` case Saturday, they will only be above 32 for a very
short time. Not until Christmas Day does it looks like we will
comfortably get above 32 degrees for much of the area for more
than a few hours.
Every weather event is different and they should all be treated as
such but for at least some modern reference here are a few Arctic
events to relate to; February 2nd through 5th 1996, January 8th
through 11th, 2010, and more recently is February 15th through
17th 2021. However, this event appears to be more potent than the
2021 airmass.
As for reference to the Holiday time frame, surprisingly there
are 2 of the more historic events and not just for our area that
occurred during this time; 1983 December 23rd through 26th and
1989 December 22nd through 25th events. These two are quite
historic events but at this time we are not anticipating testing
those 2 Arctic events. The 1989 Arctic airmass still holds
numerous records across a good portion of the US including here
where single digits were recorded in more than just a few places.
We would have to go back to 1899 to see temperatures recorded
lower than 1989 in much of the area over a multi day stretch. 1985
saw another historic cold front for our area which did set some
all time record lows but it was a short lived airmass with highs
back in the 50s the next day. /CAB/</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>LAZ034>037-039-046>048-056>060-064>071-076>090-MSZ068>071-077-080>082</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028059</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028157</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ082</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>