<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.a30796c3dd3036b41d2ec5dc6aeab3d4eb9159d8.002.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-27T04:31:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-27T04:31:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-27T22:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-27T17:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Warning issued October 27 at 4:31AM EDT until October 29 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents.
For the Coastal Flood Warning, 2 to 3 ft of inundation above
ground level expected in low-lying areas near shorelines and
tidal waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking
waves of 10 to 15 feet expected in the surf zone.

* WHERE...Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 8 AM EDT this
morning through this evening. For the Coastal Flood Warning,
from 10 PM this evening to 8 PM EDT Wednesday. For the High
Surf Advisory, from 10 PM this evening to 2 AM EDT Thursday.

* IMPACTS...Numerous roads may be closed. Low lying property
including homes, businesses, and some critical infrastructure
will be inundated. Some shoreline erosion will occur.
Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and localized beach
erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away
from shore into deeper water.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Gale force NE'rly winds and powerful long
period swell will begin to impact Hatteras Island later tonight.
As this occurs, wave runup and ocean overwash are forecast to
develop, especially across the more vulnerable areas of Hwy 12
where weakened dune structures are noted.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 270831</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 8 AM EDT THIS MORNING THROUGH THIS EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 10 PM THIS EVENING TO 8 PM EDT WEDNESDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT FROM 10 PM THIS EVENING TO 2 AM EDT THURSDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.CF.W.0006.251028T0200Z-251030T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-29T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>