<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 17 Jan 2024 06:47:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CA126884FEB8BC.HydrologicOutlook.1268850DE8A0CA.MTRESFMTR.b422bb8c102abca14c56e851cb593a65</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2024-01-17T10:47:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Monterey; San Benito; Santa Clara (California) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2024-01-17T10:47:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2024-01-18T10:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Monterey (The San Francisco area)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued January 17 at 10:47AM PST  by NWS Monterey</headline>
<description>...MODERATE TO HEAVY RAINFALL WILL LEAD TO MODERATE AND
POTENTIALLY RAPID RISES ALONG AREA STREAMS AND CREEKS...
* WHAT...Periods of moderate to heavy rainfall will bring the
potential for moderate to rapid rises along area rivers,
streams, and creeks across the region. This could result in
nuisance as well as minor flooding. Although most sites are
forecast to remain below flood stage, some locations may reach
monitor stage, especially in Sonoma County. This system will
result in an increased risk of shallow landslides as soils near
saturation across the Bay Area. Latest model guidance suggests
the coastal ranges will receive the greatest accumulation of
precipitation. Rainfall totals will range from 1.5 to 3 inches
across most areas with 3-5 inches expected over the North Bay.
Locally up to 5 to 7 inches over favored peaks and higher
terrain of the the North Bay and 4 to 6 inches in the Santa
Cruz and Santa Lucia Mountains.
* WHERE...For the entire forecast area from Napa and Sonoma
Counties and south through Monterey and San Benito Counties.
Although the current forecast shows these creeks and rivers
remaining below flood stage, some locations may reach monitor
stage. The creeks that are most likely to see rapid rises are
located within Sonoma County such as Mark West, Green Valley,
and Laguna De Santa Rosa. However, rapid rises could also occur
along the San Francisquito Creek and San Lorenzo River.
* WHEN...Friday through Monday.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Localized ponding of water in low-lying or
poorly drained areas, such as freeway offramps.
Details regarding this storm will likely change as the system
nears. Therefore, stay tuned to the latest forecast for the most
up to date weather information. Confidence is high that we will
receive rainfall from this system. However, confidence is moderate
with respect to location and total rainfall amounts.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC053-069-085</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Monterey; San Benito; Santa Clara</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>006085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAC085</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>