<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 19 Jul 2023 03:06:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-HI126654D41A08.HurricaneLocalStatement.126654D5560CHI.HFOHLSHFO.8b25aa907c919b4bef1c3db70a5b4798</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-07-19T05:06:00-10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Big Island East; Big Island Interior; Big Island North; Big Island South; Big Island Southeast; Big Island Summit; Kohala; Kona (Hawaii) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-07-19T04:49:00-10:00</effective>
<expires>2023-07-19T13:15:00-10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Honolulu (Hawaii)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued July 19 at 5:06AM HST  by NWS Honolulu</headline>
<description>This product covers the Hawaiian islands
**TROPICAL STORM CALVIN PASSING SOUTH OF THE BIG ISLAND**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Hawaii County
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 250 miles south-southeast of Honolulu or about 170 miles
southwest of Hilo
- 17.8N 156.8W
- Storm Intensity 45 mph
- Movement West or 275 degrees at 20 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Tropical Storm Calvin, currently located near South Point of the Big
Island, will continue westward today, while passing well south of
the smaller islands. Periods of heavy rainfall, damaging winds, and
life threatening surf along exposed east facing shores are expected.
Bands of heavy rainfall will continue to move ashore and impact
portions of the Big Island through the early morning hours, especially
for the southeast facing slopes of the Kau district. Rainfall totals
overnight have reached the 4 to 6 inch range on the Big Island and an
additional 2 to 4 inches remain possible as Calvin begins to move away.
Similar conditions are expected across the smaller islands today as
Calvin passes far to the south.
Damaging winds are expected through the first half of the day for
the Big Island and Maui County, which could lead to power outages,
downed trees and powerlines, potentially leading to impassable
roads. Advisory-level winds are anticipated for Oahu and Kauai, with
the strongest winds occurring over and downwind of terrain.
Significant coastal impacts will continue along exposed east facing
shores of the Big Island and Maui this morning due to a combination
of damaging onshore winds and life-threatening surf. For Oahu and
Kauai, the surf will rapidly build to advisory levels this morning,
then remain up into tonight. The threat of coastal impacts will
lower quickly for the Big Island later today as Calvin continues
westward, then for the smaller islands by Thursday.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
the Hawaiian islands. Potential impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* SURGE:
Protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across portions of windward and southeast Big Island.
Potential impacts in this area include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas
farther inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Sections of near-shore roads and parking lots become overspread
with surge water. Driving conditions dangerous in places where
surge water covers the road.
- Moderate beach erosion. Heavy surf also breaching dunes, mainly
in usually vulnerable locations. Strong rip currents.
- Minor to locally moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks,
and piers. A few small craft broken away from moorings.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across across Maui and windward and southeastern
portions of the Big Island. Potential impacts include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with swifter
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams, creeks, canals,
arroyos, and ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across the Hawaiian islands. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
Listen to local officials for recommended actions and be ready in case
you lose electrical power. Keep a battery-powered radio, charged cell
phone and flashlight handy. Keep your cell phone charged and in power-
saving mode. If you lose power, use it sparingly and mainly for
personal emergencies and check-ins.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Honolulu HI around 12 PM HST, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ023-026>028-051>054</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Big Island East; Big Island Interior; Big Island North; Big Island South; Big Island Southeast; Big Island Summit; Kohala; Kona</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>015001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ026</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ028</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ052</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>HIZ054</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>