<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6bec60f6f15975572375d168de71a979df6bb953.001.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-08T12:52:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Red Flag Warning</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FWW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-08T12:52:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-09T14:00:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-09T05:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Medford OR</senderName>
        <headline>Red Flag Warning issued August 8 at 12:52PM PDT until August 9 at 8:00PM PDT by NWS Medford OR</headline>
        <description>The National Weather Service in Medford has upgraded the Fire
Weather Watch to a Red Flag Warning, which is in effect from 2 PM
to 8 PM PDT Saturday.

* IMPACTS...Moderate to strong winds combined with critically
low relative humidity can lead to rapid growth and spread of
new and existing fires. Outdoor burning is banned during fire
season.

* AFFECTED AREA...Portions of the Rogue Valley in Fire zone
622, this includes the communities of Medford, White City,
Gold Hill, Jacksonville, Talent, Phoenix, and Ashland. In
Fire weather zone 622, the Illinois Valley, including the
communities of Selma, Cave Junction, O'Brien, and Takilma.

* WIND...In the Rogue Valley. Northwest 10 to 15 mph with gusts
as high as 25 mph. In the Illinois Valley. Northeast winds 10
to 15 mph with gusts as high as 25 mph.

* HUMIDITY...12 to 15 percent.

* DETAILED URL...View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr
</description>
        <instruction>Avoid tossing burning cigarettes on the ground, parking hot
vehicles on vegetation, and using equipment that can cause
sparks. One less spark, one less wildfire. Follow all fire
restrictions. Find links to restrictions at
weather.gov/medford/wildfire for links to fire restrictions in
your area.

Gather your fire evacuation kit now. Collect essentials you don't
want to lose and prioritize your checklist. Be sure you're signed
up for your county's emergency alert system. Familiarize yourself
with your emergency plan and make sure you listen to emergency
services. Visit ready.gov/plan for more information.

Be sure you're signed up for your county's emergency alert
system. Familiarize yourself with your emergency plan and make
sure you listen to emergency services. Visit ready.gov/plan for
more information.

A Red Flag Warning is issued when we identify weather conditions
that promote rapid spread of fire which may become life-
threatening. This does not mean there is a fire. These conditions
are either occurring now or will begin soon. It is important to
have multiple ways to receive information from authorities.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>RFWMFR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWUS86 KMFR 081952</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>RED FLAG WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM PDT THIS EVENING FOR STRONG GUSTY WIND AND LOW RH FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 620 AND 622... ...RED FLAG WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM TO 8 PM PDT SATURDAY FOR STRONG GUSTY WIND AND LOW RH FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 620 AND 622</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMFR.FW.W.0017.250809T2100Z-250810T0300Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-09T20:00:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Western Rogue Basin including the Illinois Valley; Eastern Rogue Valley</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041015</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041019</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041029</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>041033</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORZ620</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ORZ622</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>