<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ced2f0fea7d6a56f6f2e739e56b413b1fd97c33b.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-14T15:41:00-09:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-14T15:41:00-09:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-14T15:41:00-09:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-15T05:00:00-09:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Anchorage AK</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued November 14 at 3:41PM AKST by NWS Anchorage AK</headline>
        <description>A deep storm developing in the Pacific is expected to cross into
the eastern Bering Sea between late Saturday night and midday
Sunday. Confidence in the overall storm track has increased, but
some uncertainty remains. The most likely storm track is from the
eastern Aleutians Sunday morning to St. Matthew Island on Monday,
passing just east of the Pribilof Islands. A second, but less
likely track would bring the low over Nunivak Island.

For the Eastern Aleutians and Alaska Peninsula, the most likely
impact is strong southeasterly winds becoming southwesterly as the
storm passes overhead sometime Sunday afternoon. With higher
confidence in the track, the storm's timing and strength will
determine the severity of the impacts, so stay tuned to the
forecast for more details.

For Southwest Alaska, the most likely scenario is gusty
southeasterly winds from the Western Capes north into the greater
Y-K Delta region. Precipitation along the leading storm front is
likely to be snow, but a transition to freezing rain and rain is
expected as the storm moves north. Given the recent snow and cold
temperatures, rain falling onto frozen or snow-covered ground is
likely to create difficult travel conditions. Minor coastal
flooding impacts are possible with the projected storm track, but
the limited fetch and lower tide cycle should help mitigate storm
surge from this storm. The less likely, but still possible,
scenario would bring the low near Nunivak Island, which would lead
to a larger fetch and potential for more coastal erosion and/or
flooding. Stay tuned to the forecast as we continue to monitor
this system.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSALU</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWAK82 PAFC 150041</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>STRONG STORM TO BRING GUSTY WINDS, SNOW, RAIN, AND FREEZING RAIN TO COASTAL AREAS THIS WEEKEND</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Kuskokwim Delta Coast and Nunivak Island; Interior Kuskokwim Delta; Western Capes; Central Alaska Peninsula; Northern Bristol Bay Coast; Southern Alaska Peninsula; Eastern Aleutians; Pribilof Islands</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002050</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002164</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002070</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002013</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002016</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ755</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ756</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ757</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ761</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ764</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ781</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ785</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ795</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>