<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 11 Nov 2022 03:22:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12641823D988.HurricaneLocalStatement.126418251528FL.TBWHLSTBW.6f27625c8cc9199e584dd5a666d96cd3</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-11-10T22:22:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Charlotte; Coastal Citrus; Coastal Hernando; Coastal Hillsborough; Coastal Lee; Coastal Levy; Coastal Manatee; Coastal Pasco; Coastal Sarasota; DeSoto; Hardee; Highlands; Inland Charlotte; Inland Citrus; Inland Hernando; Inland Hillsborough; Inland Lee; Inland Levy; Inland Manatee; Inland Pasco; Inland Sarasota; Pinellas; Polk; Sumter (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-11-10T22:21:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-11-11T06:30:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Tampa Bay (West Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued November 10 at 10:22PM EST  by NWS Tampa Bay</headline>
<description>This product covers West Central and Southwest Florida
**NICOLE NOW A DEPRESSION...SOME LINGERING HAZARDS REMAIN ACROSS WEST
CENTRAL AND SOUTHWEST FLORIDA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- All watches and warnings have been canceled
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 130 miles northwest of Cedar Key FL
- 30.7N 84.3W
- Storm Intensity 35 mph
- Movement Northwest or 320 degrees at 15 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Nicole has weakened to a depression and has lifted north of the
area. All warnings have been discontinued at this time. However,
onshore winds will keep the threat of coastal flooding of up to 3 feet
across the Nature Coast, and 1 to 2 feet will continue to be possible
around Tampa Bay. In addition, rip currents will continue to be
possible through Friday, and winds and seas remain within Advisory
levels across the coastal waters.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Little to no additional impacts are anticipated at this time
across West Central and Southwest Florida.
* SURGE:
Minor coastal flooding will continue to be possible overnight with up
to 3 feet of inundation possible in the Nature Coast.
- Community officials are now assessing the extent of actual
surge impacts accordingly.
- Emergency response teams are attending to casualty situations
as needed.
- Emergency work crews are restoring essential community
infrastructure as necessary.
- If you have an emergency dial 9 1 1.
Elsewhere across West Central and Southwest Florida, little to no
impact is anticipated.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Little to no additional impacts are anticipated at this time
across West Central and Southwest Florida.
* TORNADOES:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across West Central
and Southwest Florida.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Remain safely sheltered until conditions improve. When going outside
be sure to stay away from downed power lines, hazardous debris and
flooded areas.
If your home or shelter was damaged, be alert to the smell of gas
leaks and be cautious around electrical wiring, broken glass, jagged
metal and wood, and protruding nails and screws.
Check to see if everyone in your group is OK. Administer first aid to
those who are injured. If possible, call 9 1 1 for any serious
injuries. Remember, it may be difficult for emergency responders to
arrive quickly.
Check in with your emergency points of contact. Let them know your
location and status. Keep conversations short and to the point. Do
not tie up communications systems.
Check on your neighbors. If necessary, help them connect with their
points of contact.
Do not attempt to return to evacuated areas until local authorities
have inspected roads and bridges and have given the all clear.
Hazards like downed power lines and trees, washed out roads,
continued flooding in low lying areas and non-functioning traffic
lights make travel difficult.
Do not go sightseeing within impacted communities. Sightseers
interfere with the emergency work of first responders.
When inspecting damage, use flashlights rather than candles or flamed
lanterns. Be aware of sparks that can ignite natural gas or other
leaking flammables.
Do not go up on your roof until the weather conditions are safe.
Ladders can be slippery in the rain and unexpected wind gusts can
blow you off the roof.
When clearing out fallen trees, be careful with chainsaws and axes.
Always wear protective gear and keep others at a safe distance.
Leaning trees and those which have fallen on roofs or power lines can
be especially dangerous. If you are not in good health or unsure
about what you are doing, have someone with tree cutting experience
do the job. Never cut trees without a partner.
If using a generator, avoid carbon monoxide poisoning by following
instructions provided by the manufacturer. Operate your generator in
a well-ventilated space outside of your living area and away from
open doors and windows.
Problems with sewer backups can further contaminate standing flood
waters. Keep children away from flood waters. Also, listen for boil
water alerts as tap water may have become non-potable.
Be alert for any lingering wind gusts which could take down weakened
trees and/or power lines, collapse damaged structures, or cause
flying debris.
Be alert for potential flooding from rising rivers and streams which
may have yet to crest. Remain informed of the latest river forecasts
and heed any flood watches and warnings.
Be alert for flooded roads which could be compromised or littered
with debris. Avoid travel until water levels subside and roads have
been cleared. Do not drive through places where flood waters cover
the road. Turn around, don`t drown!
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
As it pertains to this event...this will be the last local statement
issued by the National Weather Service in Tampa Bay Ruskin FL
regarding the effects of tropical cyclone hazards upon the area.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ043-050-052-056-057-061-139-142-148-149-151-155-160-162-165-239-242-248-249-251-255-260-262-265</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Charlotte; Coastal Citrus; Coastal Hernando; Coastal Hillsborough; Coastal Lee; Coastal Levy; Coastal Manatee; Coastal Pasco; Coastal Sarasota; DeSoto; Hardee; Highlands; Inland Charlotte; Inland Citrus; Inland Hernando; Inland Hillsborough; Inland Lee; Inland Levy; Inland Manatee; Inland Pasco; Inland Sarasota; Pinellas; Polk; Sumter</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012075</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012105</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012115</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012119</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ050</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ052</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ056</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ139</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ142</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ148</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ151</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ155</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ160</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ162</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ165</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ239</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ242</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ248</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ249</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ251</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ255</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ260</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ262</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ265</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>