<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL126418158144.StormSurgeWarning.126418168A80FL.MLBTCVMLB.319ce27dc4d3757db7a2b36001969058</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-11-10T04:21:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Storm Surge Warning</event>
<urgency></urgency>
<severity></severity>
<certainty></certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-11-10T04:21:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-11-10T11:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Storm Surge Warning issued November 10 at 4:21AM EST until further notice by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>...TROPICAL STORM WARNING IN EFFECT...
...STORM SURGE WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...HURRICANE WARNING IS CANCELLED...
A Tropical Storm Warning means tropical storm-force winds are
expected somewhere within this area within the next 36 hours
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Tropical Storm force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 35-45 mph with gusts to 70 mph
- Window for Tropical Storm force winds: through the next few
hours
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 58
to 73 mph
- The wind threat has decreased from the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for dangerous wind of equivalent strong tropical
storm force.
- PREPARE: Last minute efforts to protect life and property
should now be complete. The area remains subject to
significant wind damage.
- ACT: Now is the time to shelter from dangerous wind.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main wind event are unfolding.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Life-threatening storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 3-5 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: Around high tide
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 3 feet above ground
- The storm surge threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Shelter against life-threatening storm surge of
greater than 3 feet above ground.
- PREPARE: Flood preparations and ordered evacuations should
be complete. Evacuees should be in shelters well away from
storm surge flooding.
- ACT: Remain sheltered in a safe location. Do not venture
outside.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main surge event are unfolding.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Flood Watch is in effect
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: Additional around 1 inch
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for
moderate flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
moderate flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues
are possible.
- PREPARE: Consider protective actions if you are in an area
vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action may result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Significant
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations
and rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with
swifter currents and overspill their banks in a few places,
especially in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams,
creeks, canals, and ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken
foundations. Several places may experience expanded areas
of rapid inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and
poor drainage areas. Some streets and parking lots take on
moving water as storm drains and retention ponds overflow.
Driving conditions become hazardous. Some road and bridge
closures.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is unfavorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Tornadoes not expected
- The tornado threat has decreased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Tornadoes are not expected. Showers and thunderstorms
with gusty winds may still occur.
- PREPARE: Little to no preparations needed to protect
against tornadoes at this time. Keep informed of the latest
tornado situation.
- ACT: Listen for changes in the forecast.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Little to None
- Little to no potential impacts from tornadoes.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMLB.SS.W.1017.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River</areaDesc>
<polygon>27.74,-80.38 27.69,-80.37 27.66,-80.35 27.6,-80.33 27.56,-80.32 27.56,-80.33 27.56,-80.33 27.56,-80.33 27.56,-80.36 27.56,-80.38 27.56,-80.39 27.61,-80.39 27.61,-80.41 27.63,-80.41 27.68,-80.43 27.68,-80.48 27.76,-80.52 27.8,-80.54 27.82,-80.52 27.82,-80.51 27.86,-80.49 27.86,-80.48 27.86,-80.46 27.86,-80.45 27.74,-80.38 27.74,-80.38</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>