<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 21 Feb 2023 09:53:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-CO126637263644.WinterWeatherAdvisory.12663741E6F0CO.BOUWSWBOU.ea6709b0aac439ae7de384d75aa46912</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-02-21T14:53:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Central and East Adams and Arapahoe Counties; North Douglas County Below 6000 Feet, Denver, West Adams and Arapahoe Counties, East Broomfield County (Colorado) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Weather Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-02-22T02:00:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2023-02-22T20:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Boulder (Northeastern Colorado)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Weather Advisory issued February 21 at 2:53PM MST until February 22 at 8:00PM MST by NWS Boulder</headline>
<description>...A WINTER STORM ARRIVES THIS AFTERNOON INTO WEDNESDAY IMPACTING
NORTHERN COLORADO...
.Snow will become widespread in the mountains overnight and will
spread from north to south along the I-25 corridor behind a cold
front early Wednesday morning. Travel will deteriorate in the I-25
corridor north of Denver before rush hour Wednesday morning, and
snowy or icy roads will likely develop in the Denver metro area
around sunrise. The most likely times for accumulating snow in the
Front Range cities will be around the morning and evening rush hours.
In the mountains, snow will become widespread overnight and will be
heavy at times in the Rabbit Ears and Cameron Pass areas. In the
I-70 corridor the snow will initially be light, but heavy snow
showers are likely Wednesday afternoon.
Temperatures will also drop sharply, from around freezing in the
early morning hours to the single digits in the afternoon. Be
prepared for below zero wind chills by the end of the day Wednesday.
The snow will end Wednesday evening, but it will remain cold into
Thursday.
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 2 AM TO 8 PM MST
WEDNESDAY...
...WIND CHILL ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM MIDNIGHT WEDNESDAY NIGHT TO 9
AM MST THURSDAY...
* WHAT...For the Winter Weather Advisory, snow expected. Total snow
accumulations between 2 and 4 inches. Winds gusting as high as 45
mph. For the Wind Chill Advisory, very cold wind chills expected.
Wind chills as low as 25 below zero.
* WHERE...Denver, and Byers.
* WHEN...For the Winter Weather Advisory, from 2 AM to 8 PM MST
Wednesday. For the Wind Chill Advisory, from Midnight Wednesday
Night to 9 AM MST Thursday.
* IMPACTS...Plan on slippery road conditions. The hazardous
conditions could impact the Wednesday morning and evening
commutes. The dangerously cold wind chills could cause frostbite
on exposed skin in as little as 30 minutes.</description>
<instruction>The combination of wind and cold temperatures will create
dangerously low wind chill values. If you go outside, cover all
parts of your body, especially your head, face, and hands.
Slow down and use caution while traveling. The latest road
conditions for Colorado can be obtained by calling 5 1 1 or by going
to www.cotrip.org.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ040-045</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KBOU.WC.Y.0003.230223T0700Z-230223T1600Z/
/O.CON.KBOU.WW.Y.0014.230222T0900Z-230223T0300Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Central and East Adams and Arapahoe Counties; North Douglas County Below 6000 Feet, Denver, West Adams and Arapahoe Counties, East Broomfield County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008014</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>008031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ040</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>COZ045</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>