<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b1f6d75d777fff981ca7523a96266a32da55322e.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-03-25T15:57:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-03-25T15:57:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-03-25T15:57:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-03-26T01:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued March 25 at 3:57PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>The South Carolina Department of Environmental Services in Columbia
SC has issued an Air Quality Alert for fine particulates for Pickens
County and the northern half of Greenville County in Upstate region
region of South Carolina, from 7 PM this evening to noon EDT
Wednesday. An Air Quality Alert means that the fine particulate
concentrations within the specified areas may approach or exceed
unhealthy standards due to local wildfire smoke.

Winds will turn out of the north-northwest across the mountainous
terrain of South Carolina this evening. This is expected to push
smoke from the Table Rock wildfire in Pickens County and the
Persimmon Ridge wildfire in Greenville County southward into parts of
the Upstate. As winds become light and variable across the foothills
late tonight, stable conditions will enhance the noticeability of
smoke, especially for locations along and north of a line from
Pumpkintown to Travelers Rest. Increased mixing will help to disperse
the smoke by early afternoon Wednesday.

South Carolina DES recommends that individuals with respiratory
health issues limit time spend outdoors and/or move all activities
indoors to avoid the smoke or fine particulates. Keep windows and
doors closed. Run an air conditioner if you have one but keep the
fresh-air intake closed and the filter clean to prevent outdoor
smoke and fine particulates from getting inside.

For more information about fine particulates, please visit:
https://fire.airnow.gov.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS72 KGSP 251957</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT FROM 7 PM THIS EVENING TO NOON EDT WEDNESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Pickens Mountains; Greenville Mountains; Greater Pickens; Central Greenville</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045077</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ102</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ105</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ106</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>