<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5429b7fa915378730ff55d4d333230a838e84020.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-07T14:26:00-09:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-07T14:26:00-09:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-08T09:00:00-09:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-08T02:30:00-09:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Watch issued November 7 at 2:26PM AKST until November 9 at 3:00PM AKST by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>An atmospheric river will advance up from the south and move into
the panhandle beginning Saturday and continuing through Sunday. This
system will deliver heavy rainfall to the southern and central
panhandle beginning Saturday afternoon and continuing through Sunday
morning, before rainfall rates taper off through Sunday afternoon,
with the greatest rainfall amounts across the southern panhandle.
High winds are also expected through the time period, with the
highest wind gusts across the southern panhandle.

* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is possible.

* WHERE...The following areas, Prince of Wales, Southern Inner
Channels and Central Inner Channels. This includes the cities of
Petersburg, Craig, Klawock, Hydaburg, Coffman Cove, Thorne Bay,
Wrangell, Ketchikan, And Metlakatla.

* WHEN...From Saturday morning through Sunday afternoon.

* IMPACTS...Excessive runoff may result in flooding of rivers,
creeks, streams, other low-lying areas and flood-prone locations.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- An atmospheric river moving into the panhandle is set to
deliver heavy rain and wind across the southern and central
panhandle. Heavy rainfall begins Saturday afternoon, and
intensifies through Saturday evening, with the heaviest
rainfall rates Saturday night into early Sunday morning.
Rainfall totals through Sunday will be between 2-5 inches
near sea level, with the higher amounts in the southern
panhandle. These are consistent with 24 hour ARIs of 2 - 5
years. Areas at elevation will receive higher rainfall
amounts beyond this, as favorable SE wind enhances local
orographic forcing. The highest rainfall totals at elevation
will likewise be for the southern panhandle. Concurrent with
the rain, windy conditions will be present across the
southern and central panhandle, with the strongest winds for
the southern panhandle. High winds are expected for Prince of
Wales Island, Annette Island, and Ketchikan, with wind gusts
of between 65 to 70 mph near sea level, and higher wind gusts
aloft. These winds, similar to the heavy rain, will be
strongest Saturday night into early Sunday morning.
</description>
        <instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.

Isolated landslides are possible in areas of steep terrain.

Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFAAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK67 PAJK 072326</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WATCH IN EFFECT FROM SATURDAY MORNING THROUGH SUNDAY AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.PAJK.FA.A.0003.251108T1800Z-251110T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-09T15:00:00-09:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Petersburg Borough; Prince of Wales Island; City and Borough of Wrangell; Ketchikan Gateway Borough; Annette Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002195</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002198</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002275</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002130</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ326</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ328</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ329</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ330</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ332</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>