<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.58c65621da0dd6650daa6e39e85d4d8f88bc10d7.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-07T13:51:00-09:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>WSA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-07T13:51:00-09:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-09T00:00:00-09:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-08T15:00:00-09:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Winter Storm Watch issued November 7 at 1:51PM AKST until November 9 at 3:00PM AKST by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>...INCOMING STORM COULD BRING HEAVY SNOW TO THE NORTHERN PANHANDLE...

.This weekend's snowfall event has high potential to be a heavy
snow maker to the higher elevations of the Klondike, but for the
Haines Highway there is still some uncertainty. Even higher
uncertainty at sea level in Skagway and Haines.

A low pressure system is forecast to track north through the
eastern gulf through Saturday night. The low will then move
northeast just south of Cross Sound and move inland towards Canada
just north of Juneau. That being said, there is some evidence
that the low could track west and stay in the gulf through Sunday
or turn towards Canada and track south of Juneau on Sunday. These
other tracks would greatly affect the final snowfall amounts but
for now, the following amounts are based on the first track.

Another variable is the precipitation type forecast. As this low
moves north, the front side of the low will have northerly flow,
that would usher in cooler air and support snow. But as the low
tracks north, there will be a southerly push of wind that would
switch the snow to rain. The question is whether or not the
southerly push makes it that far north. There is more evidence in
the models that the switch to rain would happen because of the
southerly push but history and pattern recognition would say snow
would last into Sunday afternoon. So the precip type forecast will
be a challenge.

* WHAT...Heavy snow possible. Total snow accumulations of 6 to 8
inches possible passed mile marker 20. For Haines, amounts up to
2 to 4 inches.

* WHERE...Haines Highway and Klukwan.

* WHEN...From late Saturday night through Sunday afternoon.

* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Ahead of this low, northerly flow would
pull cooler air into the area, which would support snow. And as
the low tracks into Canada, we would expect winds to stay out of
the west, allowing for cooler air to continue to get pulled in
and keep the chances for snow in the forecast. But the southerly
push of wind could usher in warmer air that would switch the
snow to rain. So low confidence on the precip type forecast for
now. But if the temperature profile can stay cold enough to
support snow, heavy snow would be likely late Saturday night
into Sunday morning.
</description>
        <instruction>Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WSWAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWAK47 PAJK 072251</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>WINTER STORM WATCH IN EFFECT FROM LATE SATURDAY NIGHT THROUGH SUNDAY AFTERNOON</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.PAJK.WS.A.0007.251109T0900Z-251110T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-09T15:00:00-09:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Haines Borough and Klukwan</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002100</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ319</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>