<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.eab80876ca2b0a484e186d01fc19acb203645ee9.004.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-03-28T00:53:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-03-28T00:53:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-03-28T00:53:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued March 28 at 12:53AM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>The South Carolina Department of Environmental Services in Columbia
SC has issued an Air Quality Alert for Fine Particulates for the
Greenville mountains of South Carolina, until midnight EDT tonight.

High pressure drifting east off the Southeast Coast will continue to
dominate the region through today, minimizing dispersion from the
Table Rock wildfire in Pickens County and the Persimmon Ridge
wildfire in Greenville County. Stable conditions and light westerly
winds overnight through early this morning along the mountains of
South Carolina will enhance the noticeability of smoke in the
mountainous areas of Greenville County. Increasing southwesterly
winds during the late morning and through the afternoon will continue
to disperse and transport the smoke into the mountainous portions of
Greenville County and into North Carolina.

SCDES recommends that individuals with respiratory health issues
limit time spent outdoors and/or move all activities indoors to
avoid the smoke or fine particulates. Keep windows and doors closed.
Run an air conditioner if you have one but keep the fresh-air intake
closed and the filter clean to prevent outdoor smoke and fine
particulates from getting inside. Please note that locations closest
to the wildfire activity are more likely to experience smoke at any
given time. Anytime you see or smell smoke, take necessary
precautions.

For more information about fine particulates, please visit
https://fire.airnow.gov.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS72 KGSP 280453</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT TONIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Greenville Mountains</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ103</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>