<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 28 May 2022 09:47:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NM1263F564EDEC.RedFlagWarning.1263F58275B0NM.EPZRFWEPZ.d925f5baa3d5a2afce5876922ff287d8</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-05-28T03:47:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Capitan And Sacramento Mountains; South Central Lowlands And Southern Rio Grande Valley; Southwest Deserts and Lowlands; Southwest Mountains (New Mexico) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Red Flag Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FRW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-05-29T10:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-05-29T21:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS El Paso (Southern New Mexico and extreme Western Texas)</senderName>
<headline>Red Flag Warning issued May 28 at 3:47AM MDT until May 29 at 9:00PM MDT by NWS El Paso</headline>
<description>...CRITICAL FIRE WEATHER CONDITIONS ARE EXPECTED TODAY AND ON
SUNDAY...
.An approaching upper level system will create stronger west to
southwest winds Saturday and Sunday afternoons. Winds look to
become gusty in the higher terrain locations as stronger winds
aloft move over the area, especially over the Gila Region and
Sacramento Mountains. Afternoon humidity values will remain in
the single digits through the weekend as well, with overnight
humidity recoveries struggling to make it over 30%. A very dry
spring has led to extremely dry fuels over much of southern New
Mexico and far west Texas. These critical fire weather conditions
are expected to persist through the holiday weekend; with winds
strengthening in the afternoon hours, afternoon humidity values
remaining extremely dry, and overnight humidity recoveries hardly
reaching 30%. Similar conditions are expected on Monday except
the winds will be slightly weaker than they are this weekend.
...RED FLAG WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 11 AM THIS MORNING TO
8 PM MDT THIS EVENING FOR LOW HUMIDITY AND STRONG WINDS FOR FIRE
WEATHER ZONES 110, 111, 112, AND 113... ...RED FLAG WARNING IN
EFFECT FROM 10 AM TO 9 PM MDT SUNDAY FOR LOW HUMIDITY AND STRONG
WINDS FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 110, 111, 112, AND 113... ...FIRE
WEATHER WATCH IN EFFECT FROM MONDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH MONDAY
EVENING FOR LOW HUMIDITY AND STRONG WINDS FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES
110, 111, 112, AND 113...
The National Weather Service in El Paso Tx/Santa Teresa has
issued a Red Flag Warning, which is in effect from 10 AM to 9 PM
MDT Sunday. a Fire Weather Watch has also been issued. This Fire
Weather Watch is in effect from Monday afternoon through Monday
evening. The Fire Weather Watch is no longer in effect.
* WIND...Southwest winds of 20 to 30 mph with gusts up to 40
mph. Potentially stronger gusts in higher terrain areas.
* HUMIDITY...5 to 10%.
* IMPACTS...Any fires that develop will likely spread rapidly.
Outdoor burning is not recommended. Please check with the
local agencies for updated burn ban information.</description>
<instruction>A Red Flag Warning means that critical fire weather conditions
are either occurring now, or will shortly. A combination of
strong winds, low relative humidity, and warm temperatures can
contribute to extreme fire behavior.
A Fire Weather Watch means that critical fire weather conditions
are forecast to occur. Listen for later forecasts and possible
Red Flag Warnings.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ110>113</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.UPG.KEPZ.FW.A.0022.220529T1600Z-220530T0300Z/
/O.NEW.KEPZ.FW.W.0036.220529T1600Z-220530T0300Z/
/O.NEW.KEPZ.FW.A.0023.220530T1800Z-220531T0200Z/
/O.CON.KEPZ.FW.W.0035.220528T1700Z-220529T0200Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Capitan And Sacramento Mountains; South Central Lowlands And Southern Rio Grande Valley; Southwest Deserts and Lowlands; Southwest Mountains</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>035051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ110</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ112</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NMZ113</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>