<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 20 Dec 2022 12:58:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12641EA47C68.SpecialWeatherStatement.12641EB1D340FL.MOBSPSMOB.9bd7dc672ff724f2a2dea3f3320dfb0c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-20T07:58:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Escambia Coastal; Escambia Inland; Santa Rosa Coastal; Santa Rosa Inland (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-20T10:36:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-20T19:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Mobile (Mobile - Pensacola)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 20 at 7:58AM EST  by NWS Mobile</headline>
<description>...A SURGE OF ARCTIC AIR WILL BRING BITTERLY COLD TEMPERATURES TO
THE REGION LATE THIS WEEK AND INTO THE CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY WEEKEND...
An arctic cold front is forecast to sweep across southeast
Mississippi, southwest and south central Alabama, and the western
Florida panhandle late Thursday night into early Friday morning.
Dangerously cold temperatures are expected to settle into our area
following the passage of the cold front late this week and into
the upcoming Christmas holiday weekend. Low temperatures early
Friday morning will likely fall into the teens to near 20 degrees
across southeast Mississippi and much of interior southwest
Alabama along and northwest of the Interstate 65 corridor, with
lows in the mid 20s to lower 30s across the remainder of south
central Alabama and the western Florida panhandle. High temperatures
on Friday are only expected to reach into the mid 20s to lower
30s across much of southeast Mississippi and interior southwest
Alabama. The coldest temperatures are expected on Friday night
with temperatures expected to fall into the teens over most areas
along and north of Interstate 10, with freezing temperatures in
the 20s expected all the way to the immediate coast and beaches.
Highs on Christmas Eve are currently forecast to only reach into
the 30s over most of our region, while lows early Christmas
morning once again fall into the teens and 20s. Highs on Christmas
Day are expected to remain cold in the 30s to lower 40s across
the area.
Blustery northwesterly winds are expected to bring dangerously
low wind chills in the single digits and teens across our region
Friday morning through Christmas morning, with a few spots over
interior areas potentially below zero. Widespread Hard Freeze
Watches and Wind Chill Watches for this outbreak of arctic air
will likely become necessary across much of our region and may be
issued later today or tonight.
Residents across the area should continue to monitor the forecast
closely this week. Prepare now for bitterly cold temperatures.
Take steps to protect water pipes and ensure people, animals, and
sensitive vegetation will have ready access to warmth late this
week and this holiday weekend.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ALZ051>060-261>266-FLZ201>206-MSZ067-075-076-078-079</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Escambia Coastal; Escambia Inland; Santa Rosa Coastal; Santa Rosa Inland</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ201</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ202</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ204</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>