<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 20 Dec 2022 01:47:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MS12641EA49F2C.SpecialWeatherStatement.12641EB3F620MS.LIXSPSLIX.da1727d12480e388f516d90bd247eccb</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-20T07:47:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson (Mississippi) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-23T00:00:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-21T08:00:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS New Orleans (Southeastern Louisiana)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued December 20 at 7:47AM CST  by NWS New Orleans</headline>
<description>...Significant Impacts and Probably Dangerous  Will Begin to
Impact the Region Thursday Night as a Potent Arctic Airmass moves
into the area...
We are still anticipating an extremely cold airmass to surge
towards the Gulf coast Thursday and Thursday Night. This airmass
will lead to a multitude of hazardous conditions across the area.
Hard Freeze, duration of freezing temps, very strong winds, and
dangerous Wind Chill conditions would begin as early as Thursday
night and will continue to impact the region even after Christmas.
Now is the time to start taking measures to protect your family,
pets, friends, property, and yourself from the likelihood of
extreme and prolonged freezing conditions for southern Mississippi
and southeast Louisiana.
The Arctic airmass will start to surge south out of Canada and
across the central United States Wednesday and Wednesday night
and approach the Lower Mississippi Valley Thursday. The cold front
is expected to move at a rapid clip likely entering southwest Ms
around or shortly after sunset. The cold front will not slow down
and should be well into the Gulf before sunrise. How fast is the
front moving, it could be through Key West and approaching Cuba
around early evening. Once the front moves through temperatures
will rapidly drop and could fall by some 20 to 30 degrees or more
in only a few hours. Temperatures will continue to plummet through
the early morning hours with almost the entire area below
freezing around sunrise. The rapid temperature drop will
accompanied by very strong and possibly damaging winds which will
also produce dangerous and possibly life threatening wind chill
readings. The wind chill is now expected to fall into the single
digits and lower teens over a large portion of the area Friday
morning; there is even a small chance of a few locations
registering a wind chill of below zero.
Impacts:
- First the extremely cold temperatures being forecast. As we
mentioned there is a lot out there that says it is possible to
see morning lows in the single digits and that would be a first
for almost every location in the CWA since 1996. Lows this cold
will absolutely wreak havoc on exposed pipes, sensitive
vegetation, and possibly fatal to many animals and people if
they are unable to find cover and warm up.
- Second the duration. There is a good chance that many locations
drop below freezing early Friday and won`t see 33 degrees or
warmer till Saturday afternoon. And even if they did it would be
such a short duration above freezing that it would be almost
negligible. This would lead to a number of locations
experiencing as much as 30 to 36 hours of below freezing temps.
Locations that stay below freezing all day Friday would be
expected to climb above freezing Saturday afternoon but that may
only be for 2 to 4 hours leading to some locations possible
being at or below 32 degrees for approximately 55 out of 60
hours.
- Third the wind. The wind will be absolutely brutal for multiple
reasons. One it could be damaging leading to loss of power along
with hazardous driving conditions. Two it will make the wind
chill quite dangerous. The winds will be out of the north and
north-northwest which is perpendicular to interstates 10 and 12
along with major US hwy 190. Wind gusts of 35 to 45 mph maybe
topping out around 50 mph will be quite hazardous along the
elevated highways and to high profile vehicles. Also wind gusts
of this magnitude can bring down weak or dead trees and/or
previously damaged tree limbs onto powerlines, vehicles, and
even you if you are outside. Christmas decorations should be
secured otherwise your neighbor some 2 to 3 blocks away could
be the new owner.
- Wind Chill. So with the combination of very cold temperatures
and very strong winds, we are expecting to deal with dangerous
if not life threatening wind chill values for the Gulf coast.
These values aren`t crazy overall but for south MS and south LA
we are just not use to this. Many will not have the proper
clothing to protect against this. If you must be outside make
sure to dress in layers. Try to find as many breaks as possible
to take cover to warm up. Exposed skin is the most crucial part
and your body heat will quickly be pulled away with these winds
which could lead to Hypothermia and that can set in very
quickly.
- Travel. This is the Christmas Holiday weekend and with Christmas
on a sunday there is a very good chance that a large majority of
people will begin their travel to their destination on Friday.
With road congestion expected to be much greater than normal the
winds will complicate things making travel somewhat hazardous.
The other concern is given the amount of people expected on the
road, any accident could lead to far greater and longer backups.
If you get caught in a traffic jam or your vehicle breaks down
on Friday, this could quickly turn into a more dire situation.
If you are unable to get off the road and warm up you will have
the potential of becoming a victim of the cold. Plan ahead of
bring extra gear such as additional clothes which includes
socks, undergarments, and a hat. Never underestimate the benefit
of a pair of DRY SOCKS and a HAT. Also bring multiple blankets.
Just a few easy things to remember that we normally don`t have
to concern ourselves with.
Here is a rerun of the historical information provided the last
two days. Again this is just some info from prior Arctic airmasses
you can reference but as always every weather event is different
and they should all be treated as such.
These are the more recent events to have occurred; February 2nd
through 5th 1996 which recorded a low of 4 at Liberty, MS and 9
at McComb, MS. January 8th through 11th, 2010, with a low
temperature of 12 recorded at Clinton, LA and 14 in Woodville, MS.
More recently is February 15th through 17th 2021. In that one St
Francisville, LA fell to 16 degrees and Poplarville, Ms dropped to
17. We can`t use the Jan 17th and 18th Winter event; yes it was
cold and it appears that we even had one Co-Op site record 9
degrees for a low on the 17th, Poplarville Exp Station. This
station has a continuous data history back 1919 and partial data
back to 1896. This was part of a major winter storms for the deep
south that brought snow and ice across the region and closed I-10
from Lafayette to Slidell, LA and out airmass late this week will
not be a winter storm, just a very cold airmass.
As for reference to the Holiday time frame, surprisingly there
are 2 of the more historic events and not just for our area that
occurred during this time; 1983 December 23rd through 26th and
1989 December 22nd through 25th events. These two are quite
historic events but at this time we are not anticipating testing
those 2 Arctic events.
The 1983 airmass saw its coldest morning on Christmas Day with 11
observations dropping below 10 degrees. The coldest was
Pascagoula bottoming out at 6 degrees closely followed by
Woodville, Poplarville, and Tylertown, MS recording 8 degrees.
The 1989 Arctic airmass is the last real brutal cold airmass to
hit the region. In 3 days from the 22nd to the 25th there were 24
readings below 10 degrees. Some locations hit single digits twice
in those days. The coldest reading occurred in Clinton, LA where
the mercury fell to 1 degree...yes 1. Liberty, Ms dropped to 3
degrees while Baton Rouge came in with a reading of 8 degrees on
the 23rd.
Prior to 1989 we would have to go back to 1899 to see such
widespread single digit lows and even the 1899 event actually
brought below zero temperature readings.
1985 saw another historic cold front for our area which did set
some all time record lows but it was a short lived airmass with
highs back in the 50s the next day.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>LAZ034>037-039-046>048-056>060-064>071-076>090-MSZ068>071-077-080>082</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Amite; Hancock; Harrison; Jackson; Pearl River; Pike; Walthall; Wilkinson</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028059</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028113</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>028157</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ068</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ070</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ071</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MSZ082</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>