<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 05 Sep 2022 11:37:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640BDDC864.FloodAdvisory.12640BDEF84CSC.GSPFLSGSP.0945c05487be5b4c86ffbb9cee7e44b3</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-05T07:37:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Oconee; Pickens (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-05T11:12:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-05T15:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg (Western North Carolina and Northwest South Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Advisory issued September 05 at 7:37AM EDT until September 05 at 3:15PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg</headline>
<description>...FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 715 PM EDT THIS EVENING...
* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is expected.
* WHERE...Portions of western North Carolina and upstate South
Carolina, including the following counties, in western North
Carolina, Transylvania. In upstate South Carolina, Greenville,
Oconee and Pickens.
* WHEN...Until 715 PM EDT Monday.
* IMPACTS...Nuisance to Minor flooding of low-lying areas adjacent
to streams is likely, including farmland, boat-access areas,
greenways, parks, campgrounds, low-water crossings, and
flood-prone roadways.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 720 AM EDT, Multiple rounds of heavy rain have impacted
the region since Sunday.  Over the past 6 hours, doppler
radar indicated about 1-3 inches of new rainfall has occurred
over saturated soils, causing excessive runoff into area
streams. Nuisance to Minor flooding will continue to develop
in isolated to scattered locations across the Advisory area
through this morning hours. Rapid rises on several streams,
including the French Broad from Rosman to Brevard to
Blantyre, the Little River from Cedar Mountain to Penrose,
and the headwaters of the Toxaway River in and near Gorges
State Park as well as the headwaters of the South Saluda
River in and around Table Rock State Park, will result in
flooding of adjacent low-lying areas.
- Additional rainfall amounts of 0.5 to 1.5 inches are expected
over the area early this morning. This additional rainfall
may exacerbate ongoing flooding and cause stream levels to
continue rising.  Additional rounds of rainfall are expected
later today and this may cause new flash flooding concerns.
Please stay weather aware and prepare to seek higher ground
should a Flash Flood Warning be issued.
- Some locations that may experience flooding include...
Brevard, Slater-Marietta, Rosman, Table Rock State Park,
Jocassee Gorges, Gorges State Park, Caesars Head State Park,
Dupont State Forest, Keowee Toxaway State Park, Looking
Glass, Jones Gap State Park, Devils Fork State Park, Rocky
Bottom, Connestee, Sunset and Cedar Mountain.</description>
<instruction>In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.
Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCC175-SCC045-073-077</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KGSP.FA.Y.0133.220905T1137Z-220905T2315Z/
/00000.N.ER.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.OO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Oconee; Pickens</areaDesc>
<polygon>35.03,-83.01 35.05,-83.06 35.13,-82.98 35.16,-83 35.17,-82.98 35.19,-82.99 35.24,-82.83 35.33,-82.65 35.29,-82.61 35.26,-82.62 35.15,-82.58 35.18,-82.45 35.11,-82.49 35.03,-82.5 34.98,-82.64 34.97,-82.76 34.89,-82.95 34.94,-82.99 34.97,-83.04 35.02,-83.04 35.03,-83.01</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045077</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCC073</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCC077</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>