<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5c105410e706bdfe436251c4ae839b3df21a4a84.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2024-11-08T05:35:00+10:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Special Weather Statement</event>
        <responseType>Execute</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Observed</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2024-11-08T05:35:00+10:00</effective>
        <onset>2024-11-08T05:35:00+10:00</onset>
        <expires>2024-11-08T20:00:00+10:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Tiyan GU</senderName>
        <headline>Special Weather Statement issued November 8 at 5:35AM ChST by NWS Tiyan GU</headline>
        <description>Invest 93W, is centered near 8.3N 171.8E, or roughly 90 miles north-
northeast of Majuro, moving slowly to the west-northwest. The Joint
Typhoon Warning Center (JTWC) rates this developing circulation as a
medium risk for development, which means development into a tropical
cyclone (tropical depression) is likely beyond 24 hours.

As 93W continues to move through the northern Marshalls, there will
be an increasing potential for stronger gusts and bursts of heavy
rains, especially for islands and atolls north of Kwajalein and Roi-
Namur. Most of the convection is now north of Majuro, with scattered
showers and isolated thunderstorms expected at the atoll through
this afternoon. Current model guidance shows sustained winds reaching
to near 25 mph with gusts to around 40 mph along with additional
rainfall accumulations of 2 to 4 inches through Saturday night,
mainly north of Kwajalein and Roi-Namur. Majuro, Kwajalein and Roi-
Namur can still expect additional rainfall amounts of up to 2 inches,
with gusts to 30 mph in heavier showers and thunderstorms.

Seas will remain choppy in response to the stronger winds to the
north, so caution is urged for any boating activities. Seas are
expected to range between 6 and 8 feet, but could become higher with
strong gusts. This Special Weather Statement will only be updated if
conditions warrant.

For more information on Invest 93W, see bulletins issued by JTWC
under WMO header ABPW10 PGTW.

Residents across the Marshall Islands should continue monitoring
local weather forecasts from the National Weather Service in Guam,
and for additional information from your local Weather Service Office
and emergency management. Visit weather.gov/gum/PublicForecasts for
the latest weather information from the National Weather Service.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>SPSPQ1</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WWPQ81 PGUM 071935</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>DEVELOPING CIRCULATION WILL CONTINUE TO AFFECT NORTHERN ATOLLS OF THE RMI</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Majuro</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>068190</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>MHZ002</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>