<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 19 Feb 2023 09:07:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-WY12663705CB0C.WinterStormWatch.126637434680WY.CYSWSWCYS.0d244c9cf73cdfb63ca72f2e4111defc</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-02-19T02:07:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Sierra Madre Range; Snowy Range (Wyoming) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-02-20T05:00:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2023-02-23T05:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Cheyenne (Southeastern Wyoming and Western Nebraska)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Watch issued February 19 at 2:07AM MST until February 23 at 5:00AM MST by NWS Cheyenne</headline>
<description>...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 5 PM MST THIS
AFTERNOON...
...WINTER STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM EARLY MONDAY MORNING
THROUGH EARLY THURSDAY MORNING...
* WHAT...For the Winter Weather Advisory, snow. Additional snow
accumulations of up to 4 to 10 inches. Localized areas above
9500 feet elevation could see up to 12 inches of additional
snowfall accumulation. Winds gusting as high as 70-75 mph in
localized areas today. Blowing snow will create visibility
reductions of less than 1 mile at times through this afternoon.
For the Winter Storm Watch, heavy snow possible. Total snow
accumulations of 18 to 36 inches possible. Localized areas up to
48 inches of snowfall above 9500 feet in elevation possible.
Winds could gust as high as 75 mph, creating the potential for
blizzard conditions.
* WHERE...Sierra Madre Range and Snowy Range.
* WHEN...For the Winter Weather Advisory, until 5 PM MST this
afternoon. For the Winter Storm Watch, from early Monday morning
through early Thursday morning.
* IMPACTS...Mountain travel could be very difficult to impossible
due to near zero visibilities in falling and blowing snow,
especially with the second round Monday through Wednesday night.
Outdoor recreation could become life threatening to those
caught unprepared for severe winter conditions. Hikers, skiers,
and snowmobilers may easily become lost or disoriented.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...This will be a long duration event. While
there may be occasional lulls in snowfall, periodic moderate to
heavy snowfall with very strong winds will be possible from
Sunday through early Thursday, and possibly longer. Strong winds
and blowing snow with possible whiteout conditions will be
possible even during lulls in falling snow. Blizzard conditions
are possible as well. Be prepared for several days of difficult
conditions. The cold wind chills as low as 30 below zero could
cause frostbite on exposed skin in as little as 30 minutes on
Wednesday and Thursday.</description>
<instruction>Slow down and use caution while traveling.
Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.
The latest road conditions for the state you are calling from can
be obtained by calling 5 1 1.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WYZ112-114</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KCYS.WW.Y.0012.000000T0000Z-230220T0000Z/
/O.CON.KCYS.WS.A.0003.230220T1200Z-230223T1200Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Sierra Madre Range; Snowy Range</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>056001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>056007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WYZ112</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WYZ114</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>