<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0b462fa32639202af99c0f014a13d4d9c38c6843.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-04T18:24:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-04T18:24:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-04T18:24:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS San Diego CA</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued August 4 at 6:24PM PDT by NWS San Diego CA</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...The South Coast AQMD has issued an air quality alert due to
increased fine particle pollution from wildfire smoke.

* WHERE...San Bernardino Mountains, Angeles National Forest, San Jacinto
Mountains, Coachella Valley, the Santa Rosa Reservation, and parts
of the Inland Empire. Levels of particle pollution can vary by
time and location depending on fire activity and local weather
conditions.

* WHEN...Through Tuesday evening.

* IMPACTS...Particles in wildfire smoke can get deep into the lungs
and cause serious health problems such as heart attacks, strokes, asthma
attacks, and difficulty breathing. Everyone can be affected, but
people with lung or heart disease, older adults, people who are
pregnant, children, and those who spend a lot of time outdoors are
at greater risk.
</description>
        <instruction>To protect your health, if you smell or see smoke:

* Remain indoors with windows and doors closed
* Avoid intense outdoor physical activity
* Run your air conditioner and/or an air purifier
* If you must be outdoors, keep the time brief and wear a well-fitting
N-95 mask
* Do not use whole house fans or swamp coolers that bring in outside
air if you have other methods to stay cool
* Avoid other sources of pollution such as fireplaces, candles, incense,
grilling, and gasoline-powered lawn and garden equipment

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the South
Coast Air Quality Management District website at aqmd.gov or
download the mobile app at www.aqmd.gov/mobileapp. Additional
details for this air quality alert may be available at
www.aqmd.gov/advisory.

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the Mojave
Desert Air Quality Management District website at mdaqmd.ca.gov.
Additional details for this air quality alert may be available at
www.mdaqmd.ca.gov/advisories.

To view current and forecasted air quality levels, visit the
antelope Valley Air Quality Management District website at
www.avaqmd.ca.gov.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQASGX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS76 KSGX 050124</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT FOR HARMFUL FINE PARTICLE POLLUTION LEVELS DUE TO WILDFIRE SMOKE</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>San Bernardino and Riverside County Valleys-The Inland Empire; San Bernardino County Mountains; Riverside County Mountains; Coachella Valley; San Gorgonio Pass Near Banning</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ048</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ056</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ061</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ065</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>