<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 14 Jun 2022 07:08:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NV1263FA86A6D0.SpecialWeatherStatement.1263FA95E5F0NV.REVSPSREV.f979f97d7abeb60543a0c0683ad0d61c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-06-14T12:08:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Greater Reno-Carson City-Minden Area; Mineral and Southern Lyon Counties; Northern Washoe County; Western Nevada Basin and Range including Pyramid Lake (Nevada) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-06-14T12:08:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2022-06-15T12:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Reno (Western Nevada)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued June 14 at 12:08PM PDT  by NWS Reno</headline>
<description>...Warm and Windy Week with a Cool Weekend...
Temperatures: Plan on a couple of hot days this week on Wednesday
and Thursday. Heat Risk levels near Moderate levels with an
increased risk of heat health impacts for those without effective
cooling or hydration options. Western Nevada valleys will be in
the mid 90s, and near 100 for central Nevada locations by Thursday
afternoon.
Winds: Strong, gusty winds will develop later this week as
another system approaches the West. Widespread wind gusts 35 to 50
mph will be possible Thursday into Saturday. Spots along Highway
395 through Mono County and along Highway 95 near Walker Lake may
see gusts 60+ mph. Plan on plenty of travel and recreation
impacts from Thursday into Saturday, including but not limited to
aviation turbulence, high profile vehicle restrictions, choppy
lake conditions and areas of blowing dust.
The windy and dry conditions may also produce localized critical
fire weather conditions, particularly in the eastern Sierra. Be
fire safe and smart and avoid activities that may spark a fire. We
always want to avoid sparking a fire, but especially so on these
during these windy days.
Precipitation Chances: Saturday will be quite breezy, but cooler
than midweek. The system pushing into the region brings the winds,
the cooler temperatures, and chances for precipitation. If you
have outdoor recreation plans, be sure to account for the
possibility of some showers and possibly a thunderstorm or two.
For now, the best chances for showers will be from the Tahoe basin
northward into northeastern California and for areas along the
Nevada-Oregon border. For areas south of Highway 50, the
precipitation potential is looking scarce for now.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ070>073-NVZ001>005</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Greater Reno-Carson City-Minden Area; Mineral and Southern Lyon Counties; Northern Washoe County; Western Nevada Basin and Range including Pyramid Lake</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032510</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ004</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ005</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>