<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.6b2f822441b5a9ff15e752c14ef2c31378a4fdac.004.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-03-26T15:58:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <note>Non-Weather Emergency Message. Not sent to IPAWS.</note>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Air Quality Alert</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Unknown</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Unknown</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>AQA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-03-26T15:58:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-03-26T15:58:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-03-27T04:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</senderName>
        <headline>Air Quality Alert issued March 26 at 3:58PM EDT by NWS Greenville-Spartanburg SC</headline>
        <description>The South Carolina Department of Environmental Services in Columbia
SC has issued an Air Quality Alert for Fine Particulates for the
Greenville mountains of South Carolina, until midnight EDT Thursday
night.

Winds will turn out of the north-northeast across the mountainous terrain
of South Carolina this evening. This is expected to push smoke from the
Table Rock wildfire in Pickens County and the Persimmon Ridge wildfire
in Greenville County southward into parts of the Upstate. As winds become
light and variable across the foothills late tonight, stable conditions
will enhance the noticeability of smoke, especially for locations along
and north of a line from Clemson to Travelers Rest. Light winds will
pick up out of the south-southwest by midday Thursday, which will
disperse and transport the smoke into the mountainous portion of
Greenville County and North Carolina by early afternoon Thursday.

SCDES recommends that individuals with respiratory health issues limit
time spent outdoors and/or move all activities indoors to avoid the smoke
or fine particulates. Keep windows and doors closed. Run an air conditioner
if you have one but keep the fresh-air intake closed and the filter clean
to prevent outdoor smoke and fine particulates from getting inside. Please
note that locations closest to the wildfire activity are more likely to
experience smoke at any given time. Anytime you see or smell smoke,
take necessary precautions.


For more information about fine particulates, please visit
https://fire.airnow.gov.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AQAGSP</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>AEUS72 KGSP 261958</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>AIR QUALITY ALERT IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT THURSDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Greenville Mountains</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>045045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>SCZ103</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>