<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 08 Nov 2022 09:35:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL126417F7023C.HurricaneLocalStatement.126417F80600FL.MLBHLSMLB.2a72fe5429ded96993bea3bfb693c3ca</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-11-08T04:35:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-11-08T04:06:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-11-08T11:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued November 08 at 4:35AM EST  by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>This product covers East Central Florida
**TROPICAL STORM WARNINGS ISSUED FOR THE INTERIOR COUNTIES OF EAST
CENTRAL FLORIDA**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Watch has been upgraded to a Tropical Storm
Warning for Inland Volusia, Northern Lake, Okeechobee, Orange,
Osceola, Seminole, and Southern Lake
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Inland Volusia,
Northern Lake, Okeechobee, Orange, Osceola, Seminole, and
Southern Lake
- A Storm Surge Warning, Tropical Storm Warning, and Hurricane
Watch are in effect for Coastal Indian River, Coastal Martin,
Coastal Saint Lucie, Northern Brevard Barrier Islands, and
Southern Brevard Barrier Islands
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Hurricane Watch are in effect for
Inland Indian River, Inland Martin, Inland Northern Brevard,
Inland Saint Lucie, Inland Southern Brevard, Mainland Northern
Brevard, and Mainland Southern Brevard
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Coastal Volusia
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 540 miles east of Vero Beach FL
- 27.6N 71.6W
- Storm Intensity 45 mph
- Movement Northwest or 310 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Subtropical Storm Nicole is currently well east-northeast of the
northern Bahamas and moving northwest. Nicole is forecast to turn west
and then west-southwest today and tonight, completing transition to a
tropical storm as it moves toward the northern Bahamas through
Wednesday. Nicole is forecast approach the Florida east coast at or
near Hurricane strength late Wednesday, before making landfall late
Wednesday night somewhere along the Space or Treasure Coast.
Given the increasing confidence in the track and intensity forecast
for Nicole, a Tropical Storm Warning has been issued for all interior
counties of east central Florida. Thus, a Tropical Storm Warning is
now in effect for all of east central Florida and the adjacent
Atlantic waters out to 60 nautical miles.
A Hurricane Watch remains in effect for Brevard, Indian River, Saint
Lucie and Martin Counties, including the adjacent Atlantic waters, for
the possibility of hurricane force winds near the forecast point of
landfall. This may need to be upgraded to a Hurricane Warning for parts
of the Florida east coast later today.
Due to the large area of strong winds extending well to the north and
northwest of Nicole`s center, weather and ocean conditions will
continue to steadily deteriorate today through Wednesday. Northeast
winds will increase to 20 to 25 mph with gusts above Tropical Storm
Force in increasing coverage of squalls starting this afternoon and
evening.
As the center of Nicole nears the east coast of Florida late Wednesday,
tropical storm force winds will begin to overspread the region,
beginning along the Treasure Coast, spreading north and inland through
Thursday. Hurricane conditions are possible near and to the north of
where the center makes landfall, with the latest forecast showing the
highest likelihood along the Space and Treasure Coast counties of
Brevard, Indian River, Saint Lucie and Martin.
A Storm Surge Warning remains in effect for the entire east central
Florida coast, for the potential of 3 to 5 feet of surge above ground
level. Surge values could be a little higher along and just to the
north of the forecast track.
Large breaking waves will reach 8 to 10 feet later today, and will
exceed 10 feet beginning late tonight. Numerous life-threatening rip
currents will continue. The strong winds and high surf will combine
with ongoing high astronomical tides to bring significant storm surge
and major beach erosion around the times of the next several high tide
cycles from Tuesday through Thursday. Coastal areas of Volusia County
which suffered serious damage from Hurricane Ian remain particularly
vulnerable to additional beach erosion and inundation from coastal
flooding!
Do not enter the water under any circumstance! Small craft operators
should stay in port until conditions start to improve late this week
or the weekend.
Increasing coverage of showers and squalls is also expected from this
storm starting this afternoon. Squalls will produce wind gusts in
excess of tropical storm force, especially offshore and over coastal
counties. Bands of heavy showers will increase in frequency and
coverage, resulting in rainfall totals of 4 to 6 inches from eastern
Osceola and Brevard Counties northward across the Saint Johns River
Basin. Local totals of around 8 inches are possible. Farther inland,
2 to 4 inches are expected,with locally higher amounts. Urban and poor
drainage flooding is increasingly likely, especially where the water
table remains high.
The combination of heavy rainfall and strong northeast winds could
also cause additional flooding and standing water concerns over the
Saint Johns River Basin, where River Flood Warnings remain in effect.
A Flood Watch will likely be issued for all of east central Florida
later today.
A threat for tornadoes will develop late Wednesday into Wednesday
night as the center of the storm moves inland across the Florida
peninsula, and continue on Thursday.
Now is the time to prepare for significant impacts from Nicole!!
Take this seriously! Don`t let the fact that the calendar says
November or hurricane season fatigue allow you to become complacent
about preparing for this storm! Make sure your hurricane supply kit is
stocked, and you have a plan in place, especially if you live along
the coast or in an area that is either prone to flooding or has
recently experienced flooding
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Protect against life-threatening wind having possible extensive
impacts across Brevard, Indian River, coastal Volusia, Saint Lucie
and Martin Counties. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
Also, protect against dangerous wind having possible significant
impacts across  Lake, Seminole, Orange, Osceola, Okeechobee, and inland
Volusia Counties.
* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts along the east central Florida coast from Flagler Beach to
Jupiter Inlet.  Potential impacts in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across East Central Florida. Potential impacts
include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with swifter
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams, creeks, canals, and
ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across East Central Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
For those not under evacuation orders, assess the risk from wind,
falling trees, and flooding at your location. If you decide to move,
relocate to a safer location nearby. If you do not relocate, help keep
roadways open for those under evacuation orders.
If evacuating, leave with a destination in mind and allow extra time
to get there. Take your emergency supplies kit. Gas up your vehicle
ahead of time.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
When making safety and preparedness decisions, do not focus on the
exact forecast track since hazards such as flooding rain, damaging wind
gusts, storm surge, and tornadoes extend well away from the center of
the storm.
When securing your property, outside preparations should be concluded
as soon as possible before conditions deteriorate. The onset of strong
gusty winds or flooding can cause certain preparedness activities to
become unsafe.
Be sure to let friends and family members know of your intentions for
weathering the storm and your whereabouts. Have someone located away
from the threatened area serve as your point of contact. Share vital
contact information with others. Keep cell phones handy and charged.
Check on those who may not be fully aware of the situation or who are
unable to make personal preparations.
If you are a visitor, know the name of the county in which you are
located and where it is relative to current watches and warnings. If
staying at a hotel, ask the management staff about their onsite
disaster plan. Listen for evacuation orders, especially pertaining to
visitors.
It is important to remain calm, informed, and focused during an
emergency. Be patient and helpful with those you encounter.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 11 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041-044>046-053-058-141-144-154-159-164-247-254-259-264-347-447-547-647-747</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ058</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ144</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ159</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ164</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ247</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ254</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ259</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ347</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ447</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ547</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ647</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ747</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>