<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 08 Nov 2022 09:19:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GA126417F6FBFC.HurricaneLocalStatement.126417F838C8GA.JAXHLSJAX.5de47e0e847b7c0ffb9adcdb8b55d506</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-11-08T04:19:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Appling; Atkinson; Bacon; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Coffee; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Jeff Davis; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Pierce; Southern Ware; Wayne; Western Charlton (Georgia) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-11-08T18:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-11-08T12:30:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Jacksonville (Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued November 08 at 4:19AM EST  by NWS Jacksonville</headline>
<description>This product covers Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia
**STORM SURGE AND TROPICAL STORM WARNINGS CONTINUE FOR THE NORTHEAST
FLORIDA AND SOUTHEAST GEORGIA COAST**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Coastal Camden, Coastal Duval, Coastal Flagler, Coastal
Glynn, Coastal Nassau, and Coastal St. Johns
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Watch are in effect
for Eastern Clay, Eastern Putnam, Inland St. Johns, and South
Central Duval
- A Storm Surge Warning is in effect for Trout River
- A Tropical Storm Watch is in effect for Central Marion, Eastern
Marion, Inland Flagler, Western Marion, and Western Putnam
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 620 miles east-southeast of Jacksonville FL or about 640
miles east-southeast of Brunswick GA
- 27.6N 71.6W
- Storm Intensity 45 mph
- Movement Northwest or 310 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Subtropical Storm Nicole is expected to bring widespread impacts
with prolonged coastal flooding, tropical-storm-force winds, heavy
rainfall, rough surf, and rip currents.
Nicole is currently expected to reach Hurricane level strength as it
crosses through the Bahamas and on towards the southern Florida
peninsula. The continued track has Nicole pressing into the southern
Florida peninsula and reaching towards the Nature Coast by Thursday
evening and then turning its path towards the northeast and crossing
northeast Florida, southeast Georgia and into the Carolinas Friday and
Friday evening.
Localized flash flooding risk on Thursday and Friday, mainly impacting
coastal areas and along the St Johns River. Tropical Storm Warning has
been put into effect for coastal southeast Georgia and northeast
Florida.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across coastal northeast Florida, coastal southeast Georgia,
and the St. Johns River Basin. Potential impacts in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
* WIND:
Protect against dangerous wind having possible significant impacts
across portions of coastal and inland northeast Florida. Potential
impacts in this area include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent
in areas with above ground lines.
Also, protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts
across the rest of northeast Florida and southeast Georgia.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible significant
impacts across coastal northeast Florida and coastal southeast Georgia.
Potential impacts include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with swifter
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams, creeks, canals, and
ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across coastal northeast Florida. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions,
including possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so
immediately.
For those not under evacuation orders, assess the risk from wind,
falling trees, and flooding at your location. If you decide to move,
relocate to a safer location nearby. If you do not relocate, help
keep roadways open for those under evacuation orders.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:Now is the time to complete all
preparations to protect life and property in accordance with your
emergency plan. Ensure you are in a safe location before the onset
of strong winds or possible flooding.
If heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or have
pets. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.
Storm surge is the leading killer associated with tropical storms and
hurricanes! Make sure you are in a safe area away from the surge
zone. Even if you are not in a surge-prone area, you could find
yourself cutoff by flood waters during and after the storm. Heed
evacuation orders issued by the local authorities.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, consider moving to a safer shelter before the onset of
strong winds or flooding.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Jacksonville FL around 1030, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ020-021-023-024-030-031-033-035-038-122-124-125-132-133-136>138-140-222-225-232-236-237-240-325-340-425-GAZ132>136-149-151>154-162-163-165-166-250-264-350-364</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Appling; Atkinson; Bacon; Brantley; Clinch; Coastal Camden; Coastal Glynn; Coffee; Echols; Inland Camden; Inland Glynn; Jeff Davis; Northeastern Charlton; Northern Ware; Pierce; Southern Ware; Wayne; Western Charlton</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013039</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013065</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013101</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013161</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013229</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013299</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>013305</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ132</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ134</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ135</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ136</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ149</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ151</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ152</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ153</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ162</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ163</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ165</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ166</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ250</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ350</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GAZ364</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>