<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 16 Sep 2023 09:38:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NH126660913768.HurricaneLocalStatement.1266609272A4NH.GYXHLSGYX.d2561851b1ae64008252fc6f03cf7f83</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-09-16T05:38:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Belknap; Cheshire; Coastal Rockingham; Eastern Hillsborough; Interior Rockingham; Merrimack; Northern Carroll; Northern Coos; Northern Grafton; Southern Carroll; Southern Coos; Southern Grafton; Strafford; Sullivan; Western And Central Hillsborough (New Hampshire) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-09-16T05:38:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2023-09-16T13:45:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Gray/Portland (Southern Maine)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 16 at 5:38AM EDT  by NWS Gray/Portland</headline>
<description>This product covers NEW HAMPSHIRE AND WESTERN MAINE
**Wind and rain increasing along the coastline as Lee
moves through the Gulf of Maine**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Androscoggin, Central
Interior Cumberland, Coastal Cumberland, Coastal Rockingham,
Coastal Waldo, Coastal York, Interior Waldo, Kennebec, Knox,
Lincoln, Sagadahoc, and Southern Somerset
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 250 miles east-southeast of Portland ME or about 260
miles east-southeast of Portsmouth NH
- 41.8N 66.0W
- Storm Intensity 80 mph
- Movement North or 355 degrees at 25 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Hurricane Lee has become post tropical as it moves northward
through the eastern Gulf of Maine, but continues to generate hurricane
force winds. This technical name change yeilds no changes to the
atnicipated impacts here. The northward movement will continue today, with
landfall expected across western Nova Scotia late this afternoon. The storm
will only gradually weaken today, but the wind field will continue to
expand across our forecast area.
The potential exists for tropical storm conditions to develop by early
this morning along the coastline, which would then continue through
this afternoon. The strongest winds are expected across coastal
portions of New Hampshire and western Maine.
Large, pounding surf in addition to one to three feet of storm surge
will bring the potential for beach erosion and minor to moderate
coastal flooding.
Locally heavy rainfall is also possible at times, particularly across
MidCoast Maine where localized flooding can`t be ruled out.
While the strongest winds are expected closer to the coastline, gusty
winds will likely still be strong enough to lead to scattered power
outages outside of the warning areas. Please check back frequently for
the latest updates.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
coastal New Hampshire and western Maine. Potential impacts in this
area include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, leading to downed power lines.
- A few roads impassable from debris, caused by downed branches
and power lines. Hazardous driving conditions on bridges and
other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages likely.
Elsewhere across NEW HAMPSHIRE AND WESTERN MAINE, little to no impact
is anticipated.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts. Potential impacts include:
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swifter currents.
Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may become swollen
and overflow in spots.
- Flood possible in a few places where rapid ponding of water
occurs at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Several storm drains and retention ponds become
near-full and begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge
closures.
- Backed up drainage systems near the coast could exacerbate the
flooding from rainfall.
Prepare for locally hazardous rainfall flooding having possible
limited impacts across western Maine.
* SURGE:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across NEW
HAMPSHIRE AND WESTERN MAINE.
* TORNADOES:
Little to no impacts are anticipated at this time across NEW
HAMPSHIRE AND WESTERN MAINE.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
For those not under evacuation orders, understand that there are
inherent risks to evacuation (such as traffic congestion, accidents,
and driving in bad weather), so evacuate only if necessary. Help
keep roadways open for those that are under evacuation orders.
If you are exceptionally vulnerable to wind or water hazards from
tropical systems, consider voluntary evacuation, especially if
being officially recommended. Relocate to a predetermined shelter
or safe destination.
If evacuating away from the area or relocating to a nearby shelter,
leave early before weather conditions become hazardous.
Do not return to evacuated areas until hazardous winds diminish and
flood waters abate.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to bring to completion all preparations to protect
life and property in accordance with your emergency plan.
Outside preparations should be wrapped up as soon as possible before
weather conditions completely deteriorate. Any remaining evacuations
and relocations should be expedited before the onset of tropical
storm force wind.
If you are relocating to safe shelter, leave as early as possible. If
heading to a community shelter, become familiar with the shelter
rules before arrival, especially if you have special needs or own a
pet. Take essential items with you from your Emergency Supplies Kit.
Check the latest weather forecast before departing.
Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.
Check-in with your emergency points of contact among family, friends,
and workmates. Inform them of your status and well-being. Let them
know how you intend to ride out the storm and when you plan to
check-in again.
Keep cell phones well charged and handy. Also, cell phone chargers
for automobiles can be helpful after the storm. Locate your chargers
and keep them with your cell phone.
In emergencies it is best to remain calm. Stay informed and focused
on the situation at hand. Exercise patience with those you encounter.
Be a Good Samaritan and helpful to others.
If relocating to a nearby shelter or to the home of a family member
or friend, drive with extra caution, especially on secondary roads.
Remember, many bridges and causeways will be closed once higher winds
arrive. Also, if you encounter water covering the road, seek an
alternate route. Always obey official road signs for closures and
detours.
If you are a visitor and still in the area, listen for the name of
the city or town in which you are staying within local news updates.
Be sure you know the name of the county or parish in which it
resides. Pay attention for instructions from local authorities.
Closely monitor NOAA Weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes to
the forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Gray ME around 11 AM, or sooner if conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MEZ007>009-012>014-018>028-033-NHZ001>015</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Belknap; Cheshire; Coastal Rockingham; Eastern Hillsborough; Interior Rockingham; Merrimack; Northern Carroll; Northern Coos; Northern Grafton; Southern Carroll; Southern Coos; Southern Grafton; Strafford; Sullivan; Western And Central Hillsborough</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033015</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033017</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>033019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ004</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ006</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ008</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ011</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ012</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ014</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NHZ015</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>