<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b6036082e84def777588ee91ab74e8c81c0324c5.002.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-03T16:14:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Rip Current Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>RPS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-03T16:14:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-04T18:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-04T00:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS San Juan PR</senderName>
        <headline>Rip Current Statement issued October 3 at 4:14PM AST until October 7 at 6:00AM AST by NWS San Juan PR</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 10
to 13 feet. For the High Rip Current Risk, life- threatening
rip current.

* WHERE... For the High Surf Advisory, the most vulnerable areas
for high surf and beach erosion include Pinones along Road
187, Parcelas Suarez, Villas del Mar, and Villa Christiana in
Loiza; Fortuna in Luquillo; Pueblo and Tamarindo in Aguadilla;
Bario Obrero, Pueblo and Jareaito in Arecibo; Las Boca in
Barceloneta; Machuca in Manati; Puerto Nuevo in Vega Baja;
Ocean Park in San Juan; and Barrio Espinal in Aguada. For the
High Rip Current Risk, exposed coasts to the Atlantic,
including northwestern to northeastern Puerto Rico, Culebra,
St. Thomas and St. John.

* WHEN...For the High Surf Advisory remains until 6 AM AST
monday. For the High Rip Current Risk remains through late
monday night

* IMPACTS...For the High Surf Advisory, high waves that can wash
over jetties and sweep people and pets onto jagged rocks.
Rough surf may also knock you down. Large breaking waves will
result in localized beach/dune structure erosion and dangerous
swimming conditions, as well as minor coastal flooding in the
most vulnerable areas. For the High Rip Current Risk, rip
currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into
deeper water, where it becomes difficult to return to safety.
</description>
        <instruction>A High Surf Advisory means that high surf will affect beaches in
the advisory area, producing localized beach erosion and
dangerous swimming conditions.

There is a high risk of rip currents.

Rip currents are powerful channels of water flowing quickly away
from shore, which occur most often at low spots or breaks in the
sandbar and in the vicinity of structures such as groins, jetties
and piers. Heed the advice of lifeguards, beach patrol flags and
signs.

If you become caught in a rip current, yell for help. Remain
calm, do not exhaust yourself and stay afloat while waiting for
help. If you have to swim out of a rip current, swim parallel to
shore and back toward the beach when possible. Do not attempt to
swim directly against a rip current as you will tire quickly.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWSJU</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHCA42 TJSJ 032014</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HIGH RIP CURRENT RISK IN EFFECT FROM SATURDAY EVENING THROUGH LATE MONDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXB.TJSJ.RP.S.0024.251004T2200Z-251007T1000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-07T06:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>St Croix</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>078010</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VIZ002</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>