<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:18:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NV1266300CFD48.SpecialWeatherStatement.1266301C3880NV.REVSPSREV.f979f97d7abeb60543a0c0683ad0d61c</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-01-02T04:18:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Greater Reno-Carson City-Minden Area; Mineral and Southern Lyon Counties; Northern Washoe County; Western Nevada Basin and Range including Pyramid Lake (Nevada) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Special Weather Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Observed</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>SPS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-31T10:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2023-01-03T04:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Reno (Western Nevada)</senderName>
<headline>Special Weather Statement issued January 02 at 4:18AM PST  by NWS Reno</headline>
<description>...Fast Moving Storm Later Today Followed by a Bigger Storm
Midweek...
A couple of storm systems are on the docket for the first week of
2023 with additional storms likely into the second week.
FIRST STORM MONDAY PM-TUESDAY AM:
* Snow levels with the first storm will be down to all valley
floors. Snowfall amounts will be light, generally 5 to 10 inches
along the Sierra crest, 2 to 5 inches in the Tahoe Basin and up
to 2 inches elsewhere. Current projections have the snow
starting around commute time late this afternoon with most of
the snowfall occurring through the evening hours. Prepare for
slick roads, especially once the sun sets today.
SECOND STRONGER STORM WEDNESDAY PM-THURSDAY:
* Winds across ridges will increase Wednesday afternoon and peak
overnight with gusts approaching 100 mph. Winds down on the
valley floors do not look overly strong but typical wind prone
areas along Highway 395 and Highway 95 near Walker Lake could
experience gusts above 40 mph.
* Rain and snow return to the region Wednesday afternoon and
evening with an abundant moisture tap, but less favorable
orientation than the storm we just had. This keeps the heavier
precipitation near the Sierra crest, with periods of lighter
precipitation for the eastern Sierra and western Nevada. A cold
frontal passage late Wednesday night into Thursday morning will
spread rain and snow eastward across the region.
* Snow levels will be tricky with this storm and there may be a
period Wednesday afternoon and evening when they rise to 6500-
7000 feet in the Sierra, but stay near 4000-4500 feet in western
Nevada. This is a situation where it rains around Lake Tahoe
while seeing snow or a rain/snow mix in western Nevada valleys.
The aforementioned cold front will drop snow levels Wednesday
night in the Sierra, but help lift snow levels into the
4500-5000 foot range by mid-morning Thursday for western
Nevada.
* Total snow projections for this storm range from 2 to 3 feet
along the Sierra crest and 6 to 12 inches for the Tahoe Basin
and foothills of the eastern Sierra to several inches on valley
floors, mainly near and west of US-95.
If you have travel plans through the Sierra, prepare for winter
weather driving conditions ahead of time and try to avoid the
worst conditions. There will likely be periods of snow and icy
roads even on the valley floors at times this week and possible
next week as well as additional storms arrive.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ070>073-NVZ001>005</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Greater Lake Tahoe Area; Greater Reno-Carson City-Minden Area; Mineral and Southern Lyon Counties; Northern Washoe County; Western Nevada Basin and Range including Pyramid Lake</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032005</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032027</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>032510</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ002</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ004</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NVZ005</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>