<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.513e1e4a36ff8a751ffa8ed29ac5c3888f640bf6.003.4</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-20T15:53:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7ef6de3d6f7b26fa7a6be7f75003f151f627c071.002.2,2025-08-20T03:05:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>High Surf Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-20T15:53:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-20T15:53:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-22T04:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Upton NY</senderName>
        <headline>High Surf Advisory issued August 20 at 3:53PM EDT until August 22 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Upton NY</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the High Rip Current Risk, life-threatening rip
currents. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves
building to 12 to 16 ft through Thursday night, subsiding to and
8 to 12 feet on Friday. For the Coastal Flood Warning, 1 1/2 to
2 feet of inundation above ground level expected in vulnerable
areas near the waterfront and shoreline. For the Coastal Flood
Advisory, up to 1 1/2 ft of inundation above ground level
likely. Moderate coastal flooding potential will be highest for
north facing shoreline areas along the southern and eastern
bays, due to to enhanced wave action. This includes Orient
Point.

* WHERE...Southeast Suffolk County.

* WHEN...For the High Surf Advisory, until 8 PM EDT Friday. For
the High Rip Current Risk, through Friday evening. For the
Coastal Flood Warning, from 5 PM Thursday to 3 AM EDT Friday.
For the Coastal Flood Advisory, from 5 AM to 2 PM EDT Friday.

* COASTAL FLOOD IMPACTS...Widespread minor to locally moderate
flooding of vulnerable areas near the waterfront and shoreline
with Thursday evening's high tide. Expect 1 1/2 to 2 ft of
inundation above ground level in low lying, vulnerable areas.
This will result in numerous road closures and cause widespread
flooding of low lying property including parking lots, parks,
lawns and homes/businesses with basements near the waterfront.
Vehicles parked in vulnerable areas near the waterfront will
likely become flooded.

* SWIMMING IMPACTS...Life-threatening swimming and surfing
conditions and localized beach erosion. Life-threatening rip
currents are likely for all people entering the surf zone.
Anyone visiting the beaches should stay out of the surf. Rip
currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from shore into
deeper water.

* SHORELINE IMPACTS...Along the ocean front, the threat for dune
erosion and beach flooding will increase with successive high
tides thru Fri morning. Widespread areas of dune erosion with
localized overwashes are expected during the Thu evening and Fri
morning high tides along the ocean front. Along the north shore
of the south fork, 2 to 4 ft breaking waves will result in beach
erosion and locally moderate flooding of shoreline roads and
properties during the Thursday evening high tide. Along the
north facing shore of the barrier islands, 1 to 3 ft breaking
waves will result in beach erosion and locally moderate flooding
flooding of shoreline roads and properties during the Thursday
evening high tide
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

If you enter the surf zone, always have a flotation device with
you and swim near a lifeguard. If caught in a rip current, relax
and float, and do not swim against the current. If able, swim in
a direction following the shoreline. If unable to escape, face
the shore and yell or wave for help.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWOKX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS41 KOKX 201953</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>HIGH SURF ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT FRIDAY... ...HIGH RIP CURRENT RISK REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH FRIDAY EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 5 PM THURSDAY TO 3 AM EDT FRIDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 5 AM TO 2 PM EDT FRIDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KOKX.SU.Y.0001.000000T0000Z-250823T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-22T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7f442c94a1e0e09d56622dd0f18b0785b74f8e90.002.1,2025-08-19T15:26:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.74c926704cfd9db2534e9d97f08d3e8717966e65.002.1,2025-08-19T03:16:00-04:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0dc3ea333ca0d2d974000ab3f32e0895043b28b8.002.1,2025-08-19T02:28:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Southeast Suffolk</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>036103</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NYZ081</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>