<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.52b0279c791832ec49284db39268c05d2e5d3a72.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-28T17:30:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Tropical Cyclone Statement</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>HLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-28T17:30:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-28T17:30:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-28T23:00:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Melbourne FL</senderName>
        <headline>Tropical Cyclone Statement issued September 28 at 5:30PM EDT by NWS Melbourne FL</headline>
        <description>HLSMLB

This product covers East Central Florida

** Tropical Storm Watches Cancelled Along the Coast but Prolonged,
Dangerous Beach and Marine Conditions Developing This Week **


NEW INFORMATION
---------------

* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- All watches and warnings have been canceled

* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None

* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 350 miles southeast of Cape Canaveral FL
- 24.2N 77.3W
- Storm Intensity 40 mph
- Movement North or 360 degrees at 9 mph

SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------

At 5 PM, Tropical Storm Imelda was located about 355 miles
southeast of Cape Canaveral, moving toward the north at 9 mph. The
tropical storm is forecast to gradually strengthen but remain well
offshore the Florida east coast Monday and Monday night, and become a
hurricane early Tuesday as it turns northeast and moves out to sea.

Fast moving showers and isolated storms within rainbands will produce
periods of heavy rain in some areas with localized amounts of 1 to
2 inches of additional rainfall possible through Monday night.

Tropical storm force winds are forecast to remain offshore of east
central Florida. As a result, the Tropical Storm Watch has been
cancelled for Volusia, Brevard, Indian River, Saint Lucie and Martin
counties. Nonetheless, breezy and gusty north to northeast winds of
20 to 30 mph are forecast on Monday with gusts up to 40 mph. A Wind
Advisory will be in effect for the coastal counties on Monday. A
Tropical Storm Warning remains in effect for the adjacent Atlantic
coastal waters.

More significantly, at the coast, battering surf through the week will
produce dangerous beach conditions. A HIGH risk of rip currents is
forecast, with breaking waves of 6 to 10 feet. Beach erosion is likely
as waves run up to the dune line or sea walls, especially along the
northern Brevard and Volusia coast. Long-period swells from this
system combined with distant Major Hurricane Humberto will produce the
potential for long-duration moderate beach and dune erosion, along
with high surf conditions, through late week.

--------------------

POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------

* WIND:
North to northeast winds of 20 to 30 mph are forecast on Monday with
gusts up to 40 mph. A Wind Advisory will be in effect for the coastal
counties on Monday.

Elsewhere across East Central Florida, little to no impact is
anticipated.

* SURGE:
Little to no additional surge impacts expected. However, high surf will
cause beach erosion and potential for minor coastal flooding especially
around the times of high tide for the next several days.

* FLOODING RAIN:
Additional impacts from localized heavy rain are still a concern across East
Central Florida. Remain well guarded against locally hazardous flood
waters having further impacts of limited potential.

PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------

* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Prolonged and dangerous beach and marine conditions will develop this
week including a HIGH risk of life threatening rip currents, high surf
with breaking waves of 6 to 10 feet and moderate beach erosion.
Entering the surf is highly discouraged.


* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org

NEXT UPDATE
-----------

As it pertains to this event, this will be the last local statement
issued by the National Weather Service in Melbourne FL regarding the
effects of tropical cyclone hazards upon the area.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>HLSMLB</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WTUS82 KMLB 282130</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>Tropical Storm Watches Cancelled Along the Coast but Prolonged,
Dangerous Beach and Marine Conditions Developing This Week</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Inland Volusia; Northern Lake County; Orange; Seminole; Osceola; Okeechobee; Coastal Volusia; Southern Lake County; Coastal Indian River; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Indian River; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Martin; Mainland Northern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Inland Southern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012127</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012069</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012117</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012097</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012093</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012061</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012111</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012085</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>012009</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ041</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ044</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ045</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ046</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ053</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ058</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ141</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ144</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ154</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ159</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ164</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ247</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ254</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ259</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ264</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ347</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ447</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ547</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ647</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>FLZ747</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>