<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.9dc9eb66cd2a96b88ecbaeff4f8d546fab7229ed.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-11-13T11:37:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Watch</event>
        <responseType>Prepare</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAA</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-11-13T11:37:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-11-15T04:00:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-11-14T01:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Las Vegas NV</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Watch issued November 13 at 11:37AM PST until November 16 at 4:00AM PST by NWS Las Vegas NV</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall is possible.

* WHERE...A portion of southeast California, including the following
areas, Cadiz Basin, Death Valley National Park, Eastern Mojave
Desert, Eastern Sierra Slopes, Morongo Basin, Owens Valley, San
Bernardino County-Upper Colorado River Valley, Western Mojave
Desert and White Mountains of Inyo County.

* WHEN...From late Friday night through late Saturday night.

* IMPACTS...Excessive runoff may result in flooding of rivers,
creeks, streams, and other low-lying and flood-prone locations.
Flooding may occur in poor drainage and urban areas. Low-water
crossings may be flooded. Storm drains and ditches may become
clogged with debris.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- A strong low pressure system with anomalous moisture will
bring heavy rain to Inyo and San Bernardino Counties on
Saturday.

- For San Bernardino County, the most likely scenario is 0.50
to 1.50 inches of precipitation on Saturday with locally
higher totals in areas of higher terrain. In the event of a
worst case scenario, we are looking at 1.50 to 2.00+ inches
of rain possible.

- In Inyo County, the heaviest rain is expected across the
southern half to two thirds of the county on Saturday. For
the lower elevations of Death Valley, the most likely
scenario is 0.25 to 1.00 inches of precipitation on Saturday,
with a most likely scenario of 0.50 to 1.50 inches for the
higher terrain. A worst case scenario for Death Valley would
be over an inch of rain in the lower elevations with the
higher terrain pushing 2.00+ inches. For the southern portion
of the Eastern Sierra Slopes and Owens Valley, the most
likely scenario is 1.00 to 2.00 inches with a worst cased
scenario of 2.00 to 2.50+ inches of rain. The most likely
scenario for Saturday's precipitation in the central portion
of the Eastern Sierra Slopes and Owens valley is 0.50 to 1.50
inches with a worst case scenario of 1.50 to 2.00+ inches of
rain.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>You should monitor later forecasts and be alert for possible Flood
Warnings. Those living in areas prone to flooding should be prepared
to take action should flooding develop.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFAVEF</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS65 KVEF 131937</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WATCH IN EFFECT FROM LATE FRIDAY NIGHT THROUGH LATE SATURDAY NIGHT</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KVEF.FA.A.0008.251115T1200Z-251116T1200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-11-16T04:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Eastern Sierra Slopes of Inyo County; Owens Valley; White Mountains of Inyo County; Death Valley National Park; Western Mojave Desert; Eastern Mojave Desert, Including the Mojave National Preserve; Morongo Basin; Cadiz Basin; San Bernardino County-Upper Colorado River Valley</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006027</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>006071</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ519</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ520</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ521</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ522</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ523</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ524</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ525</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ526</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>CAZ527</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>