<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.65b2e0aec2dff3a9dbe343d8fe4293fc01a502d7.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-05-24T08:03:00-05:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flash Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-05-24T08:03:00-05:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-05-24T08:03:00-05:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-05-24T11:00:00-05:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Little Rock AR</senderName>
        <headline>Flash Flood Warning issued May 24 at 8:03AM CDT until May 24 at 11:00AM CDT by NWS Little Rock AR</headline>
        <description>FFWLZK

The National Weather Service in Little Rock has issued a

* Flash Flood Warning for...
Jackson County in eastern Arkansas...
Southwestern Lawrence County in eastern Arkansas...
Independence County in north central Arkansas...
Southeastern Izard County in north central Arkansas...
Southern Sharp County in north central Arkansas...

* Until 1100 AM CDT.

* At 803 AM CDT, Doppler radar and automated rain gauges indicated
thunderstorms producing heavy rain across the warned area. Between
2.5 and 3 inches of rain have fallen. Additional rainfall amounts
of 1 to 2 inches are possible in the warned area. Flash flooding
is ongoing or expected to begin shortly.

HAZARD...Flash flooding caused by thunderstorms.

SOURCE...Radar and automated gauges.

IMPACT...Flash flooding of small creeks and streams, urban
areas, highways, streets and underpasses as well as
other poor drainage and low-lying areas.

* Some locations that will experience flash flooding include...
Batesville...                      Newport...
Ash Flat...                        Cave City...
Tuckerman...                       Diaz...
Newark...                          Highland in Sharp County...
Swifton...                         Cushman...
Mount Pleasant...                  Grubbs...
Strawberry...                      Lynn...
Oil Trough...                      Jacksonport...
Magness...                         Sidney...
Moorefield...                      Algoa...

Strawberry River

This includes the following streams and drainages...
Town Branch, Mud Creek, Blue Hole Branch, Turkey Creek, Cache
Fork, Bennett Branch, Fool Creek, Double Branch, Lave Creek, West
Lafferty Creek, Mudtown Branch, Cypress Creek Ditch, Deep Slough,
Miller Creek, Bold Spring Branch, Dodd Branch, North Big Creek,
Tom Moore Branch, Locust Creek Ditch, Goodie Creek, Robertson
Branch, Big Creek, Schales Branch, Wolf Bayou, Dry Fork Dota
Creek, Dry Branch, Whaley Creek, Sloan Creek, Black River, Bear
Creek, Little Creek, Turner Creek, Kyler Creek, Brown Creek,
Departee Creek, Salado Creek, Underwood Branch, Village Creek,
Reeds Creek, Hinson Branch, Ladd Branch, Sheriff Springs Branch,
Pumpkin Creek, Moorefield Creek, Hars Creek, Rocky Creek, Fallen
Ash Creek, Long Creek, Cache River, Alderbrook Branch, Maple
Ditch, Piney Fork, May Branch Lateral, Pine Creek, Wooldridge
Creek, Willow Ditch, M R Branch, Rock Creek, White River, Bailey
Brooks Branch, Poke Bayou, Caney Slough, Spring Creek, Pine
Branch, Brier Creek, Glenn Creek, Sullivan Creek, Jamestown Creek,
South Prong Reeds Creek, Cedar Creek, Baker Branch, Greenbrier
Creek, Jack Creek, Jackson Creek, Overcup Slough, Twomile Creek,
Big Spring Branch, Overcup Ditch, Dota Creek, South Big Creek,
Lick Branch, Rocky Branch, Powers Creek, Pfeiffer Creek, Watson
Creek, Cattail Creek, Dry Run, Curia Creek, Dog Lick Branch,
Wycough Branch, Chandler Creek, Old Curia Creek, Blowing Cave
Creek, Mill Creek, Carter Creek, Inman Creek, Old River, Rocky
Bayou, Hamms Schoolhouse Branch, Bird Creek, Chapel Creek, Cow
Lake Ditch, Lafferty Creek, Barren Fork, Strawberry River,
Birchfield Branch, Wilson Branch, Dry Creek, Hackney Creek, Burns
Creek, Caney Creek, Dishwater Branch and Blue Spring Branch.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FFWLZK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS54 KLZK 241303</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>flashFloodDetection</valueName>
            <value>RADAR AND GAUGE INDICATED</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KLZK.FF.W.0063.250524T1303Z-250524T1600Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-05-24T11:00:00-05:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Independence, AR; Izard, AR; Jackson, AR; Lawrence, AR; Sharp, AR</areaDesc>
            <polygon>36.26,-91.54 36.07,-91.3 35.8,-91.04 35.48,-91.04 35.46,-91.06 35.67,-91.79 35.71,-91.79 35.71,-91.84 35.75,-91.84 35.77,-91.86 36.06,-91.83 36.26,-91.54</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005063</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005067</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>005135</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARC063</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARC065</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARC067</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARC075</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>ARC135</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>