<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.d17aa04f37c366d664fa5d6610fe5cbd1dbd73b3.011.2</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-10T15:37:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-10T15:37:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-12T04:00:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-11T16:00:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Fairbanks AK</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Warning issued October 10 at 3:37PM AKDT until October 13 at 10:00AM AKDT by NWS Fairbanks AK</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Major coastal flooding is likely. Record coastal flooding
is possible. Water levels rising 5 to 10 feet above the normal
high tide line. This storm is the remnants of Typhoon Halong and
will bring higher water and stronger winds than the October 8th
storm. Water levels will be very low ahead of the rapid rise
late Saturday night and Sunday morning.

* WHERE...Yukon Delta Coast.

* WHEN...From 4 AM Sunday to 10 AM AKDT Monday.

* IMPACTS...At Hooper Bay, major coastal flooding is expected and
water may approach or surpass record levels. Residences and the
drinking water source may be inundated. Fuel tanks may be
impacted and the road to the airport may be partially submerged.
Airstrip use or access may be cutoff. Water is likely to reach
into the village. If water reaches 10 feet above the normal high
tide line, the wastewater facility may be impacted. At Nunam
Iqua, major coastal flooding is also likely with water levels
approaching or surpassing record levels. The drinking water
source, wastewater facility, fuel tank farm, and lowest
residences may be impacted. Access across Causeway Road and to
the airstrip may be cut off. At Kotlik, major coastal flooding
is expected with water levels approaching or surpassing record
levels. Several buildings may be flooding by 1 foot or more of
water, the airstrip may be covered and access cut off, and the
wastewater lagoon may be impacted. There is a slight chance that
the water treatment plant, fuel tank farm platform, and
evacuation center (the school) may be impacted. At Scammon Bay,
water in the Kun River may back up and flood the west end of the
runway and adjacent low lying areas. Flooding is possible
upstream on the Yukon River to Mountain Village with significant
flooding at Emmonak and Alakanuk possible. At Alakanuk, fuel
tanks at the school, the wastewater facility, airstrip access,
and several buildings may be impacted. Water may also back up
the Ninglikfak River bringing high water to Chevak. Significant
shoreline erosion may occur.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWAFG</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHAK49 PAFG 102337</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 4 AM SUNDAY TO 10 AM AKDT MONDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.PAFG.CF.W.0002.251012T1200Z-251013T1800Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-13T10:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Yukon Delta Coast</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002158</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ825</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>