<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.bc9662962de6042bd9911c30c8549fcaabead1b7.002.3</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-10T15:29:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>High Surf Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>SUY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-10T15:29:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-11T11:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-11T03:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>High Surf Advisory issued October 10 at 3:29PM EDT until October 13 at 8:00AM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, up to 1 to 3 feet of
inundation above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines
and tidal waterways. For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous
rip currents and large breaking waves in the surf zone. For the
High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 7 to 11 feet
expected in the surf zone. For the Coastal Flood Warning, up to
2 to 4 feet of inundation above ground level expected in low-
lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways.

* WHERE...Hatteras Island.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 5 PM EDT
Saturday. For the Beach Hazards Statement, until 8 PM EDT this
evening. For the High Surf Advisory, from 11 AM Saturday to 8
AM EDT Monday. For the Coastal Flood Warning, from 5 PM
Saturday to 8 AM EDT Monday.

* IMPACTS...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, up to 1 to 3 feet of
inundation above ground level with minor ocean overwash possible
in vulnerable locations along shorelines and tidal waterways.
For the Coastal Flood Warning, up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation
above ground level is possible in some areas near shorelines and
tidal waterways resulting in an elevated threat of property
damage around the times of high tide. Flooding will extend
inland from the waterfront threatening some homes and
businesses. Road closures and flooding of vehicles will be
possible, most notably along NC 12 where ocean overwash may make
several portions of the highway inaccessible across Hatteras
Island. For the Beach Hazards Statement and High Surf Advisory,
life-threatening swimming and surfing conditions.
</description>
        <instruction>Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone property. If
travel is required, do not drive around barricades or through
water of unknown depth.

All swimmers should remain out of the water due to life-
threatening surf conditions through the weekend.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 101929</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 5 PM EDT SATURDAY... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 8 PM EDT THIS EVENING... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 11 AM SATURDAY TO 8 AM EDT MONDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 5 PM SATURDAY TO 8 AM EDT MONDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.SU.Y.0009.251011T1500Z-251013T1200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-13T08:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Hatteras Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ205</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>