<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.32ac39d2609643b0d0068821b27cf3bf1b24f348.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-10-10T04:23:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.2c11aaf1608e3a8c49fe840cadfd6dbccae1f204.001.1,2025-10-09T20:40:00-04:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-10-10T04:23:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-10-10T04:23:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-10-10T16:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued October 10 at 4:23AM EDT until October 10 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, dangerous rip currents
and strong longshore currents in the surf zone. For the Coastal
Flood Advisory, 1 to 3 feet of inundation above ground level
expected in low- lying areas near shorelines and tidal
waterways. For the Coastal Flood Watch, 2 to 4 feet of
inundation above ground level possible in low-lying areas near
shorelines and tidal waterways.

* WHERE...Ocracoke Island.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, through this evening.
For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until 5 PM EDT Saturday. For
the Coastal Flood Watch, from Saturday afternoon through
Monday morning.

* IMPACTS...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, up to 1 to 3 feet of
inundation above ground level with minor ocean overwash possible
in vulnerable locations along shorelines and tidal waterways.
For the Coastal Flood Watch, up to 2 to 4 feet of inundation
above ground level is possible in some areas near shorelines and
tidal waterways resulting in an elevated threat of property
damage around the times of high tide. Flooding will extend
inland from the waterfront threatening some homes and
businesses. Road closures and flooding of vehicles will be
possible, most notably along NC 12 where ocean overwash may make
several portions of the highway inaccessible across Ocracoke
Island. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from
shore into deeper water. Strong longshore currents will create
dangerous swimming conditions.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...A coastal low is forecast to move north
along, or just off, the coast of the Carolinas this weekend,
leading to multiple coastal hazards. Depending on the exact
track and strength of the low, there is potential for moderate
to locally major coastal flooding impacts from ocean overwash,
and users are urged to check back in on the forecast the rest of
the week. The most likely time for strong rip currents to occur
is a couple hours either side of low tide, which will occur
around 4:00 PM Friday.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

A Beach Hazards Statement is issued when threats such as rip
currents, longshore currents, and other hazards create
life-threatening conditions in the surf zone. Caution should be
used when in or near the water.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 100823</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT NOW IN EFFECT THROUGH THIS EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 5 PM EDT SATURDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM SATURDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH MONDAY MORNING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.EXT.KMHX.BH.S.0085.251010T0823Z-251011T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-10-10T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Ocracoke Island</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037095</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ204</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>