<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.b8894d285ea4c3827be5f0e785ed547f43ae839f.003.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-22T21:24:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Beach Hazards Statement</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Moderate</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>BHS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-22T21:24:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-23T07:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-23T09:30:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</senderName>
        <headline>Beach Hazards Statement issued August 22 at 9:24PM EDT until August 23 at 8:00PM EDT by NWS Newport/Morehead City NC</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, 1 to 2 feet of inundation
above ground level in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal
waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 6
to 9 feet in the surf zone. For the Beach Hazards Statement,
dangerous rip currents and large breaking waves expected in the
surf zone.

* WHERE...Northern Outer Banks.

* WHEN...For the Coastal Flood Advisory, until midnight EDT
Saturday night. For the Beach Hazards Statement, from 7 AM EDT
Saturday through Saturday evening.

* IMPACTS...Up to 1 to 2 feet of inundation above ground level is
possible in some areas near shorelines and tidal waterways.
Flooding of lots, parks, and roads with only isolated road
closures expected. Additional overwash onto NC-12 is possible
around times of high tide Saturday morning and evening due to
elevated astronomical tides and persisting strong wave energy.
Dangerous swimming and surfing conditions and localized beach
erosion. Rip currents can sweep even the best swimmers away from
shore into deeper water. Dangerous shore break can throw a
swimmer or surfer head first into the bottom causing neck and
back injuries.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...The most likely time for strong rip
currents to occur is a couple hours either side of low tide,
which will occur around 2 pm Saturday.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Life-threatening rip currents. If caught in a rip current, remain
calm. Swim in a direction following the shoreline. If tired,
float or tread water until out of the rip current. If unable to
escape, face the shore and call or wave for help.

Shore break occurs when waves break directly on the beach. It is
extremely important to protect your head and neck whenever you
are in breaking waves by keeping your hands in front of you at
all times.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWMHX</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS42 KMHX 230124</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT SATURDAY NIGHT... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY NOW IN EFFECT UNTIL MIDNIGHT EDT SATURDAY NIGHT... ...BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT IN EFFECT FROM 7 AM EDT SATURDAY THROUGH SATURDAY EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KMHX.BH.S.0055.250823T1100Z-250824T0000Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-23T20:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Northern Outer Banks</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>037055</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NCZ203</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>