<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.7e56cfd9e9c8238b4b2295a920f6f38e3287395c.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-22T16:58:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Future</urgency>
        <severity>Unknown</severity>
        <certainty>Possible</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>ESF</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-22T16:58:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-22T16:58:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-23T01:00:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Elko NV</senderName>
        <headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued August 22 at 4:58PM PDT by NWS Elko NV</headline>
        <description>ESFLKN

Forecast models are showing increasing confidence in a surge of
moisture moving into northern and central Nevada for the upcoming
weekend. Deep subtropical moisture will lead to the development of
showers and thunderstorms across much of central Nevada Saturday
with a mix of wet and dry thunderstorms across and including I-80
north. By Sunday, moisture will be plentiful and will combine with
an unstable atmosphere and slow storm motions of 5 to 10 mph or
less. This will bring the threat of localized heavy rain to the
region. Of great concern will be recent large burn scars left
from the following incidents: the Snowstorm Complex affecting near
Midas, the current Cottonwood Peak fire north of Tuscarora, the
Hot Canyon fire northwest of Montello, the Winnemucca Mountain
fire north of Winnemucca, and the Adobe fire north of Elko.
Numerous other smaller burn scars have been created this past fire
season and are also of concern. The main threat for the upcoming
weekend is heavy rain producing flash flooding and debris flows.
If living near recently burned areas, please have a way to receive
flash flood warnings and be prepared to take action should
warnings be issued. If you are traveling or recreating in these
areas that have burn scars, please consider changing plans.
</description>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>ESFLKN</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FGUS75 KLKN 222358</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Elko, NV; Eureka, NV</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>032007</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>032011</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NVC007</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NVC011</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>