<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Wed, 07 Sep 2022 02:53:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-OR12640BFAF394.RedFlagWarning.12640C0A6F40OR.MFRRFWMFR.e3e4fd1a8f02f29e20f614c53825421b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-06T19:53:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for South Central Oregon Desert including the BLM Land in Eastern Lake and Western Harney Counties (Oregon) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Red Flag Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FRW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-07T14:00:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-07T21:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Medford (Southwest Oregon and Northern California)</senderName>
<headline>Red Flag Warning issued September 06 at 7:53PM PDT until September 07 at 9:00PM PDT by NWS Medford</headline>
<description>...ISOLATED TO SCATTERED DRY THUNDERSTORMS ON WEDNESDAY ALONG WITH
STRONG, GUSTY WINDS AND LOW RH FOR PORTIONS OF THE AREA...
.A trough will move through on Wednesday bringing additional
gusty winds and dry humidities, especially over the East Side and
in NE California. Isolated to perhaps scattered dry thunderstorms
are possible Wednesday too along a line stretching from Siskiyou
County, including the Mill Fire northeastward into Oregon. These
thunderstorms will bring very little, if any rain. However, they
could produce gusty, shifting winds up to 45 mph.
...RED FLAG WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 2 PM TO 9 PM PDT
WEDNESDAY FOR DRY THUNDERSTORMS ON DRY FUELS ALONG WITH STRONG
GUSTY WIND AND LOW RH FOR FIRE WEATHER ZONES 284 AND 625...
* AFFECTED AREA...Most of fire weather zone 284 in California,
except far southeast portions, and most all of fire weather zone
625 in Oregon, except far southeastern portions.
* WIND...West to southwest winds 10 to 20 mph with gusts up to 35
mph Wednesday.
* HUMIDITY...8 to 15 percent Wednesday afternoon and evening,
lowest in eastern fire weather zone 625.
* THUNDERSTORMS: Isolated to potentially scattered
thunderstorms with little to no rain expected on Wednesday.
These thunderstorms may produce gusty, quickly shifting winds
near to 45 mph.
* DETAILED URL...View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr</description>
<instruction>Avoid tossing burning cigarettes on the ground, parking hot
vehicles on dry vegetation, and using equipment that can cause
sparks. Follow all fire restrictions. Find links to restrictions
at weather.gov/medford/wildfire. One less spark, one less
wildfire.
Gather your fire evacuation kit now. Collect essentials you don`t
want to lose and prioritize your checklist. Visit ready.gov/kit
for more information.
Familiarize yourself with your evacuation plan. Where will you
go? How will you get there? Who will you call to let others know
your are safe? Visit ready.gov/wildfires for more information.
A Red Flag Warning means that critical fire weather conditions
are either occurring now or will shortly. These conditions
promote rapid spread of fire which may become life threatening.
Evacuate if ordered to, or if a fire threatens.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>CAZ284-ORZ625</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMFR.FW.W.0028.220907T2100Z-220908T0400Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>South Central Oregon Desert including the BLM Land in Eastern Lake and Western Harney Counties</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ625</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>