<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 22 Dec 2022 07:29:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-ID12641EC40704.WindChillWarning.12641EC422C0ID.OTXWSWOTX.e6598d54c4433143b5c9e3bb0e11c3d3</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-22T12:29:00-07:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Central Panhandle Mountains (Idaho) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Wind Chill Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-22T12:29:00-07:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-22T13:00:00-07:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Spokane (Eastern Washington and Northern Idaho)</senderName>
<headline>Wind Chill Warning issued December 22 at 12:29PM MST until December 22 at 1:00PM MST by NWS Spokane</headline>
<description>...WIND CHILL WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL NOON PST TODAY...
...WIND CHILL ADVISORY IN EFFECT UNTIL 11 AM PST FRIDAY...
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM 4 AM FRIDAY TO 4
AM PST SATURDAY...
* WHAT...The Wind Chill Warning will go through noon and then be
replaced by a wind chill advisory. Wind chills as low as 5 to 15
below zero with wind speeds 5 to 10 mph. For the Winter Weather
Advisory, snow expected. Total snow accumulations between 3 and 5
inches.
* WHERE...Pinehurst, St. Maries, Fernwood, Mullan, Osburn, Kellogg,
Dobson Pass, Lookout Pass, Wallace, and Fourth Of July Pass.
* WHEN...For the Wind Chill Warning, until Noon PST today. For the
Wind Chill Advisory, until 11 AM PST Friday. For the Winter
Weather Advisory, from 4 AM Friday to 4 AM PST Saturday.
* IMPACTS...The dangerously cold wind chills could cause frostbite
on exposed skin in as little as 10 minutes. Plan on slippery road
conditions. The hazardous conditions could impact the Friday
morning and evening commutes.</description>
<instruction>Slow down and use caution while traveling. The latest road
conditions for the state you are calling from can be obtained by
calling 5 1 1.
Avoid outside activities if possible. When outside, make sure you
wear appropriate clothing, a hat, and gloves.
If you must go outside, dress in layers. Several layers of clothes
will keep you warmer than a single heavy coat. Cover exposed skin to
reduce your risk of frostbite or hypothermia. Gloves, a scarf, and a
hat will keep you from losing your body heat.
Wrap pipes with insulation and seal windows to avoid loss of heat
from your home. Keep a slow steady stream of water running from
indoor faucets, and open cabinet doors to allow warm air to
circulate around inside pipes.
Keep pets indoors as much as possible.
Make frequent checks on older family, friends, and neighbors. Ensure
portable heaters are used correctly. Do not use generators or grills
inside.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>IDZ004</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.EXB.KOTX.WC.Y.0004.221222T2000Z-221223T1900Z/
/O.CON.KOTX.WC.W.0001.000000T0000Z-221222T2000Z/
/O.CON.KOTX.WW.Y.0043.221223T1200Z-221224T1200Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Central Panhandle Mountains</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>016009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>016055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>016057</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>016079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>IDZ004</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>