<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 22 Dec 2022 04:01:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-PA12641EC386E4.WinterWeatherAdvisory.12641ED316E0PA.PBZWSWPBZ.14abd7aaf9146057d50071b0180e547a</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-12-22T11:01:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Fayette Ridges; Westmoreland Ridges (Pennsylvania) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Weather Advisory</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Minor</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-12-23T01:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2022-12-23T13:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Pittsburgh (Western Pennsylvania and East Central Ohio)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Weather Advisory issued December 22 at 11:01AM EST until December 23 at 1:00PM EST by NWS Pittsburgh</headline>
<description>...WINTER STORM TO BRING LIFE-THREATENING COLD....STRONG TO DAMAGING
WINDS...AND WINTER PRECIPITATION...
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL NOON EST TODAY...
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 1 AM TO 1 PM EST FRIDAY...
...WIND CHILL WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 6 AM FRIDAY TO NOON EST
SUNDAY...
* WHAT...For the first Winter Weather Advisory, mixed precipitation.
Additional snow accumulations up to one inch and ice accumulations
around a light glaze. For the second Winter Weather Advisory, snow
expected. Total snow accumulations up to one inch, with flash
freeze conditions possible. Winds gusting as high as 55 mph. For
the Wind Chill Warning, dangerously cold wind chills expected.
Wind chills as low as 35 below zero.
* WHERE...In Pennsylvania, higher elevations of Fayette and higher
elevations of Westmoreland counties. In West Virginia, eastern
Preston County.
* WHEN...For the first Winter Weather Advisory, until Noon EST
today. For the second Winter Weather Advisory, from 1 AM to 1 PM
EST Friday. For the Wind Chill Warning, from 6 AM Friday to Noon
EST Sunday.
* IMPACTS...Plan on slippery road conditions. The hazardous
conditions could impact the Thursday evening and Friday morning
commutes. Strong winds could cause extensive damage to trees and
power lines. The dangerously cold wind chills could cause
frostbite on exposed skin in as little as 10 minutes. Roads, and
especially bridges and overpasses, will likely become slick and
hazardous.</description>
<instruction>Avoid outside activities if possible. When outside, make sure you
wear appropriate clothing, a hat, and gloves.
Be prepared for slippery roads. Slow down and use caution while
driving. If you are going outside, watch your first few steps taken
on stairs, sidewalks, and driveways. These surfaces could be icy and
slippery, increasing your risk of a fall and injury.
Slow down and use caution while traveling. The latest road
conditions for the state you are calling from can be obtained by
calling 5 1 1.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PAZ074-076-WVZ512</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.UPG.KPBZ.WC.A.0001.221223T1100Z-221225T0000Z/
/O.NEW.KPBZ.WC.W.0001.221223T1100Z-221225T1700Z/
/O.NEW.KPBZ.WW.Y.0020.221223T0600Z-221223T1800Z/
/O.CON.KPBZ.WW.Y.0019.000000T0000Z-221222T1700Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Fayette Ridges; Westmoreland Ridges</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>042051</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>042129</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PAZ074</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>PAZ076</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>