<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 23 May 2023 05:21:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GU12664923E044.TyphoonWarning.1266492537A0GU.GUMHLSPQ1.6393018a2ff088722ab38820ded6c051</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-05-23T15:21:00+10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Guam (Guam) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Typhoon Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-05-23T15:21:00+10:00</effective>
<expires>2023-05-24T00:00:00+10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Guam (Guam)</senderName>
<headline>Typhoon Warning issued May 23 at 3:21PM ChST until further notice by NWS Guam</headline>
<description>...CAT 4 TYPHOON MAWAR INTENSIFYING AS IT APPROACHES GUAM...
.NEW INFORMATION...
Mawar now a category 4 typhoon.
.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and recommended
actions for people in Guam, Rota, Tinian and Saipan. Guam is likely
to see the brunt of the impacts from Mawar.
.Watches/Warnings...
A Typhoon Warning continues for Guam and Rota. Damaging winds of
39 mph are expected late this evening. Typhoon force winds of 74 mph
or greater expected by Wednesday morning.
A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Saipan and Tinian.
Damaging winds of 39 mph or greater expected by late tonight.
A Typhoon Watch continues for the Saipan and Tinian. Typhoon
force winds of 74 mph or greater are possible sometime on Wednesday.
A Flood Watch is in effect for Guam and all the Northern Marianas.
Please listen closely for any Flood Warnings that might be in effect
for your area.
.STORM INFORMATION...
At 1 PM ChST...the eye of Typhoon Mawar (02W) was located near
Latitude 11.5N...longitude 146.7E. This was about 190 miles southeast
of Guam. Storm motion was wobbling towards the north to northwest at
roughly 8 mph. Mawar`s intensity was 130 mph sustained winds.
.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
Mawar continues to intensify on approach to Guam. Passage very near
or directly over Guam as a Category 4 typhoon on Wednesday is looking
increasingly likely. The triple threat of cat 4 typhoon force winds,
torrential rains and life-threatening storm surge are all expected
for Guam. Large storm surge and coastal impacts are likely to occur,
particularly for coastal areas just north of the eye of Mawar on the
east to southeast sides of Guam.
.PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
This afternoon is the time to rush to completion preparations for the
protection of life and property. Stay calm and keep informed.
Comply with any evacuation orders that are issued for your area.
If your home is vulnerable to high winds, or you live in a surge
zone or any location prone to flooding, evacuate to a designated
shelter or ride out the storm in the sturdy, fully reinforced
concrete home of family or friends outside of evacuation zones.
For interests at ports...docks...and marinas...urgently complete
prescribed preparations according to your emergency operations
plan for tropical cyclones. If you live on a boat...make final
preparations for securing your craft before leaving it.
During the storm...stay inside and away from windows. Do not venture
outside when high winds are occurring or during temporary lulls as
flying debris can easily...and suddenly...cause serious injury. If
the eye passes over you, extreme winds will suddenly cease. This is
not the end of the typhoon--REMAIN IN SHELTER as extreme winds will
rapidly resume.
Have a well-charged cell phone nearby...keeping network communications
as open as possible for emergencies.
Once conditions have improved, remain in shelter until the all-clear
is announced from government officials.
Closely monitor NOAA weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for the latest forecasts.
&amp;&amp;
.NEXT UPDATE...
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tiyan around 9 PM...or sooner if conditions warrant.
...TYPHOON WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...New Information...
Mawar now a category 4 typhoon.
...PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
Stay calm and keep informed. Make the final preparations to protect
life and property. Rush to completion the hardening of your home or
business by closing shutters and bracing any garage doors.
Residents should remain in shelter within sturdy concrete homes with
concrete roofs. If you do not live in a concrete structure, or you
live in a surge zone or any location prone to flooding, evacuate to a
designated shelter or ride out Mawar in the sturdy home of family or
friends outside of evacuation zones. Do so this afternoon. Comply
with any evacuation orders that are issued.
Items to bring to a shelter include a first aid kit, medicines and
prescriptions, baby food and diapers, games and books, toiletries,
a battery powered radio, a cell phone, flashlights with extra
batteries, a blanket or sleeping bag for each person, personal
identification, copies of key papers such as insurance policies,
available cash and credit cards. Remember, pets are not allowed in
most public shelters, so check ahead with your intended shelter.
If staying in a home, turn the refrigerator to maximum cold and keep
it closed. Turn off propane tanks and unplug small appliances. Fill
the bathtub with water in case the tap water becomes unavailable after
the storm. This is for cleaning/flushing purposes. Do not drink it.
During the storm...stay inside and away from windows in a building
with concrete walls and a concrete roof. Residents must avoid power
lines as they will be tilted or broken. Stay away from the ocean due
to storm surge. Large ships should be secured as they will be torn
from moorings. Do not venture outside when high winds are occurring
or during temporary lulls as flying debris can easily...and
suddenly...cause serious injury. If the eye passes overhead, do not
go outside. Extreme winds will rapidly return.
Once conditions have improved on Thursday, remain in shelter until
the all-clear is given by government officials.
&amp;&amp;
...Probability of typhoon conditions...
Tropical storm conditions are expected to arrive tonight. Typhoon
conditions are expected to begin Wednesday morning into midday.
Intense eyewall winds may arrive around noontime.
...Winds...
Damaging winds (sustained winds &gt;40 mph) are expected to arrive this
evening, possibly late evening.
The latest forecast is for typhoon force winds (winds 74 mph or
greater) to move in Wednesday morning increasing through the morning
to around a peak of 145 mph. Gusts could reach to around 170 mph.
Exposed, higher terrain of the island is likely to experience higher
winds. Wind direction at any point on Guam is highly dependent on the
exact track of the eye. A direct passage over the island would lead
to major typhoon force winds from a mix of directions. A passage just
south of Guam would favor major typhoon force north to northeast
winds shifting east and then southeast to south. A passage just north
of Guam would favor major typhoon force winds from the northeast to
west, then southwest to west. Typhoon force winds will extend outward
from the center roughly 30 miles.
Mawar is likely to bring considerable damage to buildings and homes
of light material. Extensive damage to non-concrete roof. Non-
reinforced concrete walls could be blown down. Severe damage to
well-built wooden and metal structures possible. Some reinforced
hollow-spun concrete power poles and many reinforced wooden power
poles could be downed. Solar panels could be damaged. Large
projectiles and debris are possible. Most small and medium sized
steel frame signs could be bent over or damaged. Some fuel storage
tanks could rupture. Cars and high paneled vehicles could be
overturned. Major damage to shrubbery and trees is likely with
snapped or uprooted trees and blocked roads. Defoliation of
vegetation is likely, perhaps 50-70% defoliation.
Electricity and water may be unavailable for days and perhaps weeks
after the storm passes. Most trees will be snapped or uprooted.
Fallen trees may cut off residential areas for days to weeks.
...Storm surge and storm tide...
Storm surge of 6 to 10 feet above the normal high tide is expected
as Mawar moves overhead on Wednesday. Surge may reach to between 10
and 15 feet above normal high tide for the most vulnerable storm
surge prone areas. This 10 to 15 foot surge would most likely be
realized for coastal areas just north of Mawar`s center. Mawar`s
angle of approach could lead to considerable coastal impacts and
surge for Malesso, Inalahan, Ipan and Pago Bay, especially if the
center of Mawar scrapes by just south of Guam. Coastal roads of Guam
around Inalahan and Malesso may be impassable due to lofted beach
debris and boulders if this southern track is realized. Surge of 1
to 3 feet is possible within Apra Harbor. Surge may reach 4 feet
along western shores if Mawar passes over or north of Guam.
Severe coastal erosion is likely. Large boats could be torn from
moorings. Moderate to extensive damage is possible. A passage over
or just north of Guam would lead to greater impacts for western
coastlines.
Surf will build sharply this afternoon along south and east facing
reefs with dangerous surf of 20 to 25 feet late this afternoon into
Wednesday. Rough surf may develop along west facing reefs as early
as Wednesday night, with hazardous surf by late Thursday or Friday.
...Inland flooding...
A Flood Watch is in effect for Guam. See latest forecasts for latest
information. Listen for possible flood warnings for your location
and be ready to act if flooding rains occur.
Heavy rainfall is likely to develop tonight through the next few
days. Torrential rain is likely as Mawar passes near or overhead.
Rainfall amounts of 10 to 15 inches are possible with locally higher
amounts of around 20 inches. Landslides are a distinct possibility
for central to southern Guam along with overflowing streams and
rivers. A slowing of forward speed could lead to higher rainfall
totals. Monitor conditions for possible flood advisories or warnings.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUZ001</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.PGUM.TY.W.4002.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Guam</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>066010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUZ001</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>