<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:16:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D4D7CD0.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D5A5388FL.JAXHLSJAX.485b5bb83e82eeb825ae2822e6b9675a</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-29T17:16:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Baker; Bradford; Central Marion; Coastal Duval; Coastal Flagler; Coastal Nassau; Coastal St. Johns; Eastern Alachua; Eastern Clay; Eastern Marion; Eastern Putnam; Gilchrist; Hamilton; Inland Flagler; Inland Nassau; Inland St. Johns; Northern Columbia; South Central Duval; Southern Columbia; Suwannee; Trout River; Union; Western Alachua; Western Clay; Western Duval; Western Marion; Western Putnam (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-29T16:10:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-30T01:30:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Jacksonville (Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 29 at 5:16PM EDT  by NWS Jacksonville</headline>
<description>This product covers Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia
**SURGE CONTINUES ALONG THE NORTHEAST FLORIDA AND SOUTHEAST GEORGIA BEACHES AND ST JOHNS RIVER**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Warning has been cancelled for Brantley,
Inland Nassau, Northeastern Charlton, Wayne, Western Charlton,
Western Clay, Western Duval, and Western Putnam
- The Tropical Storm Watch has been cancelled for Baker,
Bradford, Eastern Alachua, and Union
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning, Tropical Storm Warning, and Hurricane
Watch are in effect for Coastal Camden, Coastal Duval, Coastal
Flagler, Coastal Glynn, Coastal Nassau, and Coastal St. Johns
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Eastern Clay, Eastern Putnam, Inland St. Johns, and South
Central Duval
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Inland Camden, Inland
Flagler, Inland Glynn, and Trout River
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 120 miles southeast of Jacksonville FL or about 160 miles
southeast of Brunswick GA
- 29.3N 79.9W
- Storm Intensity 75 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 10 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Ian has become a hurricane again over the western Atlantic, and was
moving towards the Carolinas. Ian is expected to intensify as it treks
through the Atlantic waters towards the Carolinas tonight and Friday
morning.
A storm surge warning is in effect along the coast as well as the St
Johns River with storm surge inundation up to 6 feet along the coast
and intracoastal waterway, and 2 to 4 feet for the St Johns River.
Trapped tides in the St. Johns river will exacerbate flooding for areas
along the St. Johns river.
Additional rainfall amounts up to 2 inches are possible this evening
before Hurricane Ian moves away from the area.
A hurricane watch is in effect along the coast of northeast FL and
southeast GA, with tropical storm warnings up for portions of
northeast FL and southeast GA. Over the tropical storm warning area,
tropical storm force winds are unfolding over northeast FL and southeast
Georgia. Gusts to hurricane strength will be possible along the coast.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are about to unfold
across coastal southeast Georgia, coastal northeast Florida,
intracoastal waterway, and the St. Johns River basin. Remain well
away from life- threatening surge having possible significant
impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across inland Glynn, Nassau, and Camden counties.
* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
coastal northeast Florida and southeast Georgia. Remain well guarded
against locally hazardous flood waters having additional limited
impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Localized rainfall flooding may prompt a few evacuations.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swifter currents.
Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may become swollen
and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter a few structures, especially in usually
vulnerable spots. A few places where rapid ponding of water
occurs at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Several storm drains and retention ponds become
near-full and begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge
closures.
Elsewhere across Northeast Florida and Southeast Georgia, little to
no impact is anticipated.
* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are unfolding across
portions of northeast Florida, north central FL, and southeast
Georgia. Remain well sheltered from dangerous wind having possible
significant impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Some damage to roofing and siding materials, along with damage
to porches, awnings, carports, and sheds. A few buildings
experiencing window, door, and garage door failures. Mobile
homes damaged, especially if unanchored. Unsecured lightweight
objects become dangerous projectiles.
- Several large trees snapped or uprooted, but with greater
numbers in places where trees are shallow rooted. Several
fences and roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. A few bridges, causeways, and access
routes impassable.
- Scattered power and communications outages, but more prevalent in
areas with above ground lines.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
If you are prone to flooding or in an area under a storm surge watch
or warning, be prepared for the possibility of a quick and dramatic
rise in water levels.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Jacksonville FL around 1130 PM EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ020-021-023-024-030-031-033-035-038-122-124-125-132-133-136>138-140-222-225-232-236-237-240-325-340-425-GAZ132>136-149-151>154-162-163-165-166-250-264-350-364</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Baker; Bradford; Central Marion; Coastal Duval; Coastal Flagler; Coastal Nassau; Coastal St. Johns; Eastern Alachua; Eastern Clay; Eastern Marion; Eastern Putnam; Gilchrist; Hamilton; Inland Flagler; Inland Nassau; Inland St. Johns; Northern Columbia; South Central Duval; Southern Columbia; Suwannee; Trout River; Union; Western Alachua; Western Clay; Western Duval; Western Marion; Western Putnam</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012001</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012003</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012007</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012019</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012083</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012089</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012109</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012121</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012125</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ020</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ021</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ023</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ024</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ030</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ033</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ038</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ122</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ124</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ125</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ132</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ136</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ137</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ138</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ140</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ222</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ225</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ232</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ236</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ237</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ240</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ325</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ340</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ425</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>