<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 29 Sep 2022 04:00:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D4ADE80.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D4C1700FL.MLBHLSMLB.2a72fe5429ded96993bea3bfb693c3ca</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-28T23:14:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-29T08:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 29 at 12:00AM EDT  by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>This product covers East Central Florida
**Significant Impacts From Hurricane Ian Will Continue Overnight**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Hurricane Warning is in effect for Coastal Volusia, Inland
Northern Brevard, Inland Southern Brevard, Inland Volusia,
Mainland Northern Brevard, Mainland Southern Brevard, Northern
Brevard Barrier Islands, Northern Lake, Okeechobee, Orange,
Osceola, Seminole, Southern Brevard Barrier Islands, and
Southern Lake
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Coastal Indian River,
Coastal Martin, Coastal Saint Lucie, Inland Indian River,
Inland Martin, and Inland Saint Lucie
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 70 miles south of Orlando FL or about 80 miles southwest
of Cape Canaveral FL
- 27.5N 81.4W
- Storm Intensity 90 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 8 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
At 1100 PM, Hurricane Ian was centered about 45 miles northwest of
the city of Okeechobee, or about 65 miles southwest of Melbourne. Ian
continues to weaken with it`s maximum sustained winds having decreased
to 90 mph, making it a Category 1 hurricane on the Saffir-Simpson
Hurricane Wind Scale. Ian is moving north-northeast at about 8 mph.
Ian will continue to weaken as its center tracks northeast into
Osceola and northern Brevard Counties through sunrise, then offshore
into the Atlantic a little north of Cape Canaveral by mid day. In
spite of the forecast weakening, the most significant wind and rain
impacts from Ian are expected overnight!!
A Tropical Storm Warning remains in effect for Indian River, St.
Lucie, and Martin counties and adjacent Atlantic waters. A Hurricane
Warning continues for Lake, Seminole, Orange, Osceola, Okeechobee,
Brevard, and Volusia counties, as well as the adjacent Atlantic
waters.
Widespread sustained winds of Tropical Storm Force will continue, with
gusts near or above hurricane Force becoming numerous, especially
along and near the track of Ian`s center, and in squalls, which are
more numerous to the north and east of the center.
A Flood Watch continues for all of east central Florida through late
Thursday night. Significant to catastrophic flooding impacts are
expected to continue overnight and last through Thursday.
Widespread heavy rainfall expected to continue overnight into Thursday
from Osceola and Brevard Counties northward, along and north of the
track of Ian`s center. Additional rainfall amounts of 8 to 15 inches
are expected across this area, dropping back to 2 to 4 inches across
Okeechobee and Brevard Counties, with the lowest amounts, less than
2 inches of additional rainfall, now expected across the Treasure
Coast.
The higher rainfall amounts across the central and north will cause
major flooding, especially for locations that have already received
high rainfall amounts over the past 7 days. Creeks and rivers that are
already approaching bankfull will overflow, leading to substantial
flooding. Urban locations and low-lying areas are especially
vulnerable with inundation of major roadways and flooding of
structures expected.
A Tornado Watch is in effect for all east central Florida counties
except for Lake County through 1 AM. The potential for tornadoes will
continue into early Thursday, especially from northern Osceola to the
Volusia and Brevard coast.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Potential impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across
east central Florida from Osceola and Brevard Counties northward.
. Remain well guarded against life-threatening flood waters having
additional devastating impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Extreme rainfall flooding may prompt numerous evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may overwhelmingly overflow their banks
in many places with deep moving water. Small streams, creeks,
canals, and ditches may become raging rivers. In mountain
areas, deadly runoff may rage down valleys while increasing
susceptibility to rockslides and mudslides. Flood control
systems and barriers may become stressed.
- Flood waters can enter numerous structures within multiple
communities, some structures becoming uninhabitable or washed
away. Numerous places where flood waters may cover escape
routes. Streets and parking lots become rivers of raging water
with underpasses submerged. Driving conditions become very
dangerous. Numerous road and bridge closures with some weakened
or washed out.
* WIND:
Potential impacts from the main wind event are now unfolding across
east central Florida. Remain well sheltered from life-threatening wind
having additional extensive impacts. If realized, these impacts include:
- Considerable roof damage to sturdy buildings, with some having
window, door, and garage door failures leading to structural
damage. Mobile homes severely damaged, with some destroyed.
Damage accentuated by airborne projectiles. Locations may be
uninhabitable for weeks.
- Many large trees snapped or uprooted along with fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- Some roads impassable from large debris, and more within urban
or heavily wooded places. Several bridges, causeways, and
access routes impassable.
- Large areas with power and communications outages.
* TORNADOES:
Potential impacts from tornadoes are still unfolding across east
central Florida, mainly Volusia and Brevard Counties. Remain well
braced against a tornado event having possible limited impacts. If
realized, these impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
* SURGE:
Potential impacts from the main surge event are now unfolding across
coastal sections of east central Florida. Remain well away from locally
hazardous surge having possible limited impacts. If realized, these
impacts include:
- Localized inundation with storm surge flooding mainly along
immediate shorelines and in low-lying spots, or in areas farther
inland near where higher surge waters move ashore.
- Moderate beach erosion, mainly in usually vulnerable locations.
Numerous strong rip currents.
- Minor damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers. A few
small craft broken away from moorings.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to stay inside and away from windows. Listen for
updates and be ready in case you lose electrical power. Keep a battery-
powered radio, charged cell phone and flashlight handy.
During the peak of the storm be ready to move quickly. Keep your
shoes on and rain gear handy. Boots and athletic shoes offer the best
foot protection if you become unexpectedly exposed to the weather.
Keep your cell phone charged and in power-saving mode. If you lose
power, use it sparingly and mainly for personal emergencies and
check-ins.
It is important to remain calm, informed, and focused during an
emergency. Be patient and helpful with those you encounter.
If you are a visitor, be sure to know the name of the city or town in
which you are staying and the name of the county or parish in which
it resides. Listen for these locations in local news updates. Pay
attention for instructions from local authorities.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
If a Tornado Warning is issued for your area, be ready to shelter
quickly, preferably away from windows and in an interior room not
prone to flooding. If driving, scan the roadside for quick shelter
options.
If in a place that is vulnerable to high wind, such as near large
trees, a manufactured home, upper floors of a high-rise building, or
on a boat, consider moving to a safer shelter before the onset of
strong winds or flooding.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather radio or local news outlets
for official storm information. Be ready to adapt to possible changes
to the forecast. Ensure you have multiple ways to receive weather
warnings.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 6 AM EDT, or sooner if conditions
warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041-044>046-053-058-141-144-154-159-164-247-254-259-264-347-447-547-647-747</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ058</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ144</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ159</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ164</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ247</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ254</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ259</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ347</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ447</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ547</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ647</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ747</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>