<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 30 Sep 2022 12:44:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-FL12640D5995B0.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D5A47D0FL.MLBHLSMLB.2a72fe5429ded96993bea3bfb693c3ca</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-29T20:44:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County (Florida) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-29T20:08:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-30T01:00:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Melbourne (East Central Florida)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 29 at 8:44PM EDT  by NWS Melbourne</headline>
<description>This product covers East Central Florida
**Even as Wind and Rain Decreases, Lingering Impacts From Hurricane Ian
Will Continue Overnight**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- The Tropical Storm Warning has been cancelled for Coastal
Indian River, Inland Indian River, Northern Lake, Orange,
Osceola, Seminole, and Southern Lake
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Coastal Volusia,
Inland Northern Brevard, Inland Southern Brevard, Inland
Volusia, Mainland Northern Brevard, Mainland Southern Brevard,
Northern Brevard Barrier Islands, and Southern Brevard Barrier
Islands
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 100 miles east-northeast of Daytona Beach FL
- 29.7N 79.4W
- Storm Intensity 75 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 10 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
As of 8 PM, Hurricane Ian was centered about 100 miles east-northeast
of Daytona Beach and continuing to move north-northeast farther away
from the east central Florida coast. Ian`s maximum sustained winds
remain 75 mph. Ian will remain a hurricane as it tracks north toward
the Carolinas.
The Tropical Storm Warning for Lake, Seminole, Orange, Osceola and
Indian River Counties has been canceled. A Tropical Storm Warning
remains in effect for Volusia and Brevard Counties, and for the
Atlantic waters from Sebastian Inlet from Jupiter Inlet. A Hurricane
Warning continues for the open Atlantic waters offshore Volusia and
Brevard Counties for frequent hurricane force gusts.
Lingering threats from Ian will continue overnight! Strong wind gusts
on the western periphery of Ian could still knock over additional
trees or power lines, especially in areas where the ground is
saturated or inundated from flooding and standing water.
Widespread flooding continues across many areas, and water will be very
slow to subside over the next several days, and possibly longer in the
Johns River Basin, and other large rivers lakes, and water retention
areas.
Do not attempt to travel through flooded areas!! It is very difficult,
if not impossible, to recognize the dangers of flooding at night!!
If you cannot see the road beneath you, it could be washed out!!
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Impacts from the flooding rain are still unfolding across many areas
of east central Florida. Remain well guarded against locally hazardous
flood waters having additional impacts. These include:
- Localized flooding may prompt continues evacuations.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly rise with swifter currents.
Small streams, creeks, canals, and ditches may become swollen
and overflow in spots.
- Flood waters can enter structures, especially in usually
vulnerable spots. A few places where rapid ponding of water
occurs at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage areas.
Several storm drains and retention ponds become near-full and
begin to overflow. Some brief road and bridge closures.
* WIND:
Impacts from the main wind event are still unfolding, especially
across Volusia and Brevard Counties. Remain well sheltered from
hazardous wind having additional impacts. These impacts include:
- Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted and the ground is saturated. Some fences and
roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* SURGE:
Rough surf will continue with additional beach erosion and coastal
flooding possible around the time of tonight`s high tide between 11 PM
and midnight.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Do not enter evacuated areas until officials have given the all clear
to return.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with orders that
are issued. Do not needlessly jeopardize your life or the lives of
others.
Do not be a thrill seeker or risk your life for senseless photos or
videos. Do not venture out near flooded roads or approach downed power
lines. Trees will fall over more easily where root systems have been
weakened due to widespread heavy rain.
Closely monitor weather.gov, NOAA Weather Radio and local news
outlets for official storm information. Listen for possible changes
to the forecast.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Melbourne FL around 12 Midnight EDT, or sooner if
conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041-044>046-053-058-141-144-154-159-164-247-254-259-264-347-447-547-647-747</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Indian River; Coastal Martin; Coastal St. Lucie; Coastal Volusia; Inland Indian River; Inland Martin; Inland Northern Brevard; Inland Southern Brevard; Inland St. Lucie; Inland Volusia; Mainland Northern Brevard; Mainland Southern Brevard; Northern Brevard Barrier Islands; Northern Lake County; Okeechobee; Orange; Osceola; Seminole; Southern Brevard Barrier Islands; Southern Lake County</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012009</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012069</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012085</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012093</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012097</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012111</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>012127</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ041</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ053</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ058</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ141</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ144</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ154</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ159</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ164</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ247</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ254</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ259</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ264</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ347</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ447</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ547</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ647</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>FLZ747</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>