<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:41:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-NC12640D4D8694.HurricaneLocalStatement.12640D5A5964NC.MHXHLSMHX.29ef2c68c549b66a8db5b54dbfcd764b</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-29T17:41:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Beaufort; Coastal Onslow; Duplin; East Carteret; Greene; Hatteras Island; Inland Onslow; Jones; Lenoir; Mainland Dare; Mainland Hyde; Martin; Northern Craven; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Pamlico; Pitt; Southern Craven; Tyrrell; Washington; West Carteret (North Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Local Statement</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HLS</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-29T17:03:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-30T01:45:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Newport/Morehead City (Eastern North Carolina)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Local Statement issued September 29 at 5:41PM EDT  by NWS Newport/Morehead City</headline>
<description>This product covers Eastern North Carolina
**HURRICANE IAN TO BRING IMPACTS TO EASTERN NC INTO THE WEEKEND**
NEW INFORMATION
---------------
* CHANGES TO WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- None
* CURRENT WATCHES AND WARNINGS:
- A Storm Surge Warning and Tropical Storm Warning are in effect
for Pamlico and Southern Craven
- A Tropical Storm Warning and Storm Surge Watch are in effect
for Beaufort, Coastal Onslow, East Carteret, Hatteras Island,
Inland Onslow, Mainland Hyde, Northern Outer Banks, Ocracoke
Island, and West Carteret
- A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for Duplin, Greene,
Jones, Lenoir, Mainland Dare, Martin, Northern Craven, Pitt,
Tyrrell, and Washington
* STORM INFORMATION:
- About 400 miles south-southwest of Jacksonville NC
- 29.3N 79.9W
- Storm Intensity 75 mph
- Movement North-northeast or 30 degrees at 10 mph
SITUATION OVERVIEW
------------------
Hurricane Ian will move north of the Southeast through tonight moving
over the Carolinas Friday into Saturday. Regardless of the exact track
of Ian, there is the potential for extensive impacts to eastern North
Carolina.
Heavy rain bands will bring widespread rainfall amounts of 3 to 4
inches, with locally higher amounts, bringing the threat of localized
flooding, especially in low-lying, urban, and poor drainage areas.
Life-threatening storm surge inundation of 2 to 4 feet above ground is
possible along much of the coast, with greatest confidence in inundation
values approaching 4 feet along the lower Neuse River. Winds approaching
tropical storm force could lead to some downed trees and isolated power
outages. Tornadoes may result in areas of locally enhanced damage.
Dangerous marine conditions are expected for all offshore waters and
the Pamlico Sound, with strong winds and seas building to create
treacherous conditions for mariners. Stronger and more frequent rip
currents will also exist along area beaches.
POTENTIAL IMPACTS
-----------------
* FLOODING RAIN:
Protect against dangerous rainfall flooding having possible
significant impacts across Eastern North Carolina. Potential impacts
include:
- Moderate rainfall flooding may prompt several evacuations and
rescues.
- Rivers and tributaries may quickly become swollen with swifter
currents and overspill their banks in a few places, especially
in usually vulnerable spots. Small streams, creeks, canals, and
ditches overflow.
- Flood waters can enter some structures or weaken foundations.
Several places may experience expanded areas of rapid
inundation at underpasses, low-lying spots, and poor drainage
areas. Some streets and parking lots take on moving water as
storm drains and retention ponds overflow. Driving conditions
become hazardous. Some road and bridge closures.
* SURGE:
Protect against life-threatening surge having possible significant
impacts across eastern NC coastal areas near the barrier islands,
southern Pamlico Sound, and Neuse and Pamlico Rivers. Potential impacts
in this area include:
- Areas of inundation with storm surge flooding accentuated by
waves. Damage to several buildings, mainly near the coast.
- Sections of near-shore escape routes and secondary roads become
weakened or washed out, especially in usually vulnerable low
spots.
- Major beach erosion with heavy surf breaching dunes. Strong and
numerous rip currents.
- Moderate damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers.
Several small craft broken away from moorings, especially in
unprotected anchorages.
Also, protect against locally hazardous surge having possible limited
impacts across areas along the Albemarle Sound.
Elsewhere across Eastern North Carolina, little to no impact is
anticipated.
* WIND:
Protect against hazardous wind having possible limited impacts across
Eastern North Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- Damage to porches, awnings, carports, sheds, and unanchored
mobile homes. Unsecured lightweight objects blown about.
- Many large tree limbs broken off. A few trees snapped or
uprooted, but with greater numbers in places where trees are
shallow rooted. Some fences and roadway signs blown over.
- A few roads impassable from debris, particularly within urban
or heavily wooded places. Hazardous driving conditions on
bridges and other elevated roadways.
- Scattered power and communications outages.
* TORNADOES:
Protect against a tornado event having possible limited impacts
across Eastern North Carolina. Potential impacts include:
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the execution
of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with power
and communications disruptions.
- Locations could realize roofs peeled off buildings, chimneys
toppled, mobile homes pushed off foundations or overturned,
large tree tops and branches snapped off, shallow-rooted trees
knocked over, moving vehicles blown off roads, and small boats
pulled from moorings.
* OTHER COASTAL HAZARDS:
Dangerous marine conditions are expected for all offshore waters and
the Pamlico Sound, with strong winds and seas building to create
treacherous conditions for mariners. The threat for stronger and
more frequent rip currents will also exist along area beaches.
PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS
----------------------------------
* EVACUATIONS:
Listen to local official for recommended preparedness actions, including
possible evacuation. If ordered to evacuate, do so immediately.
* OTHER PREPAREDNESS INFORMATION:
Now is the time to complete all preparations to protect life and
property in accordance with your emergency plan. Ensure you are in a
safe location before the onset of strong winds or possible flooding.
Failure to adequately shelter may result in serious injury or loss of
life. Always heed the advice of local officials and comply with any
orders that are issued. Remember, during the storm 9 1 1 Emergency
Services may not be able to immediately respond if conditions are
unsafe. This should be a big factor in your decision making.
Rapidly rising flood waters are deadly. If you are in a flood-prone
area, consider moving to higher ground. Never drive through a flooded
roadway. Remember, turn around don`t drown!
If a Tornado Warning is issued for your area, be ready to shelter
quickly, preferably away from windows and in an interior room not
prone to flooding. If driving, scan the roadside for quick shelter
options.
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
* ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF INFORMATION:
- For information on appropriate preparations see ready.gov
- For information on creating an emergency plan see getagameplan.org
- For additional disaster preparedness information see redcross.org
NEXT UPDATE
-----------
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Newport/Morehead City NC around 11 PM this evening, or
sooner if conditions warrant.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ029-044>047-079>081-090>092-094-193>196-198-199-203>205</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Beaufort; Coastal Onslow; Duplin; East Carteret; Greene; Hatteras Island; Inland Onslow; Jones; Lenoir; Mainland Dare; Mainland Hyde; Martin; Northern Craven; Northern Outer Banks; Ocracoke Island; Pamlico; Pitt; Southern Craven; Tyrrell; Washington; West Carteret</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037013</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037031</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037049</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037055</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037061</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037095</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037103</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037107</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037117</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037133</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037137</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037147</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037177</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>037187</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ029</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ044</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ045</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ046</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ047</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ079</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ080</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ081</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ090</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ091</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ092</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ094</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ193</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ194</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ195</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ196</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ198</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ199</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ203</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ204</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>NCZ205</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>