<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 29 Sep 2022 09:07:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-SC12640D4D794C.HurricaneWarning.12640D5A4DACSC.ILMTCVILM.5326ad0ce7febc271de37e5c516af426</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-09-29T17:07:00-04:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Coastal Georgetown (South Carolina) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hurricane Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>HUW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-09-29T17:07:00-04:00</effective>
<expires>2022-09-30T01:15:00-04:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Wilmington (Northeastern South Carolina and Southeastern North Carolina - Wilmington)</senderName>
<headline>Hurricane Warning issued September 29 at 5:07PM EDT until further notice by NWS Wilmington</headline>
<description>...HURRICANE WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...STORM SURGE WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
* LOCATIONS AFFECTED
- Georgetown
- Murrells Inlet
* WIND
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Equivalent Cat 1 Hurricane force wind
- Peak Wind Forecast: 55-75 mph with gusts to 100 mph
- Window for Tropical Storm force winds: until early Saturday
morning
- Window for Hurricane force winds: Friday morning until
Friday afternoon
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for wind 74
to 110 mph
- The wind threat has increased from the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for life-threatening wind of equivalent CAT 1 or
2 hurricane force.
- PREPARE: Last minute efforts should solely focus on
protecting life. The area remains subject to considerable
wind damage.
- ACT: Now is the time to shelter from life-threatening wind.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Unfolding
- Potential impacts from the main wind event are unfolding.
* STORM SURGE
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Life-threatening storm surge possible
- Peak Storm Surge Inundation: The potential for 4-7 feet
above ground somewhere within surge prone areas
- Window of concern: through Saturday afternoon
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for storm
surge flooding greater than 6 feet above ground
- The storm surge threat has increased from the previous
assessment.
- PLAN: Plan for life-threatening storm surge flooding of
greater than 6 feet above ground.
- PREPARE: Evacuation efforts should soon be brought to
completion before driving conditions become unsafe.
- ACT: Leave immediately if evacuation orders are given for
your area to avoid being cut off from emergency services or
needlessly risk lives.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Extensive
- Large areas of deep inundation with storm surge flooding
enhanced by battering waves. Structural damage to buildings
is likely, with several potentially washing away. Damage
will be compounded by floating debris. Some locations may
become uninhabitable for an extended period.
- Inundation is likely to impact vulnerable homes along tidal
creeks and waterways farther inland.
- Drinking water and sewer services will likely become
impacted by the storm surge. Surge waters will contain
hazardous materials.
- Large sections of coastal roads will become flooded, or
wash-out altogether.
- Severe beach erosion is expected with significant dune
loss. Sands from displaced dunes will likely deposit onto
the barrier island roads.
- Major damage to marinas, docks, boardwalks, and piers is
possible. Many small craft broken away from moorings,
especially in unprotected anchorages with some lifted
onshore and stranded inland.
- Navigation may be difficult, especially near inlets and
waterways, as some navigational aids may be off station or
missing. Debris is possible in the waterways and other
navigable channels.
* FLOODING RAIN
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST: Flood Watch is in effect
- Peak Rainfall Amounts: Additional 4-8 inches, with locally
higher amounts
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for major
flooding rain
- The flooding rain threat has remained nearly steady from
the previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should include the potential for
major flooding from heavy rain. Evacuations and rescues are
likely.
- PREPARE: Strongly consider protective actions, especially
if you are in an area vulnerable to flooding.
- ACT: Heed any flood watches and warnings. Failure to take
action will likely result in serious injury or loss of life.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Extensive
- Major flooding from rainfall may prompt evacuations and
numerous rescues.
- Rivers and streams may rapidly overflow their banks in
multiple places. Creeks and ditches will flood and may
contain strong currents.
- Flood waters may enter many structures, and some may become
uninhabitable. Some road scours or complete road failures
will be possible, along with the potential for sinkholes.
Many streets and parking lots may flood, and may be
impacted by flowing water. Many road and low-lying bridge
closures are possible with some weakened or washed away.
Driving conditions will be dangerous.The delivery of
drinking water and sewer services may be interrupted. Flood
waters may be polluted and contain hazardous materials.
* TORNADO
- LATEST LOCAL FORECAST:
- Situation is somewhat favorable for tornadoes
- THREAT TO LIFE AND PROPERTY THAT INCLUDES TYPICAL FORECAST
UNCERTAINTY IN TRACK, SIZE AND INTENSITY: Potential for a few
tornadoes
- The tornado threat has remained nearly steady from the
previous assessment.
- PLAN: Emergency plans should continue to include possible
tornadoes.
- PREPARE: Stay within your shelter keeping informed of the
latest tornado situation.
- ACT: Move quickly to the safest place within your shelter
if a tornado warning is issued.
- POTENTIAL IMPACTS: Limited
- The occurrence of isolated tornadoes can hinder the
execution of emergency plans during tropical events.
- A few places may experience tornado damage, along with
power and communications disruptions.
- Tornadoes can cause damage to trees, vehicles, boats, and
buildings. Unsecured mobile homes and poorly constructed
structures are particularly vulnerable.
* FOR MORE INFORMATION:
- http://www.weather.gov/ilm/Tropics
- http://ready.gov/hurricanes</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ056</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KILM.HU.W.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/
/O.CON.KILM.SS.W.1009.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Coastal Georgetown</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>045043</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>SCZ056</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>