<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 06 Jun 2023 04:29:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MT12664E180BD4.FloodWatch.12664E279C98MT.BYZFFABYZ.c2b3236e19a59bc7acdbb2bf73d233c9</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-06-06T10:29:00-06:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Golden Valley (Montana) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Flood Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>FLA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-06-06T10:29:00-06:00</effective>
<expires>2023-06-07T12:30:00-06:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Billings (Southeastern Montana)</senderName>
<headline>Flood Watch issued June 06 at 10:29AM MDT until further notice by NWS Billings</headline>
<description>...The Flood Watch continues for the following rivers in Montana...
Musselshell River near Lavina affecting Golden Valley County.
Musselshell River near Shawmut affecting Wheatland County.
.The Musselshell river continues to flow near bankfull from Shawmut
through Lavina, and the forecast keeps the river just below flood
stage for the next several days. However, additional heavy rainfall
is possible in this area, and any additional precipitation may push
the river above minor flood stage at times over the next several
days. In addition to the potential for minor flooding, significant
bank erosion is likely with flows of this magnitude which may cause
additional damage to infrastructure along the river.
...FLOOD WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE...
* WHAT...Flooding is possible.
* WHERE...Musselshell River near Lavina.
* WHEN...Until further notice.
* IMPACTS...Flooding of low lying areas along the river is possible.
Significant erosion is likely at flows of this magnitude and may
result in damage of infrastructure along the river as well as land
loss.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 9:30 AM MDT Tuesday the stage was 9.0 feet.
- The river is nearly steady just below flood stage. The river
will fluctuate near flood stage through the next few days
with the potential to go above flood stage at times based on
upstream precipitation.
- Forecast...Flood stage may be reached based on the latest
forecast information.
- Flood stage is 9.5 feet.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
&amp;&amp;
Fld   Observed           Forecasts (12 pm)
Location      Stg   Stg   Day/Time     Wed   Thu   Fri
Musselshell River
Lavina        9.5   9.0   Tue 9 am     9.2   8.7   8.5
&amp;&amp;</description>
<instruction>Residents and those with interests near the river should monitor
rising water levels and be prepared for possible flood warnings. Now
is the time to prepare for action in the event flooding occurs.
Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.
Stay away or be swept away. River banks and culverts can become
unstable and unsafe.
Do not enter or cross flowing water or water of unknown depth.
Please report observed flooding to local emergency officials and
request they pass the information to the National Weather Service.
Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.
The latest stages and forecasts for rivers and streams can be found
at our web page: https://water.weather.gov.
The next statement will be issued Wednesday afternoon by 1230 PM
MDT.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MTC037</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KBYZ.FL.A.0003.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/
/LVNM8.0.RS.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.000000T0000Z.NO/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Golden Valley</areaDesc>
<polygon>46.33,-109.4 46.3,-108.8 46.26,-108.8 46.28,-109.4 46.33,-109.4</polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>030037</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MTC037</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>