<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:23:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MN12663DB1BBDC.WinterStormWarning.126641DF5700MN.MPXWSWMPX.d41f6bcc48fbfa6303f86f51af0d2a79</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-03-30T21:23:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Chisago (Minnesota) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-03-31T19:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2023-04-01T07:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Minneapolis (Southern Minnesota)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Warning issued March 30 at 9:23PM CDT until April 01 at 7:00AM CDT by NWS Minneapolis</headline>
<description>...AREAS OF FREEZING RAIN TONIGHT WITH WIDESPREAD WINTRY
PRECIPITATION FRIDAY AFTERNOON AND NIGHT WITH SNOW RATES OF 1 TO 2
INCHES PER HOUR POSSIBLE...
.A complex storm system developing over the Rockies will shift
east into the Central Plains tonight then gradually move into the
Great Lakes Friday night. Precipitation will continue developing
overnight as rain or freezing rain, depending on surface
temperatures. A light icing to a tenth of an inch of ice
accretion is likely mainly north of a line from Redwood Falls to
Buffalo MN to Rice Lake WI. The precipitation will then gradually
change over to snow Friday afternoon and evening, which could be
heavy at times. Snowfall amounts should range from 5 to 8 inches
across east central Minnesota and western Wisconsin, with locally
higher totals possible. 3 to 5 inches are expected across the rest
of central and western Minnesota. In addition, strong winds will
develop Friday afternoon which will persist through Friday night,
potentially producing blizzard conditions over much of western
Minnesota and possibly into parts of eastern Minnesota.
A Winter Weather Advisory is in place for much of western and
central Minnesota into northwest Wisconsin for freezing rain
tonight into early Friday. A Winter Storm Warning is now in effect
in areas north Interstate 90 for the combination of heavy snow
and blowing snow late Friday and Friday night. Blizzard conditions
remain possible and the Winter Storm Warning may be upgraded to a
Blizzard Warning in some areas when confidence continues to
increase with snow amounts.
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 10 AM CDT
FRIDAY...
...WINTER STORM WARNING IN EFFECT FROM 7 PM FRIDAY TO 7 AM CDT
SATURDAY...
* WHAT...For the Winter Storm Warning, heavy snow and blowing
snow expected. Total snow accumulations of 3 to 5 inches and ice
accumulations of a light glaze. Winds gusting as high as 45
mph. For the Winter Weather Advisory, mixed precipitation.
Additional snow accumulations of up to one inch and ice
accumulations of a light glaze.
* WHERE...Chisago County.
* WHEN...For the Winter Storm Warning, from 7 PM Friday to 7 AM
CDT Saturday. For the Winter Weather Advisory, until 10 AM CDT
Friday.
* IMPACTS...Plan on slippery road conditions. Widespread blowing
snow could significantly reduce visibility. The hazardous
conditions could impact the morning or evening commute.</description>
<instruction>If you must travel, keep an extra flashlight, food, and water in
your vehicle in case of an emergency.
Slow down and use caution while traveling.
The latest road conditions for the state you are calling from can
be obtained by calling 5 1 1. Road conditions can also be found
at 511mn.org for Minnesota or 511wi.gov for Wisconsin.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ053</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.UPG.KMPX.WS.A.0009.230401T0000Z-230401T1200Z/
/O.NEW.KMPX.WS.W.0008.230401T0000Z-230401T1200Z/
/O.CON.KMPX.WW.Y.0017.000000T0000Z-230331T1500Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Chisago</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>027025</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MNZ053</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>