<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Thu, 30 Mar 2023 04:26:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-WI12663DA49DA8.WinterStormWatch.126641E04160WI.ARXWSWARX.ba1ca8e4011f1a935e7a35f2f322fa66</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-03-30T11:26:00-05:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Taylor (Wisconsin) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Watch</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSA</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-03-31T22:00:00-05:00</effective>
<expires>2023-04-01T13:00:00-05:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS LaCrosse (Southwestern Wisconsin, Southeastern Minnesota, and Northeast Iowa)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Watch issued March 30 at 11:26AM CDT until April 01 at 1:00PM CDT by NWS LaCrosse</headline>
<description>...Strong Spring Storm to Bring Heavy Snow to the Region...
.A complex storm system will begin to affect the area this
afternoon, finally ending Saturday and bringing a variety of
weather with it including heavy rain, severe storms, and heavy
snow. A wintry mix with some freezing rain and icing is looking
more likely for the Highway 29 corridor and north tonight. Ice
accumulations of around one-quarter inch could occur by morning. A
Winter Weather Advisory has been issued for Taylor county.
Most of the wintry mix should change to rain Friday. Rain changes
to snow Friday night, with heavy, wet snow. At this time, the
heaviest snow looks to fall north of Highway 10 in northcentral
Wisconsin with 6 to 10 inches of accumulation. Farther south,
amounts are less confident due to potential differences in when
the rain switches over to snow and how far south the heavy snow
will make it. In addition northwest winds will increase on the
backside of the storm with gusts 35 to 45 mph with reduced
visibilities and some blowing and drifting of snow. The winds will
remain elevated Saturday morning.
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM 10 PM THIS EVENING TO
10 AM CDT FRIDAY...
...WINTER STORM WATCH REMAINS IN EFFECT FROM FRIDAY EVENING
THROUGH SATURDAY AFTERNOON...
* WHAT...For the Winter Weather Advisory tonight, mixed
precipitation expected. Total snow accumulations of up to one
inch and ice accumulations of around one quarter of an inch. For
the Winter Storm Watch, heavy snow possible. Total snow
accumulations of 5 to 10 inches possible. Winds could gust as
high as 45 mph.
* WHERE...Taylor County.
* WHEN...For the Winter Weather Advisory, from 10 PM this
evening to 10 AM CDT Friday. For the Winter Storm Watch, from
Friday evening through Saturday afternoon.
* IMPACTS...Some power outages and tree damage are possible due to
the ice. Travel could be challenging. Widespread blowing snow
could significantly reduce visibility. Gusty winds could bring
down tree branches.</description>
<instruction>Slow down and use caution while traveling.
Monitor the latest forecasts for updates on this situation.
Visit 511wi.gov for road conditions.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ017</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.NEW.KARX.WW.Y.0015.230331T0300Z-230331T1500Z/
/O.CON.KARX.WS.A.0007.230401T0300Z-230401T1800Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Taylor</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>055119</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>WIZ017</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>