<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sat, 08 Oct 2022 10:30:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GU126412014658.HydrologicOutlook.126412027ED8GU.GUMESFGUM.05a8c2f769ba2a12e0b9db4515b669c1</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-10-08T20:30:00+10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for GUC100; GUC110; GUC120; Guam (Guam) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Hydrologic Outlook</event>
<urgency>Future</urgency>
<severity>Unknown</severity>
<certainty>Possible</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-10-08T20:30:00+10:00</effective>
<expires>2022-10-09T04:30:00+10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Guam (Guam)</senderName>
<headline>Hydrologic Outlook issued October 08 at 8:30PM ChST  by NWS Guam</headline>
<description>...HEAVY RAINFALL POSSIBLE NEXT WEEK...
This Hydrologic Outlook is for Guam, Rota, Tinian and Saipan in the
Mariana Islands.
A developing monsoon trough and moderate surge combined with a
possible tropical disturbance is expected to bring heavy rain to the
Marianas from Tuesday to Friday next week. A monsoon trough is
currently in place across the Marianas, with easterly winds over
Tinian and Saipan and south to west winds for Guam and Rota. The
monsoon trough looks to remain fairly stationary over the next
several days, then drift northward as weak circulations develop and
move west-northwestward, dragging the trough with them. Early to
midweek next week, a modest surge is expected over the region,
resulting in increasing convection. This surge and associated
increased moisture looks to maintain moderate to heavy showers
across the Marianas through the remainder of the week.
Latest model guidance varies on expected rainfall amounts, with the
ECMWF being the most consistent. Amounts range from 6 to 12 inches
for the ECMWF to 3 to 4 inches for the GFS. Regardless, the
developing situation looks very favorable for locally heavy rainfall
capable of producing flash flooding across the Marianas.
Residents need to closely monitor this developing situation as
watches, advisories and warnings could be issued as early as Tuesday.
If living near streams and rivers, prepare to move items away from
stream and river banks. Make sure storm drains nearby are not
clogged, especially if living in low-lying areas.
This outlook will be updated over the next few days with additional
information, or cancelled if the situation changes.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUC010-100-110-120</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>GUC100; GUC110; GUC120; Guam</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>066010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUC010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUC100</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUC110</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUC120</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>