<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.edc4fff57eac398ed7325be1cf4b51f4634754a8.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-08-28T17:32:00-07:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.5319d7475749b7ccd46f9fba340838f81c4314d6.001.1,2025-08-28T15:08:00-07:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-08-28T17:32:00-07:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-08-28T17:32:00-07:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-08-28T18:15:00-07:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Elko NV</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Advisory issued August 28 at 5:32PM PDT until August 28 at 6:15PM PDT by NWS Elko NV</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...Flooding caused by excessive rainfall continues.

* WHERE...A portion of northeast Nevada, including the following
county, Elko.

* WHEN...Until 615 PM PDT.

* IMPACTS...Minor flooding in low-lying and poor drainage areas.
Rises in small streams and normally dry arroyos. Overflowing poor
drainage areas. Some low-water crossings may become impassable.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 532 PM PDT, Doppler radar continues to show light to
moderate off and on rain showers. Minor flooding is ongoing
or expected to begin shortly in Jakes Burn Scar. Doppler
radar estimates between 0.6 and 1.1 inches of rain has
fallen.
- Jakes Burn Scar is the most likely place to experience minor
flooding.
This includes the following streams and drainages...
Frazer Creek, Brush Creek, Milligan Creek, Buffalo Creek,
Spring Branch, Summit Creek, South Fork Little Humboldt
River, Squaw Creek and Secret Creek.
Additional rainfall amounts of 0.1 to 0.2 inches are expected
over the area. This additional rain will result in minor
flooding.
- Some locations that will experience flooding include...
Midas.
- http://www.weather.gov/safety/flood
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

Be aware of your surroundings and do not drive on flooded roads.

In hilly terrain there are hundreds of low water crossings which are
potentially dangerous in heavy rain. Do not attempt to cross flooded
roads. Find an alternate route.

Move away from recently burned areas. Life-threatening flooding of
creeks, roads and normally dry arroyos is likely. The heavy rains
will likely trigger rockslides, mudslides and debris flows in steep
terrain, especially in and around these areas.

Flooding is occurring or is imminent. It is important to know where
you are relative to streams, rivers, or creeks which can become
killers in heavy rains. Campers and hikers should avoid streams or
creeks.

Please report observed flooding to local emergency services or law
enforcement and request they pass this information to the National
Weather Service when you can do so safely.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSLKN</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGUS85 KLKN 290032</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 615 PM PDT THIS EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.KLKN.FA.Y.0012.000000T0000Z-250829T0115Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-08-28T18:15:00-07:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Elko, NV</areaDesc>
            <polygon>41.44,-116.76 41.36,-116.68 41.25,-116.73 41.19,-116.9 41.31,-116.93 41.4,-116.86 41.44,-116.76</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>032007</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>NVC007</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>