<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Sun, 02 Jan 2022 10:39:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-OR1263DC02A81C.WinterStormWarning.1263DC1F96C0OR.MFRWSWMFR.5db567e1b1c5a35d724e5aeef64d38d9</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2022-01-02T14:39:00-08:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Klamath Basin (Oregon) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Winter Storm Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Moderate</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value>WSW</value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2022-01-02T16:00:00-08:00</effective>
<expires>2022-01-04T04:00:00-08:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Medford (Southwest Oregon and Northern California)</senderName>
<headline>Winter Storm Warning issued January 02 at 2:39PM PST until January 04 at 4:00AM PST by NWS Medford</headline>
<description>...WINTER STORM WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 4 AM PST
TUESDAY...
...WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 4 AM PST
TUESDAY...
* WHAT...Winds will continue to increase today through Monday,
likely peaking late Monday morning through mid-afternoon Monday.
Snow is likely to begin Monday morning. For the Winter Storm
Warning, heavy snow and blowing snow expected. Total snow
accumulations of 6 to 12 inches. Winds gusting 35 to 55 mph. For
the Winter Weather Advisory, 2 to 6 of new snow expected. Wind
gusts 35 to 55 mph.
* WHERE...
-For the Winter Storm Warning: Generally areas north
and west of Klamath Falls including portions of Highway 140
and along Highway 97 in the Klamath Basin.
-For the Winter
Weather Advisory: The Klamath Falls area south and eastward in
Klamath County.
* WHEN...From 4 PM Sunday to 4 AM PST Tuesday.
* IMPACTS...Travel could be very difficult to impossible, at
times, in the warning area. Blowing snow could significantly
reduce visibility to near whiteout conditions, at times,
especially in areas prone to strong southerly winds. The
hazardous conditions could impact the morning and evening
commutes Monday into early Tuesday. Gusty winds could also
bring down tree branches possibly leading to power outages.
* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...Snow is likely to begin Monday morning from
north to south with time. The heaviest snow is most likely to
occur Monday afternoon with snowfall rates of 1 to 2 inches per
hour, at times.
* View the hazard area in detail at
https://www.wrh.noaa.gov/map/?wfo=mfr</description>
<instruction>* Travel is strongly discouraged because of dangerous conditions.
* If you must travel, keep tire chains, a flashlight, blankets,
food, water, medications, and a fully charged phone with you.
* The safest place during a winter storm is indoors.
* A Winter Storm Warning means that severe winter weather is
likely and poses a threat to life and property. Take
protective action now.</instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ029</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.KMFR.WS.W.0001.220103T0000Z-220104T1200Z/
/O.CON.KMFR.WW.Y.0001.220103T0000Z-220104T1200Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Klamath Basin</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>041035</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>ORZ029</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>