<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ea61416b1e3a567f0154c7d1577fbf90d5ce021a.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-15T02:17:00-04:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Alert</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Coastal Flood Advisory</event>
        <responseType>Monitor</responseType>
        <urgency>Expected</urgency>
        <severity>Minor</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>NWS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>CFY</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-15T02:17:00-04:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-15T12:00:00-04:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-15T11:15:00-04:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Wakefield VA</senderName>
        <headline>Coastal Flood Advisory issued September 15 at 2:17AM EDT until September 16 at 1:00PM EDT by NWS Wakefield VA</headline>
        <description>* WHAT...For the Beach Hazards Statement, a high risk of rip
currents and large breaking waves. For the Coastal Flood
Advisory, up to one foot of inundation above ground level
expected in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal
waterways. For the High Surf Advisory, large breaking waves of 7
to 9 feet expected in the surf zone. For the Coastal Flood
Watch, one to two feet of inundation above ground level possible
in low-lying areas near shorelines and tidal waterways.

* WHERE...Virginia Beach.

* WHEN...For the Beach Hazards Statement, through this evening.
For the Coastal Flood Advisory, from noon today to 1 PM EDT
Tuesday. For the High Surf Advisory, from noon today to 4 PM
EDT Tuesday. For the Coastal Flood Watch, from Tuesday
afternoon through Tuesday evening.

* IMPACTS...Numerous roads may be closed. Low lying property
including homes, businesses, and some critical infrastructure
may be inundated. Some shoreline erosion may occur. Dangerous
swimming and surfing conditions and localized beach erosion.
Breaking waves of 7 to 9 feet will result in rough surf
conditions and a high risk of rip currents.
</description>
        <instruction>If travel is required, allow extra time as some roads may be
closed. Do not drive around barricades or through water of
unknown depth. Take the necessary actions to protect flood-prone
property.

Inexperienced swimmers should remain out of the water due to
dangerous surf conditions.

Remain out of the water to avoid hazardous swimming conditions.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>CFWAKQ</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WHUS41 KAKQ 150617</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>BEACH HAZARDS STATEMENT REMAINS IN EFFECT THROUGH THIS EVENING... ...COASTAL FLOOD ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM NOON TODAY TO 1 PM EDT TUESDAY... ...HIGH SURF ADVISORY IN EFFECT FROM NOON TODAY TO 4 PM EDT TUESDAY... ...COASTAL FLOOD WATCH IN EFFECT FROM TUESDAY AFTERNOON THROUGH TUESDAY EVENING</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.NEW.KAKQ.CF.Y.0013.250915T1600Z-250916T1700Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-09-16T13:00:00-04:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>Virginia Beach</areaDesc>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>051810</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>VAZ098</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>