<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ef493453eeb2cb592143862af7e5c4fdb9ef2e51.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-15T17:11:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f5c72c78a64074879667d37aeb3afb2d7227d5bb.001.1,2025-09-15T09:29:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.817c4a30f73171521e748f73790b3f01e3f557d9.001.1,2025-09-15T14:07:00-08:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-15T17:11:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-15T17:11:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-16T01:15:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued September 15 at 5:11PM AKDT until September 16 at 6:00PM AKDT by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>Mendenhall Lake gauge levels, water temperatures, and water level
within the basin indicate that the basin continues it's release of
water into Mendenhall Lake. The forecast timing for when the lake
will crest has been moved up to early Tuesday morning between 2am
and 6am. The crest height has remained the same between 11 and 12
ft. More information below.

* WHAT...Flooding caused by a glacier-dammed lake outburst continues.

* WHERE...The Mendenhall Lake and River near areas around the
glacier visitor center, the Mendenhall campground, Skaters Cabin
Road, View Drive and possibly below Back Loop bridge.

* WHEN...Until 600 PM AKDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Flooding of Mendenhall lake and river is imminent or
occurring.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 450 PM AKDT, gauge reports indicated a glacier-dammed lake
outburst across the warned area. Flooding is ongoing or
expected to begin shortly, especially near the Mendenhall
Lake and River.

- The outburst flood forecast is based on an estimated volume
of water in the glacier dammed lake and an estimated release
rate based on previous events.  The extent of water drainage
within the basin (partial or full) can vary widely between
outburst flood events and is a major source of uncertainty in
the forecast, particularly with regard to the peak flood
stage.

- For Mendenhall Lake :
At 4:30pm the stage was 8.76 feet.
Flood Stage is 9.0 feet.
Forecast: A crest between 11 to 12 feet is expected between
2am to 6am Tuesday.
Water levels will go above minor flood stage between 3pm to
7pm Monday.
Water levels will go above moderate flood stage between 7 pm
to 11 pm Monday.

Impacts:
At 6.7 feet: Nugget Falls trail begins to flood near the
"causeway" at the end of the trail.

At 7.7 feet: Nugget Falls trail begins to flood near the
beginning of the trail. Along the Mendenhall River some
sections will experience bank erosion resulting in dangerous
tree fall. These conditions could make floating the river
more hazardous with the higher water levels.

At 9.0 feet: Water starts to cover Skaters Cabin Road between
Skaters Cabin and West Glacier Trailhead, also water will
flow into the Mendenhall Lake Campground.

At 9.5 feet: Water levels up to 0.5 feet will cover Skaters
Cabin Road between Skaters Cabin and West Glacier Trailhead.
Campsite 7 will be flooded with water starting to flow over
the road between campsites 8 and 9 in the Mendenhall
Campground.

At 10.0 feet: Water levels will inundate Mendenhall
Campground with up to 3 feet of water covering low areas as
well as up to 1.5 feet of water covering Skaters Cabin Road.
Portions of West Glacier Trail will be impassable. Areas
along View Dr will start to flood and cause minor flooding of
yards. Closure of pedestrian pathways beneath Brotherhood
Bridge and the trail system on the west side of Mendenhall
River during outburst events.

At 10.5 feet: Significant flooding along the Mendenhall Lake
area with more than 3 feet of water in places near Mt.
McGinnis trailhead and the Mendenhall Campground will be
evacuated.

At 11.0 feet: Some homes along View Dr will have up to 1.5
feet of water in yards. Locations below back loop bridge will
see bank erosion along unreinforced river banks along with
hazardous navigation from debris in the river. Homes along
the river on Meander Way will begin to see flooding of some
backyards on the outside of the HESCO levee. Portions of the
Dredge Lake Trail System will be impassable. Flood waters
start to reach Dredge Lake.

At 11.5 feet: The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
begin to flood along with water approaching some homes
towards the end of road.

At 12.0 feet: Significant bank erosion along unreinforced
river banks. The low section of road past 9374 View Dr will
be flooded with up to 0.5 feet of water. Some houses on the
south side and the east end of View Dr will start to flood.
Water begins to flood some backyards of homes on the
northside of View Dr as well as other low lying areas. Back
Loop Rd Bridge will be closed during outburst events.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

The cold water temperatures can increase the threat of hypothermia
and lower the time required to cause hypothermia.

Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK87 PAJK 160111</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING FOR A GLACIER-DAMMED LAKE OUTBURST REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 6 PM AKDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PAJK.FA.W.0003.000000T0000Z-250917T0200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-09-16T18:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8c183cfcea94d1b24f41ff5ac7470f4faff27861.001.1,2025-09-15T07:56:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>City and Borough of Juneau</areaDesc>
            <polygon>58.41,-134.6 58.42,-134.6 58.45,-134.6 58.47,-134.56 58.46,-134.52 58.44,-134.47 58.43,-134.47 58.4,-134.54 58.36,-134.59 58.35,-134.6 58.36,-134.62 58.41,-134.6</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ325</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>