<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alert xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.2">
    <identifier>urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.0aeb02995abe5f1540bc3ca98f9679dea9962d7e.001.1</identifier>
    <sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
    <sent>2025-09-15T20:44:00-08:00</sent>
    <status>Actual</status>
    <msgType>Update</msgType>
    <scope>Public</scope>
    <code>IPAWSv1.0</code>
    <references>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.817c4a30f73171521e748f73790b3f01e3f557d9.001.1,2025-09-15T14:07:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.ef493453eeb2cb592143862af7e5c4fdb9ef2e51.001.1,2025-09-15T17:11:00-08:00</references>
    <info>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <category>Met</category>
        <event>Flood Warning</event>
        <responseType>Avoid</responseType>
        <urgency>Immediate</urgency>
        <severity>Severe</severity>
        <certainty>Likely</certainty>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>SAME</valueName>
            <value>FLS</value>
        </eventCode>
        <eventCode>
            <valueName>NationalWeatherService</valueName>
            <value>FAW</value>
        </eventCode>
        <effective>2025-09-15T20:44:00-08:00</effective>
        <onset>2025-09-15T20:44:00-08:00</onset>
        <expires>2025-09-16T04:45:00-08:00</expires>
        <senderName>NWS Juneau AK</senderName>
        <headline>Flood Warning issued September 15 at 8:44PM AKDT until September 16 at 6:00PM AKDT by NWS Juneau AK</headline>
        <description>The release of water from Suicide basin into Mendenhall Lake and
river has come to an end. Mendenhall Lake was observed to have a
crest of 9.6 ft around 7:30 pm Monday evening, just below moderate
flood stage of 10.0 ft. Water levels are starting to drop in
Mendenhall lake. More information below.

* WHAT...Flooding caused by a glacier-dammed lake outburst continues.

* WHERE...The Mendenhall Lake and River near areas around the
glacier visitor center, the Mendenhall campground, Skaters Cabin
Road, View Drive and possibly below Back Loop bridge.

* WHEN...Until 600 PM AKDT Tuesday.

* IMPACTS...Flooding of Mendenhall lake and river is occurring.

* ADDITIONAL DETAILS...
- At 811 PM AKDT, gauge reports indicated a glacier-dammed lake
outburst across the warned area. A crest of 9.6 ft was
observed on Mendenhall Lake around 7:30 pm Monday evening,
just below moderate flood stage of 10.0 ft. Lake levels are
showing a rapid drop and will likely be below minor flood
stage by 10 pm this evening. Areas farther down Mendenhall
River will likely see water levels cresting up to an hour or
two later, but they should also start to see water levels
cresting and starting to drop soon.

- The outburst flood forecast is based on an estimated volume
of water in the glacier dammed lake and an estimated release
rate based on previous events.  The extent of water drainage
within the basin (partial or full) can vary widely between
outburst flood events and is a major source of uncertainty in
the forecast, particularly with regard to the peak flood
stage.

- For Mendenhall Lake :
At 8:30pm the stage was 9.3 feet and falling.
Flood Stage is 9.0 feet.
Forecast: a crest of 9.6 ft was observed at around 7:30pm and
is expected to continue to fall through the night.
Water levels will go below minor flood stage by 10 pm.

Impacts:
At 6.7 feet: Nugget Falls trail begins to flood near the
"causeway" at the end of the trail.

At 7.7 feet: Nugget Falls trail begins to flood near the
beginning of the trail. Along the Mendenhall River some
sections will experience bank erosion resulting in dangerous
tree fall. These conditions could make floating the river
more hazardous with the higher water levels.

At 9.0 feet: Water starts to cover Skaters Cabin Road between
Skaters Cabin and West Glacier Trailhead, also water will
flow into the Mendenhall Lake Campground.

At 9.5 feet: Water levels up to 0.5 feet will cover Skaters
Cabin Road between Skaters Cabin and West Glacier Trailhead.
Campsite 7 will be flooded with water starting to flow over
the road between campsites 8 and 9 in the Mendenhall
Campground.
</description>
        <instruction>Turn around, don't drown when encountering flooded roads. Most flood
deaths occur in vehicles.

The cold water temperatures can increase the threat of hypothermia
and lower the time required to cause hypothermia.

Stay tuned to further developments by listening to your local radio,
television, or NOAA Weather Radio for further information.</instruction>
        <web>http://www.weather.gov</web>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>AWIPSidentifier</valueName>
            <value>FLSAJK</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>WMOidentifier</valueName>
            <value>WGAK87 PAJK 160444</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>NWSheadline</valueName>
            <value>FLOOD WARNING FOR A GLACIER-DAMMED LAKE OUTBURST REMAINS IN EFFECT UNTIL 6 PM AKDT TUESDAY</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>EAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>NWEM</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>EAS-ORG</valueName>
            <value>WXR</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>VTEC</valueName>
            <value>/O.CON.PAJK.FA.W.0003.000000T0000Z-250917T0200Z/</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>eventEndingTime</valueName>
            <value>2025-09-16T18:00:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>BLOCKCHANNEL</valueName>
            <value>CMAS</value>
        </parameter>
        <parameter>
            <valueName>expiredReferences</valueName>
            <value>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.f5c72c78a64074879667d37aeb3afb2d7227d5bb.001.1,2025-09-15T09:29:00-08:00 w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov,urn:oid:2.49.0.1.840.0.8c183cfcea94d1b24f41ff5ac7470f4faff27861.001.1,2025-09-15T07:56:00-08:00</value>
        </parameter>
        <area>
            <areaDesc>City and Borough of Juneau</areaDesc>
            <polygon>58.41,-134.6 58.42,-134.6 58.45,-134.6 58.47,-134.56 58.46,-134.52 58.44,-134.47 58.43,-134.47 58.4,-134.54 58.36,-134.59 58.35,-134.6 58.36,-134.62 58.41,-134.6</polygon>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>SAME</valueName>
                <value>002110</value>
            </geocode>
            <geocode>
                <valueName>UGC</valueName>
                <value>AKZ325</value>
            </geocode>
        </area>
    </info>
</alert>