<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 23 May 2023 05:49:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-GU12664925BFF4.TyphoonWarning.12664932A520GU.GUMHLSPQ1.6393018a2ff088722ab38820ded6c051</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-05-24T03:49:00+10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Guam (Guam) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Typhoon Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-05-24T03:49:00+10:00</effective>
<expires>2023-05-24T12:00:00+10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Guam (Guam)</senderName>
<headline>Typhoon Warning issued May 24 at 3:49AM ChST until further notice by NWS Guam</headline>
<description>...SUPER TYPHOON MAWAR CONTINUES A SLOW APPROACH TOWARDS GUAM...
.NEW INFORMATION...
None.
.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and recommended
actions for people in Guam, Rota, Tinian and Saipan. Guam will
see the devastating impacts from Super Typhoon Mawar.
.Watches/Warnings...
A Typhoon Warning continues for the following locations, Guam and
Rota. Damaging winds of 39 mph are expected within the next few
hours. Typhoon force winds of 74 mph or greater are expected soon
after sunrise.
A Tropical Storm Warning and a Typhoon Watch continues for the
following locations, Tinian and Saipan.
A Flood Watch is in effect for all of Guam and the Northern
Marianas. Please listen closely for any Flood Warnings that might
be in effect for your area.
.STORM INFORMATION...
At 1 AM ChST...the center of Super Typhoon Mawar (02W) was
located near latitude 12.3N...longitude 145.9E. This was about
110 miles southeast of Guam. Storm Motion was west-northwest at 5
mph. Storm intensity is currently 155 mph.
.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
Super Typhoon Mawar continues its approach to Guam. Passage very
near or directly over Guam is imminent. The latest forecast from
the Joint Typhoon Warning Center (JTWC) indicates this storm will
strengthen further to a category 5 typhoon with maximum sustained
winds of 160 mph, with gusts approaching 200 mph. This is
expected to occur over the next few hours, prior to making
landfall. The triple threats of Super Typhoon Mawar are,
torrential rains that may result in landslides and flash
flooding, catastrophic wind, and life-threatening storm surge.
This is expected for Guam, with potently catastrophic coastal flooding
for southeastern and southern portions of Guam. A mandatory
evacuation order was initiated by the governor of Guam yesterday.
Storm surge potential is extreme, please see the storm surge and
surf info below, as a large storm surge and coastal impacts are
expected, particularly for coastal areas just north of the eye of
Super Typhoon Mawar on the east to southeast sides of Guam. Gaum
and the CNMI are all in COR1 by their respective governors.
.PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
All preparations for the protection of life and property should now
be complete. You should be in a fully-reinforced concrete
structure, especially on Guam.
For interests at ports, docks and marinas, prescribed preparations
according to your emergency operations plan for tropical cyclones
should now be complete. If you live on a boat, if you haven`t already
done so, make final preparations for securing your craft before
leaving it.
During the storm...stay inside and away from windows. Do not venture
outside when high winds are occurring or during temporary lulls as
flying debris can easily, and suddenly, cause serious injury. If the
eye passes over you, extreme winds will suddenly cease. This is not
the end of the typhoon--REMAIN IN SHELTER as extreme winds will
rapidly resume.
Have a well-charged cell phone nearby, keeping network
communications as open as possible for emergencies.
Once conditions have improved, remain in shelter until the all-clear,
COR 4, is announced from government officials.
Closely monitor NOAA weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for the latest forecasts.
&amp;&amp;
.NEXT UPDATE...
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tiyan around 5 AM...or sooner if conditions warrant.
...TYPHOON WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING IS NOW IN EFFECT...
...PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
Stay calm and keep informed. Final preparations to protect life and
property should already be complete. It is too late to make any
further attempts to secure your shutters or other preparatory
concerns. DO NOT VENTURE OUTSIDE until the government of Guam
gives the &quot;all clear&quot;. This will be a very long event. IF YOU`RE
IN THE EYE, you may experience calm conditions for an extended
period of time. Remain indoors, the conditions will rapidly
deteriorate as the back edge of the eye wall approaches.
Residents should remain in shelter within sturdy concrete homes with
concrete roofs, or wherever you are.
If staying in a home, turn the refrigerator to maximum cold and keep
it closed. Turn off propane tanks and unplug small appliances. Fill
the bathtub with water in case the tap water becomes unavailable
after the storm. This is for cleaning/flushing purposes. Do not
drink it.
During the storm, stay inside and away from windows in a building
with concrete walls and a concrete roof. Residents must avoid power
lines as they will be tilted or broken. Stay away from the ocean due
to storm surge. Large ships should be secured as they will be torn
from moorings. Do not venture outside when high winds are occurring
or during temporary lulls as flying debris can easily, and
suddenly, cause serious injury. If the eye passes overhead, DO NOT GO
OUTSIDE!!! Extreme winds will rapidly return.
Again, once conditions have improved on Thursday, remain in
shelter until the all-clear, Cor 4, is given by government
officials.
&amp;&amp;
...Probability of tropical storm/typhoon conditions...
Typhoon conditions are most likely to begin during the next few
hours and continue into midday. Intense eyewall winds are expected
around between noontime and 5PM.
&amp;&amp;
...Winds...
The latest forecast is for typhoon force winds (winds 74 mph or
greater) developing over the next few hours, and increasing
through the morning, peaking near the eye wall where maximum
sustained winds of 160 mph, with gusts between 195 and 200 mph
are likely.
Exposed, higher terrain of the island is likely to experience
higher winds. Wind direction at any point on Guam is highly
dependent on the exact track of the eye. A direct passage over the
island would lead to major typhoon force winds from a mix of
directions. A passage just south of Guam would favor major typhoon
force north to northeast winds shifting east and then southeast
to south. A passage just north of Guam would favor major typhoon
force winds from the northeast to west, then southwest to west.
Typhoon force winds will extend outward from the center roughly 30
miles.
Super Typhoon Mawar is likely to bring considerable damage to
buildings and homes of light material. Extensive damage to non-
concrete roof. Non-reinforced concrete walls could be blown down.
Severe damage to well-built wooden and metal structures possible.
Some reinforced hollow-spun concrete power poles and many
reinforced wooden power poles could be downed. Solar panels could
be damaged. Large projectiles and debris are possible. Most small
and medium sized steel frame signs could be bent over or damaged.
Some fuel storage tanks could rupture. Cars and high paneled
vehicles could be overturned. Major damage to shrubbery and trees
is likely with snapped or uprooted trees and blocked roads.
Defoliation of vegetation is likely, perhaps 50-70% defoliation.
Electricity and water may be unavailable for days and perhaps weeks
after the storm passes. Most trees will be snapped or uprooted.
Fallen trees may cut off residential areas for days to weeks.
...Storm surge and storm tide...
Storm surge of 6 to 10 feet above the normal high tide is expected
as Mawar moves overhead today. Surge may reach to between 20 and
25 feet above normal high tide for the most vulnerable storm surge
prone areas near the eye wall, just north of Super Typhoon Mawar`s
eye. Super Typhoon Mawar`s angle of approach could lead to
considerable coastal impacts and surge for Malesso, Inalahan, Ipan
and Pago Bay, especially if the center of Mawar scrapes by just
south of Guam. Coastal roads of Guam around Inalahan and Malesso
may be impassable due to lofted beach debris and boulders if this
southern track is realized. Surge of 1 to 3 feet is possible
within Apra Harbor. Surge may reach 4 feet along western shores
when Mawar passes over Guam.
Severe coastal erosion is likely. Large boats could be torn from
moorings. Moderate to extensive damage is possible. A passage over
or just north of Guam would lead to greater impacts for western
coastlines.
Surf continues to build along the south and east facing reefs,
with dangerous surf of 20 to 30 feet possible late tonight into
Wednesday. Rough surf may develop along west facing reefs as early
as Wednesday night, with hazardous surf by late Thursday or
Friday.
...Inland flooding...
A Flood Watch is in effect for the entire area. Listen for
possible flood warnings, and be ready to act if flooding rains
occur.
Heavy rainfall is likely to develop tonight through the next few
days. Torrential rain is likely as Mawar passes near or overhead.
Rainfall amounts of 10 to 15 inches are possible with locally higher
amounts of 20 inches or more. Landslides are a distinct possibility
for central to southern Guam along with overflowing streams and
rivers. A slowing of forward speed could lead to higher rainfall
totals. Monitor conditions for possible flood advisories or
warnings.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUZ001</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.PGUM.TY.W.4002.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Guam</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>066010</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>GUZ001</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>