<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8' standalone = 'yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='capatomproduct.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>

<!--
This atom/xml feed is an index to active advisories, watches and warnings 
issued by the National Weather Service.  This index file is not the complete 
Common Alerting Protocol (CAP) alert message.  To obtain the complete CAP 
alert, please follow the links for each entry in this index.  Also note the 
CAP message uses a style sheet to convey the information in a human readable 
format.  Please view the source of the CAP message to see the complete data 
set.  Not all information in the CAP message is contained in this index of 
active alerts.
-->

<alert xmlns = 'urn:oasis:names:tc:emergency:cap:1.1'>

<!-- http-date = Tue, 23 May 2023 11:08:00 GMT -->
<identifier>NOAA-NWS-ALERTS-MP126649269A50.TyphoonWarning.126649338F80MP.GUMHLSPQ1.86ffa31939958950f8ed7677130e28bb</identifier>
<sender>w-nws.webmaster@noaa.gov</sender>
<sent>2023-05-24T09:08:00+10:00</sent>
<status>Actual</status>
<msgType>Alert</msgType>
<scope>Public</scope>
<note>Alert for Rota (Marianas) Issued by the National Weather Service</note>
<info>
<category>Met</category>
<event>Typhoon Warning</event>
<urgency>Expected</urgency>
<severity>Severe</severity>
<certainty>Likely</certainty>
<eventCode>
<valueName>SAME</valueName>
<value></value>
</eventCode>
<effective>2023-05-24T09:08:00+10:00</effective>
<expires>2023-05-24T18:00:00+10:00</expires>
<senderName>NWS Guam (Guam)</senderName>
<headline>Typhoon Warning issued May 24 at 9:08AM ChST until further notice by NWS Guam</headline>
<description>...CATEGORY 4 TYPHOON MAWAR CONTINUES A SLOW APPROACH TOWARDS GUAM...
Corrected details in Guam inland flooding section
.NEW INFORMATION...
None.
.AREAS AFFECTED...
This local statement provides important information and recommended
actions for people in Guam, Rota, Tinian and Saipan. Guam will see
the devastating impacts from Mawar.
.Watches/Warnings...
A Typhoon Warning continues for the Guam and Rota. Damaging winds of
39 mph are occurring. Typhoon force winds of 74 mph or greater are
expected later this morning.
A Tropical Storm Warning and a Typhoon Watch continues for Tinian and
Saipan.
A Flood Watch is in effect for Guam and the Northern Marianas. Please
listen closely for any Flood Warnings that might be in effect for
your area.
.STORM INFORMATION...
At 8 AM ChST...the eye of Cat 4 Typhoon Mawar (02W) was located near
latitude 12.8N...longitude 145.7E based on a PGUA radar fix. This was
about 75 miles southeast of Guam. Storm motion was towards the north-
west at 6 mph. Storm intensity is currently 140 mph.
.SITUATION OVERVIEW...
Mawar continues its approach towards Guam. Passage very near or
directly over Guam is imminent. The latest forecast from the Joint
Typhoon Warning Center (JTWC) indicates that Mawar may strengthen
slightly on approach to Guam with maximum sustained winds of 145 mph,
with gusts approaching 175 mph at landfall. This is expected to
occur over the next few hours, prior to making landfall.
The triple threats of Cat 4 Typhoon Mawar are, torrential rains that
may result in landslides and flash flooding, catastrophic wind, and
life-threatening storm surge. This is expected for Guam, with
potently catastrophic coastal flooding for southeastern and southern
portions of Guam if a southern Guam or Cocos passage is realized. A
mandatory evacuation order was initiated by the governor of Guam
yesterday. Storm surge potential is extreme, please see the storm
surge and surf info below, as a large storm surge and coastal impacts
are expected, particularly for coastal areas just north of the eye
of Typhoon Mawar on the east to southeast sides of Guam. Guam and the
CNMI are all in COR 1 by their respective governors.
.PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
All preparations for the protection of life and property should now
be complete. You should be in a fully-reinforced concrete structure,
especially on Guam.
During the storm...stay inside and away from windows. Do not venture
outside when high winds are occurring or during temporary lulls as
flying debris can easily, and suddenly, cause serious injury. If the
eye passes over you on Guam, extreme winds will suddenly cease. This
is not the end of the typhoon. REMAIN IN SHELTER as extreme winds
will rapidly resume.
Have a well-charged cell phone nearby, keeping network communications
as open as possible for emergencies.
Once conditions have improved, remain in shelter until the all-clear,
COR 4, is announced from government officials.
Closely monitor NOAA weather radio or other local news outlets for
official storm information. Listen for the latest forecasts.
&amp;&amp;
.NEXT UPDATE...
The next local statement will be issued by the National Weather
Service in Tiyan around 3 PM...or sooner if conditions warrant.
...TYPHOON WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...COASTAL FLOOD WARNING REMAINS IN EFFECT...
...PRECAUTIONARY/PREPAREDNESS ACTIONS...
It is too late to make any further attempts to secure your shutters
or other preparatory concerns. Residents should remain in shelter
within sturdy concrete homes with concrete roofs, or wherever you are.
Again, once conditions have improved sometime late Thursday or
Friday, remain in shelter until the all-clear, Cor 4, is given by
government officials.
&amp;&amp;
...Probability of tropical storm/hurricane conditions...
Typhoon conditions may arrive this afternoon, especially if Mawar
drifts a bit farther north than the current forecast track.
...Winds...
Damaging winds (sustained winds of 39 mph or more) will arrive later
during the next few hours.
There is still a distinct possibility for typhoon force winds. The
most likely timeframe for typhoon force winds would be noontime to
5 PM today. Wind direction is still likely to be northeast,
shifting east to southeast.
Corrugated metal and plywood may be stripped from poorly constructed
buildings and become airborne. Wooden power poles which are rotten or
not reinforced could be tilted or even broken. Poorly constructed
signs could become damaged. Banana, papaya and other similar crops
could topple.
...Storm surge and storm tide...
Storm surge of 2 to 5 feet above the normal high tide is expected as
Mawar passes closer to Guam today. Higher surge values around 5 feet
would be realized if Mawar passes closer to northern Guam. Large boats
could be torn from moorings. Moderate coastal erosion and reef damage
is likely, particularly along southeast to eastern reefs. Moderate
damage is possible.
Surf continues to build along south and east facing reefs with
dangerous surf of 15 to 20 feet expected. Hazardous surf is likely
to spread to west facing reefs Friday or Saturday as Mawar moves west
into the Philippine Sea.
...Inland flooding...
A Flood Watch is in effect for Rota. Listen for possible flood
warnings for your location, and be ready to act if flooding rains
occur.
Heavy rainfall is likely to develop later this morning and continue
through Thursday. Torrential rain is quite possible as Mawar passes
to the south closer to Guam. Rainfall amounts of 3 to 5 inches are
possible with locally higher amounts. A slowing of forward speed and
drift farther north could lead to higher rainfall totals. Monitor
conditions for possible flood advisories or warnings.</description>
<instruction></instruction>
<parameter>
<valueName>WMOHEADER</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MPZ001</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>VTEC</valueName>
<value>/O.CON.PGUM.TY.W.4002.000000T0000Z-000000T0000Z/</value>
</parameter>
<parameter>
<valueName>TIME...MOT...LOC</valueName>
<value></value>
</parameter>
<area>
<areaDesc>Rota</areaDesc>
<polygon></polygon>
<geocode>
<valueName>FIPS6</valueName>
<value>069100</value>
</geocode>
<geocode>
<valueName>UGC</valueName>
<value>MPZ001</value>
</geocode>
</area>
</info>
</alert>